1. A Second Wind

It is the stars,

The stars above us, govern our conditions.

(King Lear, 4.3.37), Kent

"You're very welcome."

The last of the motes of light faded. Madoka sighed and rubbed her eyes. A draining, swirling exhaustion pulled at her. When Madoka opened her eyes again, she was leaning on her elbows in the cafe near her old middle school.

"You alright there?" asked Sayaka. Madoka looked up. Sayaka was giving her a worried look.

"I'm fine, Sayaka-chan," said Madoka, sitting up and stretching. Her bones popped. "Mmm. Just a little tired. We've been working hard."

"You're doing all the heavy lifting," said Sayaka. "Me and the others are just showing up to say things. It's not like we actually doing anything when you ask us to come with."

"Saying things is important, Sayaka-chan," said Madoka. She picked up her tea cup with a gloved hand and sipped at the bracing beverage. "The right words can topple empires, you know."

Sayaka rolled her eyes. "Sure, Mado-okaa-san, whatever you say."

Madoka pouted as their food arrived, sliding onto the table from the top of an Anthony's head. "I'm not that old, Sayaka-chan!"

"Yes, you are," said Sayaka bluntly. "I watched you rescue friggen Joan of Arc, Madoka!"

"Oh hush," said Madoka, prodding her friend with a foot. "Time is like origami, don't you remember?"

"And besides, you're avoiding the question," continued Sayaka, ignoring the sandwich and soda that had been placed in front of her. "Are you sure you're okay? Ripping open a hole in time and space can't be good for you."

"I'm fine, Sayaka-chan, really," said Madoka. She took another bite of cake. "Hmm, not as good as Mami-san's…."

"But it's only been, like, five girls," said Sayaka anxiously. "Maybe you should cut down on the trips? You didn't really need to go see Emma, she's not that important in the—."

The room physically dropped in temperature as Madoka looked up and dropped ice into Sayaka's very soul. "Every girl is important, Sayaka."

Sayaka quailed.

"S-sorry, Madoka," said Sayaka. "I'm… I'm just worried. You're not completely omnipotent, and I… I guess I still remember the meek little Madoka-chan from before."

Madoka sighed. She reached across the table and flicked Sayaka on the nose.

"Ow!"

"It's fine, Sayaka-chan," said Madoka. She gave Sayaka a reassuring smile. "Being a little tired isn't going to hurt me now, and this is important."

"But you're a goddess now!" said Sayaka. "I mean, you getting tired, period, is a problem!"

"It's not as big a problem as making sure this battle goes well," said Madoka firmly. "Samsara is important to humanity. Economically, politically, socially… it cannot be allowed to burn."

Sayaka pressed her lips together unhappily, then pushed her sandwich across to Madoka. "Here, I'm not hungry anyway."

"Eh? But—."

"I just need some sugar to keep going," said Sayaka, sucking down her soda with the provided straw. "Hurry up, we've got more to do, like you said."

Madoka blinked at Sayaka for a moment, before nodding. She quickly devoured the sandwich and the cake.

"Let's get going then, Sayaka-chan," said Madoka. She stood and brushed the crumbs off her gown. "Are you ready?"

"Always, Madoka-chan," said Sayaka. She adjusted her cape and stood at Madoka's side. "Who are we visiting now?"

"Her name is…"

A flash of pink, and the two were gone.

Emma blinked her eyes open.

She was lying on her side, curled gently around her gem. The cold of the floor, seeping through her costume, was the only discomfort she felt. She felt well rested, alert, ready to fight. Two days of combat had been wiped away, leaving her at the peak of fitness. Emma went to push herself up and—

—collapsed in agony as her dying gem ripped open her body. It was like being burned and flayed alive while animals gnawed at your limbs. A ragged scream tore out of Emma's throat as she struggled to retain consciousness. What remained of her soul's light glimmered faintly at the base of her gem, barely holding itself together as the filigree slowly rusted.

Emma gasped, then grit her teeth. Have to keep it together. Have to- have to purify. Three, two, and—

—There was an almost physical impact as she forced her remaining magic into herself, locking her limbs and forcing her backpack to extrude her remaining grief cubes. Emma burned through her last reserves dumping her gem into the pile of cubes. For a second, nothing happened. The pain was getting worse, she was supposed to be purifying, why wasn't she purifying Goddess no not now—

—a surge of relief, like a pitcher of water being poured down her body. An almost literal sizzling as the pain ebbed, washed away. It left her weak and exhausted, collapsed onto her side as she struggled to take in air. Her gem had consumed all of her remaining grief cubes.

But, she was alive.

With a groan, Emma pushed herself upright and slump against the wall. She glanced at Ingrid's body.

"I guess that could have gone better," she said.

Emma sat there recovering her strength. The exhaustion she felt slowly ebbed as her magic did its work. It wasn't much. Deep seated fatigue like this wasn't something you could deal with that easily. Some food would help, but this was the entirely wrong place to break out a food pack.

Instead, Emma dragged herself to her feet and cleaned. The electrical equipment was heavy, but Emma had enough strength to deal with it. Within the hour, the wreckage had been shoved to the side. A battery pack and VR cable were scrounged from the destruction. Emma placed the defenders' remains in neat rows across the back.

A speech would have been good. Emma was too tired to think of anything appropriate.

Emma bowed, then made her way back outside. It was still raining. With a sigh, she pushed the piled squid dead over with a splash of mud.

There was something disquieting about the silence that echoed afterwards. A moment after, Emma realized that it was because she could no longer hear detonations in the background. The march up had been interspersed with the sound of distant combat. Now though, she couldn't hear a thing.

Emma wasn't sure what that meant. On the one hand, it could mean that the defenders had been overwhelmed, pushed into the tunnels of Helsinberg's redoubt and besieged. On the other, it could merely be a lull in the fighting. A quick breath, before both combatants plunged back into the fray.

She grimaced. Best play it safe then. Emma climbed up the hillside as stealthily as she could. The ground was slippery, saturated with water and having little to hold it together. Pebbles and gravel slid beneath Emma's feet. Twice, she had to catch herself from falling completely into a puddle. Once she failed.

Goddess, she desperately need a rest. That would never have happened if she had been at peak fitness. As she neared the top of the hill, Emma took a deep breath and moved to her hands and knees. Slowly, she peered out from behind a boulder to survey the land around her.

The valley had burned. Bits still smoldered as the cool rain tried and failed to quench the fiery hunger of plasma and laser blast. It was a field of ruin, destroyed by forces unmatched by man alone, but contested with unyielding anger and pride. The dead littered the valley, black dots upon blacker dust. The river swelled to match the fury of the men and women who had defended it to their last breath. Little remained of what had once been a dense network of emplacements and weaponry.

Emma sighed. For all her despair and anguish, it seemed the reality of the situation was that she would have been of little use on the field this battle. Her powers were meager, in comparison to the almighty force wielded by a Reaper's laser cannon. Even with her company behind her, the result would probably have only been tragedy. It had been wrong of her to despair.

Emma squeezed her eyes shut. Dammit. She was so stupid.

With another deep sigh, Emma began to search for something to home in on as her next destination. The fields of the valley were stripped of their fortifications, most of them shattered and burnt. The suburbs surrounding Helsinberg been blasted and destroyed as well. Twisted remnants of apartments and houses were all that remained of a once active, if not necessarily vibrant, urban center.

What wasn't utterly ruined had been occupied, the oblong forms of cephalopod drones drifting about and small figures that could only be troopers moving about on patrol. The density of forces increased with proximity to Helsinberg. It was difficult to tell, from this distance, but the constant haze hovering over the area had to be cephalopod drones.

Still, the human line was standing firm. Just within the bounds of downtown Helsinberg, several towers had been toppled to interfere with cephalopod plans. They weren't much, but booby trapping and firing angles made them a challenge that had to be planned for. On top of that, many towers still stood, making them good, if obvious, positions for the many magical sniper teams.

Oddly enough, the Reapers in the area weren't firing. A large amount of wreckage, distantly visible to the east, implied some sort of impact from orbit. Emma had no idea how the battle in space was going, but it appeared that the Home Fleet was making some sort of progress. If that held—

Emma's train of thought was cut off as she caught a bright flash of light about twenty kilometers away, near a building that might have been taken over as a supply depot. Cascading explosions followed, then more bright flashes in an array of colors.

More survivors? No, that didn't make any sense. The tightly controlled sequence of flashes was too organized. MagOps then. Emma wasn't familiar with the redoubt tunnels underneath Helsinberg. Maybe there was a way to get to the underground fortress from the suburbs. But, for all she knew, the team had a teleporter with long range capability.

Either way though, that was her ticket out of here. Emma had to get into the outskirts. If there was one MagOps team causing havoc and, apparently, meeting success, then there had to be more either already in place or about to enter the area. As long as Emma could get into telepathy range, she could get rescued.

First though, the downhill slope.

Freshly soaked in more mud from the downhill trek, Emma moved more quickly. Eyeing her gem warily, Emma dropped out of her costume and walked in the street clothes she had kept from Mitakihara. It was a little more slippery and the chill soaked in deeper, but it used up no magic and wasn't that much worse.

Emma didn't try very hard to scavenge this time. She wanted to get back as quickly as possible, after all. Batteries and ammo packs, however, she saved whenever she could find them. ID Chips she stored in her backpack as best she could. Any potentially useful data was yanked as well, since she now had the VR cable to act as data I/O.

If it weren't for the fact that being numb to death was an alarming state to be in, Emma would have congratulated herself for not letting it get to her. She should probably talk to a counselor about that later. To be fair, though, Emma didn't try very hard to feel sad. Her thoughts were instead focused on the… well Emma wasn't sure what it was that she'd seen, just before waking up.

Technically speaking, it was more of a fever-death-dream than an honest-to-goodness vision. Wasn't it expected for visions to be prophetic in some way? If so, she was completely screwed. Like all dreams, she had started forgetting it the moment she'd woken up. If there was something she was supposed to remember to keep from dying, then it'd been lost by now.

Thinking about it though, she wasn't even sure that it had been any sort of vision at all. She still believed what she had concluded after the IFV had been hit: you didn't survive that sort of thing without outside help. But what you'd been thinking before you fell asleep had strong influences on what you dreamed abut. There was no guaranteeing she hadn't just imagined everything, and since she couldn't remember much, there was no way to tell.

Whatever it was, it had definitely involved swimming. That, and being burned alive while underwater, ominously. There had been music, the sound of violins, and the feeling that everything would be okay, eventually. But aside from that…

…Well, there was one thing. She remembered… she remembered lying on a bed, and someone pulling the sheets over her, before kissing her goodnight. It was like… it had been like she was a little kid again, being tucked in by her parents at the end of a long day.

Part of her suddenly wanted to be done with it all. Not die, no, that was too much, but just to go away into some forgotten corner of space and spend her days napping. Maybe find someone to date, but nothing serious. It seemed like she hadn't felt safe, properly safe, for an entire epoch, and that was something she desperately wanted to feel again.

But if she did die, Emma wasn't sure she wouldn't be… well, "welcoming" was a stretch, but it didn't seem that bad anymore. No one could say for sure what happened after you died, but being rescued by the Goddess was somewhere in that list. As would be, Emma hoped, the chance to take a long nap.

...It seemed childish, but being tucked in by the Goddess would be really nice too.

Getting to the suburbs ended up taking longer than Emma had liked. Her gem was still weakened from coming so close to death. The crushing exhaustion kept her from maintaining long periods of activity. Eating some food from the food packs she had brought from Team B-4's position gave her more strength, but Emma didn't dare spend more time than was absolutely necessary in the open.

There was no sign of any activity from the MagOps team Emma had seen earlier. The outskirts of the suburbs seemed totally abandoned, devoid of any military presence by any side. Emma treated this with cautious optimism. Hopefully, this meant that the squid had pulled away from the area, not wanting to risk further engagement with the MagOps team.

Emma crouched behind a pile of fallen decorative bricks. They had surrounded a playground once. The swings still creaked in the wind as the rain tap tap tapped along the ground, tinging off the metal and scattering amongst the torn shrubbery. There was no movement.

Cautiously, Emma walked forward. Her footsteps were muffled by magic. Carefully placed as well, lest a misstep herald the collapse of rubble and draw the ire of any nearby drones or patrols. The tumbledown walls and impromptu stairways surrounding her beckoned forth, inviting Emma to explore their depths and find what lay within. It was a tempting offer, to be sure, as no doubt there was plenty of interest to find inside.

But that was gratuitously unwise. Emma had no doubt that every single building was booby trapped. If by the squid, then probably with no small amount of explicitly anti-magical girl hardware. If not, then there would certainly be whatever traps human forces had been able to place. No, the main streets were, ironically, much safer.

Emma stayed low, flitting from bit of rubble to bit of rubble. There were some passive sensors wired into her skull, but their range was limited and they did nothing for static emplacements. Emma needed only to run into a turret and she'd be done for. But, from what she could remember, the last attack had been just a bit further west from where she was. It seemed reasonable to assume that the MagOps team was still in the area.

Still, it was a big assumption to make. MagOps teams tended to be created to fulfill specific missions. It was just as likely that the team had melted away into the shadows and returned to wherever they had came from, waiting for another day and place to strike. There was no guarantee that Emma would find them, and for all she knew, she was walking right into—

—an enemy patrol. Emma sucked in her breath and dived for cover, praying that she hadn't been spotted. After a moment's silence, she peeked around the side.

Shit, they were fanning out. One of them must have caught sight of the tail of her robe. The only path that Emma had was through the building next to her. It hadn't been bombed completely, and still stood several stories tall. Glancing back once more, Emma braced herself, then slid in as noiselessly as she could through a ground-level window.

She landed with a quiet thud. Emma waited breathlessly for a moment. Nothing. Good. She immediately set forth, moving forward at a crouch. She kept one eye on the passive sensor readout and another on the ground. The light was dim inside, but she could just make out the shapes that she needed to avoid.

It was true, what she'd expected. The building was riddled with booby traps, the sort that had little feet and scuttled about to find a suitable position. Just at the first door, Emma had needed to brush aside a handful of caltrops and shimmy herself underneath a hip-height ultraviolet tripwire.

More alarming was the array of proximity mines that she found strung across the obvious routes out. With no way to heal herself and death guaranteed if she was found, Emma had to find alternate paths and shimmy herself through tiny gaps to get through. More than once, she held her breath as the clink of an armored tentacle hitting the ground heralded the presence of a patrolling squid. The traps could sense friendly units and let them pass unharmed.

Briefly, Emma considered following a squid from room to room, until she got a chance to escape. This was quickly dismissed as untenable. She wished for rooftops to run across, something that could be accomplished easily and quietly. Perhaps more open to drone attack, sure, but this was maddening.

Emma quickly found herself lost. A growing sense of being herded plagued her as she scanned each area for potential exits. Holes in walls were too convenient, it seemed, and she was going ever higher in the building. Something was definitely not right.

Emma tried to think back across what she'd done so far. She'd gone in through the one window, but she was sure she hadn't been followed. She'd evaded all the tripwires easily too, and hadn't managed to set off a proximity mine yet. The detonation range on those things was only a few meters, but—

—they should have killed her by now. Damn. She WAS being herded. Emma had never been more than five feet from any one mine, the things must have been linked together and were being moved around by the patrol. Her every movement had been orchestrated to push her into a corner, where it'd be easier to pin her down and blow her to bits with a well placed grenade.

Damn it damn it DAMN it. Emma breathed deep and tried to think through the situation. What to do, what to do…

Well they were just standard troopers, from Emma had seen. No unique insignia anywhere. She should be able to take them with just hand to hand. If she used magic to blast some of the mines away… wait no, the window! If she went out the window, she could aeromaneuver away from the building and back into cover.

Nodding decisively, Emma moved hurriedly to the window and checked it for any traps. There was nothing she could see on the frame. She didn't have a good angle, but it didn't seem like there was anything hanging above or below the window either.

Time to hope for the best then.

Carefully, ever so carefully, Emma pushed open the window. Nothing. Holding her breath, Emma began climbing over the window sill. One booted foot touched the window frame before she was fully out.

There was a massive flash and horrendous explosion. Her vision was completely whited out, her ears were ringing, and something was dripping from her mouth and nose. A second later, she realized it was blood.

Blind and deaf, Emma felt her combat instincts begin to scream at her to move, to get out of there, to escape. The explosion must have alerted the entire patrol to her presence, and the trip mines kept trying to climb onto her. Something metal scraped at her boot—

—and then her vision suddenly snapped back into place. The terrifying sight of dozens of mines scrabbling towards her filled her vision for a moment before Emma felt herself get yanked bodily out the window.

"Don't panic, I've got you," said a voice in her head. Emma looked up to see a skull looking down at her, wearing black lace and ruffles. She felt her mouth open to scream, before it snapped shut and her entire body went limp.

"Fuck, if you're going to do that, I'm just carrying you," said the magical girl. Emma lolled limply, in a semi-panicked state. "Oi, you alive in there?"

"W-wha?"

"I said," repeated the magical girl, slowly, as if speaking to a toddler. "Are you alive in there?"

"I- yes, yes I'm alive," said Emma. "Can you let me down now, please?"

"Not yet," said the girl. "Name's Nodoka. I'm going to keep you like this until we get to somewhere safe, okay? Take a nap or something."

"…I can't close my eyes."

Emma blinked. Then she realized she'd done it on her own. "…Thanks?"

"Don't mention it," said Nodoka. "Hold tight now."

Emma resisted the urge to say something sarcastic. She realized now that they were moving at an extraordinary pace, flicking over the ruins on an apparently completely arbitrary path. The girl must have been wearing some sort of high performance stealth generator, or they'd have been picked up by enemy drones by now.

"Hold on, braking," said Nodoka shortly. Seconds later she came to a hard stop in the courtyard behind a strip mall. Emma felt herself twitch once, before she was dropped unceremoniously to the ground. Evidently, she had control of her body back, because she landed on her hands and feet and bounced back up.

"What's your name?" asked Nodoka. She had pushed the skull, evidently a mask, up on her forehead.

Emma took a deep breath and sighed before answering. "My name is Emma Sinclair."

"Burnside-Sinclair, you mean?" asked Nodoka. She turned and waved for Emma to follow.

"No, just Sinclair," said Emma, confused.

"Huh, that's weird," said Nodoka. "Well, we'll see if you're related to Agapita later. Come along, Emma."

"What's going on?" asked Emma, following behind hurriedly. "Thanks for the save, but where are we?"

"We are exactly five kilometers distant from the nearest entrance to the redoubt," said Nodoka. "MagOps Team Four has been tasked with supply line harassment. Apparently, it's also extended to rescuing your sorry newbie ass."

Emma frowned. "I'm not that new."

"Yes you are," said Nodoka. "Compared to us, anyway."

Oh come on! Seriously? Again? "Why?" challenged Emma. "You're part of MagOps, but you can't have more than a few years—."

"Kid, you are drastically underestimating what it takes to get into MagOps," said Nodoka, severely unimpressed. "I turned ninety-seven two weeks ago, brat. Respect your elder."

Emma blanched. "O-oh."

"Yeah. Now shut up and follow me."

Meekly, Emma trailed behind Nodoka as the girl, woman really, led Emma into the strip mall, the down into the basement.

"Right, stay here," ordered Nodoka. "We'll come pick you up in a bit. Don't do anything stupid."

Emma nodded. With a swish of lace, Nodoka turned and left, basement door clicking shut behind her.

…Well damn. Talk about ruined first impressions.

The basement door suddenly opened again.

"Catch."

Emma caught a small bag full of grief cubes.

"Figured you might want some," said Nodoka from the doorway. "Leave at least half for me."

"Right."

The door clicked shut again.

With a sigh, Emma sat down on a crate and settled in to wait.

2. Much Ado About Everything

The basement Emma was in was best described as "claustrophobic". Yes, its ceiling was actually rather tall and its walls widely spaced, but it was also piled high with crates of product and various bits of unused shelving and office supplies.

Sitting there on the crate, Emma quickly grew bored. She had little to do except introspect or manually process the data she'd collected from the dead. The first would probably end up weakening her soul gem, and the second would probably cause the first from sheer boredom.

Exploring the basement in some attempt at entertainment appeared to be her only option. Some food would be good for her as well. Honestly, ration packs were not great tasting, but at least they were better than, say, that random clump of moss you'd pulled off a rock.

Each ration pack consisted of wrappers within a wrapper. Emma rummaged in her backpack and pulled out a pack labeled "Beef bourguignon". The pack included silverware and an insulated metal tray you could balance on your knees. Each component was labeled and nanite-infused, so that it heated automatically when it came in contact with the tray. You could skim off the nanites after the heating cycle if you wanted, and Emma did since it tended to make the food slightly bitter. She didn't need to though. It was perfectly safe to eat either way.

Emma ate as she made her way through the densely packed basement. Oddly enough, she didn't feel that hungry. Then again, implants.

The basement was actually vaguely interesting, now that she looked at it more carefully. It was a bit surprising for her to see, for example, the vast array of tablets that were available. The devices were going outdated by now on Earth, but here, there were a half-dozen different brands available. The number of different clothing brands was somewhat alarming.

Although then again, she didn't exactly go out shopping much. Maybe this was normal? Emma chewed a piece of meat thoughtfully as she wandered onwards. Hm… Moving to Mitakihara had really turned her into a stereotypical shut in. She didn't have many friends, kept to herself, defended her preferred hobbies vigorously…

Jeez, she sounded like one of those gamers who hacked their implants to do VR dives. When had that happened? She remembered having friends outside of football back in London. Surely she hadn't always been like this.

Emma huffed. No, she was pretty sure it was a recent thing. If only she hadn't moved. It'd have been nice if she'd at least had some warning. But no, right at the end of the season, when she'd just gotten into her stride as team captain. There had been arrangements to make, team positions to reshuffle, last minute retraining, ugh.

It'd all been completely mad, and it'd only been half of what needed to be done. The remainder, things that had gone way over Emma's head at the time, had been taken care of by Coach Williams. When all was said and done, Emma had managed to get things sorted in time, but really.

Emma scraped up a spoonful of sauce and stirred it into her mashed potatoes. Truth be told, it was probably time to let it go. Dwelling on this was killing her gem. She'd… well, she'd managed to deal with it all. Mitakihara wasn't that bad, not really, and logistics and economics were things she didn't hate with complete unholy passion. Just… just some passion, yeah.

A mental ping pulled her out of this line of thought. Moments later her tactical interface rebooted. Emma grinned. This was a good sign. Her TacComp must have finally self-repaired to a point where it could process basic functions. As she watched, toolbars and message boxes tiled in. They were all familiar, if mostly empty, and a welcome sight after running on only the rudimentary HUD for hours.

"Conducting self diagnostic," said a familiar synthetic voice. "Please wait. Estimating time remaining… fifteen minutes."

Good. She would take some time to fiddle with it later. That reminded her, there was also the implant diagnostic she had been meaning to run. It would be a bit of a pain, but it was probably wise to do it sooner rather than later. Her TacComp might need hours to finish repairs, and she had no idea when the MagOps team would be back.

Emma paused in front of a crate full of teddy bears to finish her meal. She felt mostly full, but might grab another food pack in a bit. The teddy bears brought a nostalgic smile. She and Anna had each been given one way back when, and had dragged them around everywhere. Then she'd gotten into football and used Anna's for over-enthusiastic childish penalty kick practice. That had gone predictably terribly. Anna had cried for days afterwards.

Impulsively, Emma picked up one of the teddy bears, somewhat gangly-limbed with a blue ribbon around its neck, and carried it back to the crate she had been sitting on before. She crumpled the tray into a ball and shoved it into the empty wrapper, then carefully placed the teddy bear into her backpack. She had a sudden desire to have a teddy bear, and nobody would miss the one.

That done, Emma cleared out enough space to sit down against the crate. The diagnostic would probably ruin any spacial awareness she had, and she didn't want to come out of the dive sprawled inelegantly across the crate. Especially if Nodoka or someone else from the MagOps team came to pick her up. She'd embarrassed herself enough already.

Training had made sure to cover how to use the Universal Command Prompter. It was a slow and clunky way of going about implant I/O in an age of artificial telepathy, but it had its uses. Emma plugged the data cable into the back of her neck, then into the transmitter she'd pulled from the IFV back by Cluster 14. She fitted a battery into the transmitter's power supply, then daisy chained a few more together. It was probably not that safe, but it would do.

Now, Emma just had to remember what she was supposed to do. She pulled up the UCP and stared at it blankly.

"Uhhh… oh right, _system update /force_," she thought at the blipping cursor.

Emma's world abruptly cut out, before she began falling endlessly and accelerating. Complete pressing nothingness overwhelmed her. Emma unsuccessfully fought against rising panic, belatedly recalling that this had, in fact, happened in training.

Then an impossibly loud bing as her auditory cortex came back online, followed swiftly by her olfactory system. She could smell beef stew most strongly, followed by… well it was herself, clearly. At some level, everyone knew what they smelled like, of course, but she'd never taken the time to sniff herself before. Who did that?

Then a flash of white text. Emma mentally recoiled as streams and streams of information spiraled across her vision. It was all moving too fast to read, and the sheer glut of data was dizzying. Emma picked out something about mind-to-mind communication and muscular enhancements.

The word "ERROR" kept appearing with alarming frequency. There wasn't nearly enough time to figure out what was error-ing out, but it was enough for Emma to feel nervous about combat. What if something failed half way through? What if her data I/O wasn't functional and she didn't get any updates? Alright, fine, most of what she did was uniquely magical, but it wasn't as if they gave you an exhaustive list of the implants you had. Cascading failure could happen, after all, and—

—the world clicked off as the logos of Chronos Biologics and Hephaestus Nanotechnology blinked across her vision. Another, quieter, bling, and then everything rushed back in.

Emma jerked back to her body with a gasp. Everything burned and sparked, as if she'd been dropped into a vat of liquid nitrogen, left for a few seconds, and then doused with molten iron.

Well, that was probably hyperbole, but calling it a "tingle" was complete understatement.

With a groan, Emma sat up. Her tactical interface rebooted a moment later, almost cheerfully telling her that the reset had restored some other basic functions to her TacComp, including hardware management protocols. Would she like to access these now?

Yes, yes she would. A window blinked open, turning translucent to overlay her field of view. A list rapidly propagated, along with several columns of information.

…Goddess, half her implants were nonfunctional. The readout was also totally unhelpful, merely stating that "the requested implant technology cannot be found". Were they burned out? Was her diagnostic malfunctioning? Did the firmware on the implants get corrupted?

Completely useless.

But, at least, her I/O implants were definitely working, and she had a much more useful TacComp than she'd thought. It was already capable of very, very basic computing. File management, running scripts, et cetera. It'd probably be another day to get even close to full combat capacity, but anything was better than nothing.

More worryingly, her medical implant readiness kept flickering between 30 and 98 percent. A two-percent degradation was easily manageable, but if Emma actually only had access to 30% of her implants' regeneration capabilities, any hit she took would burn through her gem like fire through tissue paper.

Still, things seemed alright at face value. Emma stood, flexed her limbs, and stretched, testing the feel of her body. If everything was, indeed, broken, she at least felt like she could do things as usual.

Well, trusting in her body to be ready was something Emma was used to. There was a special device that suppressed some implant functions, to keep football games even. A lot of the nervousness that went into games came from fear of not being ready for the struggle to come. Emma knew how to deal with that.

A small flicker at the edge of Emma's consciousness made her pause. The sensation was a bit like someone running a handkerchief over your face. You could feel it whenever Rebecca was using her powers and you were within range. Just enough warning to shield yourself during training, if you weren't part of the day's exercise.

But Rebecca was back with the rest of the military, and her range wasn't more than a kilometer. Maybe someone else? One of the MagOps? Tentatively, Emma reached out telepathically.

"Hello?"

"Ah, hello!" said a voice, inflected with a slightly excessive amount of cheer. "There you are! I thought your signal was around here."

"Who are you?" asked Emma. The voice sounded perfectly androgynous to her, but maybe she was just out of it.

"My name is Senbey!" said the voice. "I am an Incubator!"

Emma blinked. They told you in training, if there wasn't a more convenient disposal method, to just drop your grief cubes when you maxed them out. An Incubator would swing by at some point to pick them up, but it wasn't preferred. Grief cubes spawned demons, after all.

"What are you doing here then?" asked Emma. "I thought you'd have picked up all the grief cubes by now."

"As it turns out, we hadn't!" said Senbey. "The pile you left behind in the bunker tipped us off that you were alive, and I've been trying to get a fix on your position ever since!"

Emma winced. Partly because she now realized she'd forgotten to clean up her grief cubes, but more because Senbey's voice had spiked into the higher registers. It was the closest she'd ever felt to "eardrum piercing" in her head, and it was bound to give her a headache.

"Could you uh, tone it down a bit?" she asked.

"Hm? Oh, I am sorry, I must be sounding excited again," said Senbey. Its voice ticked marginally downwards in pitch and volume, to just barely a manageable level. "I am young by Incubator standards. Interacting with you all is occasionally difficult."

A moment later, the Incubator faded into existence, six inches from the top of the crate. Emma blinked as Senbey fell the short distance with a flail of limbs and a flump.

"Calculation error again," muttered Senbey telepathically, slightly crumpled. "How do the others keep doing this so well?"

"Um…."

"Oh, hello!" said Senbey, popping up into a sitting position. The fur still stood out at odd angles from the disorganized fall. "Hello, hello, hi, how are you?"

Emma blinked at Senbey again. "…you're not very good at this, are you?"

Senbey seemed to pout. "Maa, Emma, just because I'm young…."

"As if that actually means anything," said Emma, frowning. "It's been hours, how are you just now getting to me?"

Senbey looked contrite. "Unfortunately, we had already reallocated resources to other things— Not that you are not important!" it tagged on hastily as Emma glowered, "but moving resources around requires a lot of different Incubators to agree and then there's the other girls to think about and that's why it took so long to find you."

Emma glared. "So other than making me angry, why are you here?" she asked, folding her arms.

"Well!" said Senbey, waving its tail back and forth cheerily. "Given the fact that you've somehow managed to get aaallllll the way back to the suburbs, you've shown some remarkable resilience to your gem! It really does warrant further study, even if it's a bit of an unusual time, so I'm here to formally request the chance to follow you around! Past experience indicates that humans object to being observed for some reason, but tend to be less antagonistic if asked beforehand."

"It's great to know that I'm a science project for you," said Emma sarcastically. "Truly an honor."

"Excellent! If you don't mind, then, I will be taking a nap!"

"Wait- no, that's not—," sputtered Emma ineffectually. It was too late though. The Incubator had curled up in the exact center of the crate and begun snoring softly.

"Ugh," said Emma exasperatedly, before sitting down against the crate again. Goddess damned Incubators. Kyubey had at least been something resembling courteous, but this guy….

Emma sighed and closed her eyes, settling in for a nap herself. At least the Incubator had something right. Naps were always good.

"You've seen the future, right Madoka?" asked Sayaka.

"Well, sort of," said Madoka. She and Sayaka were lying on a grassy field spotted with flowers. Overhead, countless stars in an infinite variety of color sparkled against a dark sky. "It depends on a lot of things."

"But you've seen something, at least?"

"Yes," said Madoka.

"Can you tell me?"

"…it's… no, I don't think I can."

"Why?"

"Because I'm afraid that if I do, I'll make it happen."

"What, you're superstitious?" asked Sayaka incredulously. "About what? Yourself?"

Madoka giggled. "It's silly, I know, but…."

"Whatever," said Sayaka, rolling her eyes. "It's, well, I guess it's not that important anyway. I was just curious."

There was a gust of wind that tossed flower petals into the air. When the wind died down, no trace remained that anyone had been there.

"Oi. Emma, was it? Wake up."

Emma rubbed her eyes and looked up. Nodoka was standing over her, looking slightly more amused than before.

"Oh, hey," said Emma sleepily. "Is it time to go?"

"Well I'd just leave you there drooling otherwise," said Nodoka. "C'mon, up and at 'em."

Emma hurriedly wiped her mouth and brushed the saliva onto her costume. "So, um, what's the plan?" she asked, standing and tossing her backpack on. Senbey had disappeared.

"First, you aren't doing anything," said Nodoka. She pulled her mask down and adjusted it. "We've got enough issues without you mucking about. Just don't panic and do something stupid."

"Oh."

Nodoka glanced at her. "And get any ideas that you can keep up with us in combat out of your head. You're too green."

"No, I understand," said Emma, looking away with embarrassment. "I uh. I'm sorry about earlier."

"Eh, whatever," said Nodoka with a shrug. She gestured for Emma to follow. "S'long as you get the reality of the situation."

Emma nodded as they climbed the stairs. "So, uh, me following aside, what else is happening?"

"Well, in response to you appearing and us blowing up part of a supply depot, the squid have sent an extra company's worth of seek and destroy drones," said Nodoka. The stairway opened into a hallway by some bathrooms, then directly into the open courtyard. Emma didn't see or feel anyone. "So getting to the extraction point is going to be a bit hairy, even with Maria's stealth generation skills."

In retrospect, it was probably all staged just to scare her. Emma jumped as three more girls, all wearing skull masks at various angles, appeared to bracket her.

"That's Mia," said Nodoka, coming to a stop and turning. She nodded at a girl with a scarlet headband tied around her eyes, the rest of her costume a dress of assorted whites and blues. "Team sensor type. Say hi, Mia."

"Hi."

"Maria's the girl to your rear," continued Nodoka. Maria was alarmingly black, in the sense that she seemed to be actively made of shadow, with eyes that glittered yellow. "She's our stealth generator. You know what powers I've got, and I pull close range and command duty. Last but not least is Miss Aggressively Scottish over there, Agapita."

Emma turned to the only girl she hadn't met, even as Agapita protested that she wasn't THAT Scottish, dammit. To be fair, part of Agapita's costume was perfectly plain. Her shirt and vest were white and black, respectively, with gold buttons and a pointless watch chain. Then came flat black trousers, neatly pressed, and classic wingtip patent leather boots that shone with a mirror finish.

This was somewhat offset by the cloak swung around her shoulders, woven in bright red and green plaid. A small hat sat perched atop her head, the brim curled on one side and a large white feather sticking out of it. Most prominently, though, were the—

"Bagpipes?" asked Emma incredulously. "Are you serious?"

"Oh shut, up new girl," said Agapita. "Yes they're bagpipes and no it doesn't make me more Scottish. Irish people used to play bagpipes too!"

"Yeah, but they didn't march into battle with them," said Nodoka teasingly. "And the fuckin' plaid you have going there isn't helping."

"To be fair," interjected Emma, "you're not really doing it right if you're wearing part of a three piece under a cloak. It's not actually Scottish, it's just a cloak at that point."

"See, I told you!" said Agapita. "And besides, it's not like plaid automatically makes it Scottish. You're just being racist."

"Ugh, fine, fine, we're wasting time anyway." said Nodoka, rolling her eyes. "Anyway, the plan. Usual business for a target saturated environment, everyone knows the drill. Newbie, you stay with Agapita."

"Er, right," said Emma. It seemed a weird assignment, considering Maria was the stealth generator, but she'd put her foot in her mouth enough times in the last forty-eight hours.

The group moved out. They scattered across a wide area, moving through destroyed buildings to give themselves a bit of cover. The ruined structures had little in terms of obstructions to slow them down though, and the team and Emma made good time across the suburbs.

"So what's your name?" asked Agapita.

"Uh, Emma Sinclair."

"Really?" asked Agapita. "Huh."

"What?"

"Well, my family name is Burnside-Sinclair," said Agapita. "It's probably the single most English thing you've ever heard."

Emma snorted. "It is. Are you from England, or are you just named that way?"

"Nah, the whole family's from England. I'm from East London."

"Oh hey," said Emma, grinning. "I'm from Canary Wharf, myself."

"Aww yeah, Londoners for the win!" said Agapita with a grin. "You seen the expansion to the starport they're making? Gonna be epic."

"No, uh," said Emma, wilting. The two of them ducked into the upper floors of a ruined apartment block. "My family moved."

Agapita frowned. "...Well, I'll find you later and fill you in," she promised as they shot out into the rain again. "Like I said, the thing's gonna be epic."

"I'll look forward to it," said Emma with a smile.

Agapita smiled back, but nodded at the run. "Pay attention now, let's not get shot."

"Right."

Emma took a deep breath and focused on where they were going. The MagOps team had distributed itself across several hundred yards, staying within telepathy range of each other and Maria's magic. They hadn't encountered anything yet. Still, considering the number of drones that should have been incoming…

"I'm getting kind of nervous about this," Emma mentioned to Agapita as they continued running. "This doesn't seem right."

"Yeah, same here," said Agapita. "Nodoka's noticed by now, so we should be—."

Emma and Agapita ducked to the side simultaneously as a laser blast tore through where they'd been a moment ago.

"There they are!" said Agapita, tugging Emma into a building and shooting through the ruins as a dozen attack drones chased after them. "We'll have to shake them!"

"Why not—?" Emma began to say, but cut herself off as she leaped upwards to roll through a broken window, then pushed herself through the air into the building across the street. Agapita was close behind, having made the leap without using aeromaneuver. "Why not just shoot them?"

Agapita huffed. "I'd love to, but it's the worst plan possible."

Emma began to protest, then reconsidered. In the field, knocking out a set of drones usually meant that they wouldn't be replaced. You usually had friendly drones that could take over those positions, but in the rear of the enemy line, that was impossible.

Damn.

"Turn left, advance thirty meters, then turn right," ordered Nodoka. "On my mark…. mark."

Abruptly, Agapita changed direction as they passed through another window and onto the street. Emma barely kept up, skidding on one foot as she hurriedly pumped magic downwards to grip the surface, then launching herself toward Agapita. A small jet of wind cut her forward speed just as Agapita turned right, giving Emma time to—

—tumble headlong as a series of explosions went off just behind her. An instinctual magic shield caught most of the debris that was flung at her, but the explosion was mostly noise and light. Very loud noise and very bright light.

Emma autocorrected as best she could while deaf and partially blinded. She stumbled slightly on the landing, bounced onto a nearby wall, and ran for several meters before leaping off to jump from ruin to ruin. A flash of red heralded Agapita's position.

"Good, we didn't lose track of you," said Agapita with a relieved sigh, running onward.

"Sorry for falling behind," said Emma as she caught up.

"Just try to do better next time," said Agapita. She glanced behind them. "Drones are clear though. Thanks Maria."

"Just doing my job," answered Maria. Her voice was a silky hiss that left Emma's hair standing on end.

"What the hell-?!"

"Side effect of the transformation," whispered Maria. "Hehehe, newbies. Always get freaked out by it, you do."

Emma shivered. "I guess you get used to it."

"Oh it's quite pleasant in the right context," said Agapita with a small grin.

Complete silence.

"Wait, what?" asked Emma. Had she just implied-?

"Don't worry about it-" began Maria, but she never got a chance to finish.

"Contact left!" Nodoka shouted over telepathy. "All units bear right!"

"Shit," said Agapita, pivoting and shooting rightward. Emma was ready this time and followed reasonably well.

"What's going on?"

"Platoon," said Mia. She sounded much more pleasant than Maria did. "We'll be alright."

Emma nodded, then realized Mia couldn't see. "Uh, right."

"Building ahead," called Nodoka. "Labeling it on your comps now. Regroup on the second floor."

Emma blinked, then mentally poked her TacComp. She'd completely forgotten about it.

"This unit is still repairing," reported the TacComp. "Basic functionalities have been restored."

A second later, a waypoint blipped onto her vision, prompting a grin. Ah, jeez, it was good to have even a basic-functions-only TacComp.

"Shadow cloak activated," hissed Maria. "We are invisible for the next twenty seconds."

A dark haze dropped onto Emma, staining her body into a dark, grayed out version of herself. It was slightly freaky, but lasted only briefly. Twenty seconds, as it turned out, was plenty. Agapita and Emma slipped into the building, a relatively undamaged apartment block, with eight seconds to spare.

"Everyone okay?" asked Nodoka. A chorus of affirmatives. "Good. Mia?"

"The extraction point is lousy with squid," said Mia. "It feels like about a platoon's worth, with the complimentary drones."

"Have Agapita lead us in?" suggested Maria.

"That's an idea," said Nodoka. "What else?"

"Could blow them up," said Agapita. "Newbie's rather eager."

"Call it a backup plan," said Nodoka. "Any places to hole up and wait for them to lose interest?"

"Not in the area," said Maria. "Could wait in here, but we don't—."

"Have enough cubes, right," said Nodoka. "Looks like it's a Tattoo then. Agapita, you ready for this?"

"Oh hell yes," said Agapita with a grin. "I was born ready."

Emma blinked confusedly.

"What?"

3. Homecoming Parade

"This is insane," said Emma.

"Shush," replied Agapita.

The plan had been heinously, ridiculously simple. Agapita would play a song on her bagpipes as the group marched stolidly down the main thoroughfare to the extraction point, where the teleporters would pick them up. Nodoka had developed some degree of clairvoyance, so she would be guiding the teleporters in. Maria could cloak everyone from sensors before they bugged out.

Teleporters plural, yes. Emma hadn't realized, but in hindsight it was obvious. If you needed to really, really rapidly extract a team, then you would have one girl drop herself and another teleporter in with the team, and then have the second teleporter instantaneously pull everyone out. With the combination of cloaking and clairvoyance, it would be fast and secure, with a minimum of expenditure for nearly everyone involved.

But Goddess, the lead up.

Emma took deep, calming breaths as she marched behind Agapita. Maria, Nodoka, who carried Agapita's gem, and Mia followed behind. Maria was trailing black smoke as she marched, magic coiled, leaving Nodoka continuously fighting a sneeze. Agapita made sure the bagpipes were inflated as they went.

"Incoming," said Mia with compete calm. Emma gulped. She really wanted to duck into cover.

Then, with eerie serenity, Agapita began to play.

She began with a drawn out tone from the long pipes. Then, just as the first drones appeared, she began trilling out an even tune, clearly written for marching. Emma felt a tingle wash over her skin and her nervousness fade away. It wasn't the squashing down that emotional suppression created, but rather a firm, and growing, confidence that the team was going to be fine.

The drones were affected as well. They wavered briefly, then quietly switched off. The flying drones clunked to the ground, while ground-based, dog-sized drones simply keeled over where they stood. Emma blinked at this as she continued to march behind Agapita, who seemed tireless in her bagpipe playing.

"What's going on?" Emma asked Nodoka.

"Agapita's got the ability to drop entire companies of squid with those pipes of hers," said Nodoka. "It's not even that they explode or whatever. Somehow they just… switch off."

"Like the drones."

"Exactly like the drones."

"That's… that's really creepy."

"Don't tell her you said that," said Nodoka, stifling a grin and another sneeze. "Fweh. Still, it works really well."

Emma pursed her lips and kept marching. What they really needed was a drummer. Emma's fingers twitched, trying to tap a cadence out as Agapita continued playing. Actual squid were showing up now, arraying themselves across the way and bringing weapons to bear. Astoundingly, they didn't open fire. It was impossible for anyone except a magical girl. One by one, the squid stood to attention and lowered their weapons. As Agapita passed them, they crumpled to the ground.

"Cubes," said Agapita shortly as she continued playing. "Nodoka."

"Right," said Nodoka. She cupped Agapita's gem in her hands, holding it close to Maria. The wisps of smoke concealed the gem and the grief cubes neatly, making it seem like Nodoka was holding her hands out in some sort of religious gesture.

"If you grab my ass, Nodoka," hissed Maria. "I swear—."

"Just because you're the team uke doesn't mean—."

"Is this the time?" asked Emma shortly. She could feel her cheeks reddening.

"Aww, is the newbie embarrassed?" teased Nodoka. "Hey hey, maybe later we should—."

"Nodoka, stop," said Mia, stifling a giggle. She reached forward and pinched Nodoka hard on the back of the neck. "You're letting the magic affect you again."

"Ah— ow! Sorry, sorry, jeez."

Emma resisted the urge to shake her head, a grin spinning its way onto her face anyway. Agapita's magic was starting to have an euphoric effect. It was like when you knew your team was on a roll, during a game, and victory was almost assured. You just had to close out the next few minutes and it'd be a perfect finish.

"We're almost there," said Mia. "Nodoka, concentrate."

Nodoka cleared her throat and coughed. "Right, right. Black Parade to Flash One, we're ready for extraction. Be advised, we've got a greenie from the sticks with us, and will be under cloak. Home in on my link for the teleport."

"Understood Black Parade," replied one of the teleporters. "We'll, uh, plan for one extra and home in with your clairvoyance. Teleport conditions?"

"Hot, but cloaking should cover it," said Nodoka. Her voice was getting steadily more grounded. The mental activity necessary to coordinate helped her shake off the effects of Agapita's magic. Just listening in was keeping Emma's euphoria in check.

"Understood, we'll drop in on your mark then," said the teleporter.

The extraction point, where the limit of the teleporters' ranges were, was just ahead. The number of squid had been steadily increasing as the team had penetrated deeper into enemy space. Agapita was still perfectly fluid in her movement, playing ceaselessly and flawlessly as they continued the march. She didn't seem in any way affected by her efforts, even though Nodoka had already begun draining grief from Agapita's gem.

Then again, no sense taking chances. The team and Emma advanced through a large intersection, where an enemy IFV spontaneously shut itself off, and into a bombed out office building. Automated turrets sparked and failed themselves. Mines clicked into safe mode. It was the most singularly smooth entrance Emma had ever seen.

Maria's magic spread out now, blanketing them in black fog. Emma was briefly startled as she looked down and saw her feet, legs, and torso disappear, but quickly came to grips with it as Agapita worked her magic. The group came to a stop inside the main atrium, grouping into a circle around Agapita.

"We're ready," announced Nodoka.

"Understood," said the teleporter. "In three, two, one—."

A rapid fire flash of blue then orange. Emma blinked as the concrete and hazard-lines of a teleportation room came into focus. Agapita immediately stopped playing with a sigh of relief.

"And that, Ladies," said Nodoka with a satisfied grin, "is how we do that."

The debriefing of MagOps Team 4, "the Black Parade", was scheduled to happen almost immediately. There was a bit of allowance for everyone to untransform and drop their extra equipment into a locker. The exception was Emma, who wasn't allowed to untransform for unspecified reasons and soon headed to the nearest medical center.

"Hey, don't forget to tell me where you're staying," said Agapita as attendants pursed their libs at Emma's delay. "I still need to update you on everything back home."

"Couldn't we just mental transfer?" asked Emma. "I mean, it seems more efficient."

"Bah, it's no fun alone," said Agapita. "Trust me, I've got this program I pulled offa the net. It'll be cool!"

"Uh, sure, whatever then," said Emma, shrugging. One of the attendants began tapping a foot. "I should go."

"Take care of yourself, newbie," said Nodoka as Emma made placating gestures and began to edge away.

"Yeah, stay safe," added Maria, voice now returned to normal. She was actually rather pretty as a normal person rather than a shadow ghoul. "Don't do anything stupid."

"Yeah, yeah," said Emma, waving as she got ushered off, trailing mud and bits of masonry. "See you guys around or something."

The redoubt's ceilings were lower than Emma would have preferred. The entire structure was made of concrete with alloy rebar, designed to hold up to massive explosions that would level large amounts of surface-Helsinberg. Still, this didn't mean that everything was pure utilitarian, monochrome, exposed concrete. Every hallway was painted over with semi-intelligent paint. The default was a gentle shade of mauve, but you could perceive it as whatever color you wanted.

It also served as a convenient backup for if there was a breach and the network went down. When under attack, the paint automatically transitioned to high visibility white-on-blue and provided directions over your implants. It couldn't be hacked, either, though she had no idea why.

Emma decided on a pastel lime green. It was the sort of color you'd expect from a macaron. A bit of fiddling got the walls to display a translucent overlay of fleur-de-lis patterns. Maybe she could—

A mental yoink made her veer left suddenly. She autocorrected and dodged a passing drone as the attendants came to a stop with sighs.

"Pay attention, please," said one of the attendants exasperatedly. "Your health is important, and it's best to get it checked as soon as possible."

"Sorry, sorry," said Emma. She rubbed the back of her head sheepishly.

"Come on," said the other attendant. Emma followed them, actually paying attention this time, into the med center. She was lead into an examination room, where a nurse and small platoon of medical drones were waiting.

Emma stopped short at the doorway. "Is this really necessary?" she asked, raising an eyebrow.

"Just in case," said the attendant, gently pushing Emma inwards.

Reluctantly, Emma shuffled into the room.

"Hello!" greeted the nurse, extending a hand to shake. "My name's Angelo Huerta, how are you feeling?"

"I feel fine," said Emma, shaking his hand. "My name is Emma Sinclair."

"It's good to meet you, Emma," said Angelo with a smile. "I understand this all looks rather intimidating, but I'm sure you know how important we all consider magical girls to be. We just want to be absolutely sure that you're okay, alright?"

"I, uh, I guess," said Emma. "I was uh, I was told that I shouldn't untransform yet."

"That's correct," said Angelo. He led her over to one of the drones. "We need to take a baseline of your gem's drainage rate, to make sure it's within expected bounds. If you could?"

"Just put it in this slot here?" asked Emma, pulling out her gem and stepping to the machine. It had a housing for her gem and a box of grief cubes. The idea, apparently, was to keep a digital eye on her gem by measuring the amount it glowed, then feed it cubes when needed. "And uh, why does the rate matter?"

"The MHD uses it to evaluate if they need to do an emergency visit," said Angelo. The machine whirred briefly, then beeped. "The results will be sent to the MHD. You're well within normal ranges though, so you're free to untransform and change."

The rest of the examination went about as expected. Emma's street clothes, her jeans especially, had gotten ragged from the long slog. They were sent off to the laundry for repairs. Emma had been given a set of generic underclothes and loose, airy pants and shirt. Angelo ended up being somewhat redundant, acting only as a technician to begin the repairs to Emma's implants and TacComp. The drones took care of everything.

"Well, I'll let you rest," said Angelo, leaving Emma swinging her legs on the side of the bed. "We'll need to keep you under observation for a few hours, but since you're looking good, we've sent a notification to your unit commander and friends. It's set to automatically propagate after they get after duty."

"Oh, ok," said Emma with a relieved sigh. She had been worried she might ruin someone's concentration. Then she grimaced. "Do I really need to stay here?"

"I'm sorry, but it's procedure," said Angelo. He smiled commiseratingly and shrugged.

"Ah, fine, whatever," said Emma, sighing again. She flopped backwards onto the bed. "This sucks."

"I understand," said Angelo. "We have a list of vids and games you can try, if your friends take—."

The door chimed urgently.

"Ah, I assume—," began Angelo, stepping to the side and deactivating the privacy locks. He never got a chance to finish as Ayane literally flew into the room, slamming into Emma and knocking her back onto the bed.

"You stupid, stupid idiot!" shouted Ayane, clutching tightly onto Emma's body as she cried. "I— I was— I was so scared you were—!"

Emma wrapped her arms around Ayane as the other girl dissolved into wracking sobs. Unnoticed to either of them, Angelo quietly slipped out and closed the door behind him to leave them alone. It would be unprofessional for him to stay, and there wasn't anything pressing anyway.

"Shh, shh, I'm back," said Emma, rubbing soothing circles into Ayane's back. "I'm sorry, I'm sorry…"

"Stupid," murmured Ayane into Emma's chest. She weakly punched Emma in the shoulder. "Stupid stupid stupid. W-What'd you go and get lost for?"

"Shh, I'm sorry, don't worry, I'm back now," said Emma soothingly. She patted Ayane on the head, then smoothed her braid back. Ayane was wearing generic hospital clothing as well. "Wait, why're you in hospital clothes? Are you hurt?"

"Mm-mm," said Ayane. "I— they, t-the MHD, made me check in for o-observation. They were afraid I'd f-fade."

Emma bit her lip and pulled Ayane closer. "Oh, Ayane," she whispered. "I am so, so sorry. I didn't mean to… to…"

Ayane sniffed. "Idiot."

"I'm sorry."

"…I-It's okay," Ayane managed. "Y-you're back now."

"Yeah," said Emma. She rubbed her head against Ayane's. "Do you… do you want to stay a bit? Watch a vid?"

Ayane nodded. She let Emma up and sat nearby, rubbing at her eyes. Emma levered herself upright, popping out a crick in her back from Ayane's tackle.

"S-sorry," said Ayane. She sat with her hands in her lap, fiddling with the hem of her shirt and looking away from Emma.

"Don't worry about it," said Emma. She directed the bed to auto-recline, letting them lean back against it. "I, ah, understand where you're coming from."

Ayane smiled wobblily at Emma. "T-thanks. If, um, if you don't mind, could I…?"

She looked away again, this time blushing.

Emma felt herself blushing as well. It made sense, sort of, that Ayane wanted more bodily contact. Some people were more comforted by being able to touch someone. Emma wasn't one of them, but a well timed hug or pat on the shoulder could do wonders for a teammate feeling discouraged. What Ayane was asking was a little more than that, and really, Emma wanted to help her feel better, but, well…

"I'm, uh, uh," stammered Emma. "This is, uh…"

"If you're not comfortable—."

"No it's fine," said Emma immediately. "Er, that is, it's… I'm not… really into girls, and uh, if you are, I don't want to send mixed messages."

"Oh, nonono," said Ayane. "S-sorry, I didn't mean it like that. I mean, I guess yes, I'm kind of interested, but not right now, and uh—."

"As long as I'm not going to screw things up, it's fine," said Emma quickly, saving Ayane from further stammered responses. "I know that, uh, physical contact, can help people, so um… yeah."

There was a brief silence that Emma filled with awkwardly shuffling back and forth, before adjusting the bed's recline pointlessly and moving over to lean back against it. The bed dipped slightly as Ayane moved over to sit close to her.

There was a brief moment of hesitation, before Ayane wrapped her arms around one of Emma's. The tightness of Ayane's grip, while not enough to be painful or cut circulation, pressed her close against Emma. The heat that radiated off of Ayane had a strange double effect on Emma. Part of her wanted to edge away, but another part of her wanted to get closer. She compromised by doing neither.

She was also highly aware of the fact that Ayane's body was surprisingly soft and yielding. It was probably a result of being a science-type person. Emma wasn't used to it. She was used to running into people who were more tightly muscled, able to put up resistance against a hit. The exact opposite to… this.

"So, um, what do you want to watch?" asked Emma. The list of vids propagated across their vision in a shared arc.

"Mm, I dunno," said Ayane. "Something kinda quiet?"

"Okay," said Emma. "How does this one sound?"

The title of the vid was "These Dimmed City Lights". It was about an old, embittered Soul Guard getting embroiled into a massive investigation. Multiple made-up matriarchies, a few mobsters, and a slinky Shizuki girl were all involved. That last one would certainly be a protagonist, given the politics of dealing with real matriarchies.

It was extremely bog-standard. The usual sort of vid that producers made for not-to-well-known actors who had some decent talent. But it would probably be fairly low key, which was what Ayane wanted, and have a few nice action sequences, which would keep Emma suitably entertained.

Ayane considered. "Mmm… it sounds decent. Let's try it."

"Do you, uh, want to get any food or something?" asked Emma as the vid started.

Ayane shook her head.

"Alright then."

The two of them laid back as the film began. The bed was luxuriously comfortable. Tilted at just the right angle, Emma could feel herself nodding off. That was odd, but she had been given quite a lot of drugs for implant repair. Maybe this was a side effect.

With a sleepy blink, Emma checked the progress on her implants. There were a lot of chemicals that the implants produced, along with the drugs, to help with repairs and integration into the body, but that apparently wasn't the culprit. What was making her so tired was the energy draw from the implants in order to finish repairs. The status dialogue even warned that drowsiness and disorientation may occur, and that she should find a place to rest.

Well, Emma wasn't going to be disoriented anytime soon. She yawned hugely. The heat from Ayane's body was amplifying her sleepiness.

"Sleepy cat," said Ayane. She poked Emma teasingly in the side.

"Mmgnh," mumbled Emma. She let herself slowly sag into Ayane, head drooping onto the other girl's shoulder. "S'rry."

"It's okay," said Ayane.

"The implants'r, um, weird," explained Emma sleepily.

Ayane nodded. "Go to sleep."

"But the vid…"

"It's fine, don't worry."

"M'kay…"

"…Emma?"

"Mm?"

"I'm glad you're back."

Emma slowly slipped out of sleep. Blinking, she yawned and rubbed her face into Ayane's shoulder. Nnnh… soft.

"Hey, are you up?" asked Ayane. She poked Emma gently in the cheek. "You've got visitors."

Emma blinked again and looked up. A small group was gathered around her bed.

"Oh," said Emma, breaking into a grin. "Hey guys."

Everyone had come to visit. Rebecca and Varsha had claimed a chair, with Rebecca sitting in Varsha's lap. Emily had occupied the other chair, and was trying very hard to look cool. Renee was perched on the end of the bed, petting Alanis' cat form.

"Hey yourself," said Alanis, shaking off Renee's hand and jumping off the bed. She slid back into human form as she fell, then turned and stretched. "Nnh. Did you sleep well?"

"Oh, uh, yeah, I guess?" said Emma. She realized suddenly that she'd managed to get herself tangled around Ayane's arm in her sleep. Emma consciously tried not to jerk away too quickly. Part of it was so that she didn't accidentally slight Ayane, but also because playing it casual would, hopefully, prevent any teasing that might occur.

She wasn't really sure she succeeded, in the end. Ayane's hand seemed to drift towards Emma's as Emma drew away, but it stopped early and landed on the covers instead. As the conversation began to pick up, Ayane scooted to the edge of the bed to let her legs dangle.

"You have got some nerve, leaving us in the lurch like that," said Renee with false haughtiness. The aristocratic air she was trying to project failed miserably as she smiled. "Welcome back, Emma."

"The projections for you were stupid low," said Varsha. "It's amazing that you survived, much less got back here in one piece."

"No, the projections were just stupid," said Rebecca with a confident nod. "I knew you'd be back, Emma. If you were gunna die, it'd be in a big firefight, not during a retreat."

"How d'you know that then?" asked Emma, raising an eyebrow.

"I'm a precognitor in secret, didn't you know?" asked Rebecca. "Right guys?"

There was a moment of pure silence.

"Aww, come on!"

Ayane rolled her eyes. "Yes, yes, you can see the future. Though—" She furrowed her brow. "—you are right, sometimes. It's a little freaky."

"Well anyway," said Emily, rolling her eyes at the younger girls. "Glad to see you're back in one piece, new girl."

"Bah, why so cold, Emily?" asked Emma, grinning. She hadn't realized Emily's attitude would be something she'd miss.

"Well you know," said Emily, doing her best to look casual, "not really looking forward to saving your ass again."

"Says the girl who was crying when she found out," quipped Rebecca.

Emily scowled at her. "Shut up."

Emma laughed. It really was good to be back. "You've all introduced yourselves then?"

"Yes, and nearly got into a fight besides," said Renee. "Ms. Cross took offense to Rebecca's teasing."

"Shut UP."

"In her defense," piped up Ayane. "Rebecca can be very loud."

Alanis nodded in agreement. "My poor ears," she said, wincing as she rubbed her ears.

"Hey, that's my girlfriend you're talking about!" protested Varsha with a grin. "Watch it, or I'll be forced to defend her honor!"

"Oh, my valorous princess," sighed Rebecca overdramatically, draping herself across Varsha. "Do not go forth unto battle for my sake, for surely only death awaits you!"

"Hey, hey, some support, c'mon!"

"But she's OLD!" cried Rebecca. "Have you not heard that experience outstrips the strength of youth?"

"Oi," said Alanis flatly, her ears matching her tone.

The group had a laugh at her expense.

"Hey, so, I don't see Qing Duo," said Emma after the laughter died down. "Is she still on duty or something?"

An awkward silence fell.

"Qing Duo didn't… make it, during the retreat," said Alanis.

Emma blinked, then swallowed hard. "O-oh. That's…"

"Yeah."

"D-did she, um, did she fade? Or was it…?"

"No, she faded away," said Emily. "She— her platoon got zeroed by squid artillery. She managed to help most of them get away before she died. It was—," Emily sniffed and swallowed, wiping at her eyes angrily. "It was actually really impressive to see. It just pisses me off that we couldn't do anything to help."

Emma bit her lip. It was a bad business. Getting hit by an artillery strike like that was inevitably bad. Sometimes it was because you screwed up, and other times there was nothing anyone could do about it. It was always devastating, unless…

…well, unless a magical girl pulled off a minor miracle, like Qing Duo had.

"I… I didn't know her as well as you guys did, but—," began Emma, before she paused to swallow. Her throat felt surprisingly thick. "But it sounds like, in the end…"

"It'd be the way I'd prefer to go," said Alanis. "I just wish she could be here."

"Yeah."

The group was quiet. Their silence was somber and contemplative. Death was a constant for magical girls. There were innumerable ways to die on the battlefield, after all. Even if, miraculously, there hadn't been a war going on, you would have still been dependent on grief cubes to survive. For them, few things were more tenuous than life.

Emma sighed. "We should have a ceremony," she said. Dwelling on this was bad for everyone involved. They had to move on. "Or, um, did you do that already?"

"No, we were… we were going to wait and do a joint one, actually," said Varsha. "It was looking grim, for you, so we figured we'd ask your unit if they wanted to come with. And then we found out about Qing Duo, so…."

"Alright," said Emma. Hearing her own funeral plans would be a little unnerving, but she pressed on grimly. "So, what arrangements did you guys make? Can we go ahead with them for Qing Duo?"

Alanis nodded, rubbing at an eye. "I just have to square some things away, since I'm our ranking officer. There's a city farther back in Kolasi where we can have a ceremony without risking getting bombed. We can hitch a ride on a supply drone to and back."

"Ranking officer?" asked Emma. "I thought you were a First Lieutenant?"

"Nah, Alanis got promoted," said Emily. She had dropped her act. It was too painful to keep it up. "She's Captain Siyankin now."

"Shush," said Alanis, sounding distinctly embarrassed despite everything. "Anyway. The plan we came up with was a bit of a picnic and a bonfire vigil. I… guess the others won't be coming now, so—."

"No, we didn't know her, but I think we'd all be willing to come honor Qing Duo," said Ayane. She glanced around and received nods from Renee, Varsha, and Rebecca. "So please, if you'll have us, we'd like to come too."

"In that case, please," said Alanis. "Qing Duo deserves more than three girls at her funeral. That doesn't change the plan all that much though."

"Alright," said Emma. She took a deep breath to center herself. It all felt a bit mad, but Emma preferred that. She could handle a little madness. It was stagnation that she couldn't handle. "When are we headed out?"

"There's still a week left," said Alanis. "We were going to wait it out a bit longer, for you. Seems like that was a good idea, yeah?"

Emma smiled. "Yeah. Thanks for not giving up on me."

4. Post Operative Care

Emma's repairs finished quickly. Ayane was found by a slightly panicked nurse soon afterwards, and given a vigorous scolding for running off. The group had a good laugh at Ayane's expense, before dispersing to leave Emma and Ayane in the hands of the medical personnel.

The two of them were quickly herded off to separate places. Both had mandatory psychiatric evaluations to attend, but Emma went to be debriefed first. She and Ayane bid each other farewell, then went their separate ways.

Emma's debriefing was several hallways over, in a sparsely furnished but well lit room. One of the intelligence officers from Division HQ greeted her as she entered, and quickly began sending a battery of questions her way. It was a standard physical debriefing, and Emma reported the facts as best she could. It was all saved for later use.

After what felt like an entire eon, Emma was dismissed and sent to her psych eval. She hovered apprehensively outside the door of the consultation room for her appointment, keeping it from opening specifically to put the appointment off a bit longer. It was a bit irrational of her, but for some reason she felt nervous. The only other time she'd been to a psychiatrist had been for her initial evaluation, back when she'd first contracted. She hadn't been nervous then though.

Ugh. Screw it.

Emma keyed the door, then stepped through. The room was small and sparsely decorated, belying its transitory nature. It had been left largely unfurnished, with a pair of comfortable looking armchairs surrounding a table in the center. A small synthesizer stood at the end for any drinks that might be asked for.

"Uh, hello," said Emma, closing the door behind her. It sealed out the noise in the hallway quite well.

"Hello," said the psychiatrist with a smile. She was part of the MHD as a matter of course. "How are you? Please, have a seat. My name is Jessica Valenti."

"I'm uh, I'm doing alright," said Emma as she sat across from Jessica.

"That's good," said Jessica. "Would you like anything to eat or drink?"

"Um, could I have a cup of tea, actually?" asked Emma.

"Sure," said Jessica. "You're British, so you'd want an English Cuppa, right? Tea from that one particular blend and milk?"

"Oh, yes, and two sugars please," said Emma, pleasantly surprised. "A Cuppa" was a British anachronism. She hadn't expected someone to randomly know what that was.

The synthesizer whirred and extruded two mugs.

"Here's yours," said Jessica. "I like my tea black though."

Emma raised an eyebrow as she took a sip. Mmmm… "It's so bitter though."

"Even if you adjust the strength?" asked Jessica.

"Well then it just gets bland and boring," said Emma. "You can't win with black tea, is what I'm saying here."

"Hmm, I suppose," said Jessica thoughtfully. She took another sip of her tea. "Well, maybe I'm just strange then."

"Mmm. Thanks for the cuppa, though."

"Don't mention it."

The drank in silence for a bit, Jessica apparently waiting for something. Emma stared at the contents of her cup, then looked up and to the left at the corner of the room. Then she looked down at the table, then back to her cup. After a moment, she took a deep breath.

"So, what are we doing today?" Emma asked.

"It's nothing to be worried about," said Jessica. "The MHD just wants a basic diagnostic. I'm sure you're fine, and this will just be a formality."

"Well, what do you need to ask me about?" asked Emma. She bit her lip and looked away. "I uh, I'd like to get this over with."

"Just a few questions about your experiences lately," said Jessica. "Your debrief's covered basic details, of course, but there were a few places I'd like to go over again."

Ah yes. This was the reason Emma had been nervous.

"…might as well get it over with," said Emma finally. She set her tea down and braced herself. "What do you want to talk about?"

"Well, let's start with your decision to have your platoon pull back without you," said Jessica. "It's a very interesting decision. The rationale you've provided makes sense, but can you tell me more about why protecting your platoon is so important to you?"

Emma raised an eyebrow in confusion. "I mean… how could it not be?"

"Can you elaborate?"

"Not really," said Emma, scratching her nose. "I mean, sure, there are times when it's not possible, but shouldn't you do everything you can? Do people think that it's not important?"

"Well, yes," said Jessica. "There are many who'd argue that the survival of a magical girl is worth a platoon of soldiers."

Emma frowned unhappily. "I… guess? In theory? But it's like, you can't just call one girl enough to cover an entire square kilometer. You need more people with experience who know what to do. Especially if you don't have the experience necessary."

"I see. Doesn't that seem kind of denigrating to you?"

"I mean, I'm not going to sugar coat this for myself," said Emma. "You can't do that, especially if you're put in a leadership position with a team to run. If you're not honest with yourself, you're just going to tear the team down."

"Can't you rely on the network's predictions and updates to keep things going?" asked Jessica. "Or even let your warrant officer worry about it all. You're young, as you said."

"I guess I could," said Emma. "But then what's the point of being an officer? I may as well resign and re-enlist as a private."

"You would say, then, that your rank is important to you?"

"I feel like I should act to deserve it, yeah," said Emma. "If you're going to be a leader, then you should lead."

"And do you think you can do that successfully?" asked Jessica.

"No," said Emma. "I mean, well, kind of? But I… I didn't do that great of a job, this time. Like I said, I think that I just don't have enough experience to deal with stuff on the scale of open combat that well. I'll get better though."

"Hm, I see," said Jessica. She blinked thoughtfully. "That's an interesting way of looking at things. Is there anything else you want to add?"

"Umm… not really."

"Alright, we'll move on," said Jessica. "Would you like more tea?"

Emma shook her head, fingering the edge of her hoodie. She suddenly felt like she'd said too much.

"Alright. Well then, next question, can you tell me more about your reaction to finding Third Platoon in the position they had been holding?"

Emma gulped and drank from her mug. She took a long time. Jessica shifting in slight impatience finally prompted her to stop stalling.

"I uh… I was upset," said Emma. "I… I…"

Jessica waited patiently.

"…Can I skip this question?" asked Emma, blinking rapidly. "I'd… I'd rather not talk about it."

"That's fine," said Jessica, nodding. "I will note, however, that most girls find it beneficial to talk about it eventually. Your friends will be more than willing to help, I'm sure, and the MHD is always open to listening."

"I— yeah, okay," said Emma. She licked her lips. "I'm just… I'm not ready yet."

"I understand," said Jessica. "In that case, can you tell me more about working with the Black Parade?"

"Oh, they were pretty cool," said Emma. "Though, I'm not sure how much of their innuendo I should take seriously."

"Like what?"

"Well, Nodoka called Maria the 'team uke'," said Emma. "If you're uh… well uh, it's kind of awkward…"

"I know the term," said Jessica, pressing her lips together firmly. Emma was almost certain the psychiatrist was blushing, but the lighting was just dim enough to make it ambiguous. "I wouldn't think too much of it. MagOps teams can be… unusual."

"I know, right?" asked Emma rhetorically. "Agapita played the bagpipes. It was a little creepy."

"How so?"

"She's got the ability to sort of directly force squid to drop dead or something," said Emma, shivering. "It was kind of cool at the time, but now that I think more about it..."

"Isn't one of your friends a mind controller though?"

"What, Rebecca? Rebecca's different."

"Can you elaborate?"

"I mean, it's a really just sort of a, uh, a tickling feeling," said Emma. "We got bored once and she led me on a dance. Like I said, it sort of tickled. But Agapita's power feels like… well it makes you really happy, I guess."

"Isn't that a… well, not unpleasant thing?"

"Normally, but its more subconscious than Rebecca's powers. You can't really feel Agapita's, and that's kinda freaky."

"I see," said Jessica. "Well, I've not had that experience, but you've taken it in stride it seems. How do you feel about your life in general then?"

"I mean… it could be better," said Emma. "I found out one of my teammates died today. That sucked."

"But overall…?"

"I guess in general, I'm sort of falling into the average newbie, aren't I?" said Emma. "You know, screws up a lot, has to get rescued by older girls, generally behaves unintelligently…"

"Well, all new contractees go through an acclimation period," said Jessica reassuringly. "Don't worry. It will get better."

"I hope so," said Emma. She sighed. "I've been making a right hash of it lately."

Jessica nodded sympathetically. "If it helps, you've been doing much better than I did."

"I mean, not really, but thanks for the sentiment," said Emma. She smiled a little at Jessica. "I measure myself against what I expect from myself is all."

"You're a footballer, if I recall?"

"Yes."

"That would explain a lot then," said Jessica. "Sports people tend to be like that. The drive for self improvement, right?"

"Yeah, exactly," said Emma.

"How do you feel about going back into combat then?" asked Jessica.

"Pretty good, I'd like to get moving," said Emma with a decisive nod. "It's… I dunno, I don't like sitting for too long."

"I understand," said Jessica. "If that's the case, then I think we're done here. I'll see about getting you something to do while the administration spins."

"Do you think, uh, that it's going to be alright?" asked Emma hopefully.

"I do, actually," said Jessica. "You appear to be coping well, even though you've had some trying experiences. The adolescent mind is more malleable and adaptive, so that's to be expected."

Emma grinned as she got up to go. "I'll uh, I'll look forward to my approval for combat duty then."

"Well, don't get your hopes up," said Jessica. "This meeting has been recorded, and someone senior to me will review it. If they decide that I missed something, they'll want to have you do another eval."

"Oh," said Emma, deflating. "I see."

"But we'll see," said Jessica. She sent Emma her contact information. "If you ever want to talk, send me a chat request, okay?"

"Alright," said Emma. Her TacComp filed it away for her. "Thanks, I guess."

"You're very welcome," said Jessica. She gave Emma smile and a handshake. "Have a good day!"

Rapid transit in the redoubt was almost entirely identical to rapid transit on Earth. The only difference was that on Earth, you could see outside. Here, everything was up-armored and windowless in case the squid exploded something nearby. They were also all identical single person pods, since the extra space to have multiple types of vehicle was better utilized by supply drones or reserve materiel storage.

Emma's TacComp pinged, informing her of new situation updates. She told it to bother her later. She had no desire to deal with it right now. It was guaranteed to be unpleasant reading, and after going through debriefing and psych eval, Emma really just wanted to have a nap. Maybe another cup of tea.

She was headed to Residence Block 4E. It had been built just like every other residence block in the redoubt. The entry way was narrow and low ceilinged, only wide enough for four transport pods to drop off their cargo or passengers. According to her TacComp, Emma's entire training cohort had been assigned there, along with a multiplicity of other girls from different units. Emma would be rooming next to Ayane, Varsha, Rebecca, and Renee. The idea, apparently, was that they'd give each other moral support as the fight continued.

The ride was short. Stepping out of her transit pod, Emma was greeted by two large, multi-paneled concrete blocks. Thick enough to withstand an AT Missile, the blocks were large enough to provide cover for several people in case of an attack. The surface of each block had been painted over with graffiti. It ranged from scribbled words of vague legibility to oil paintings, still slightly damp and crafted by a devotee to the art. Both stretched onto the floor and the walls, then reached up to span across the ceiling in a spray of color. Each step taken treaded across a flower or animal or hand or face, all rendered in myriad shapes and colors.

Emma paused to look at one of the paintings. It was a portrait of a magical girl, smiling melancholically at the viewer from the surface of the concrete. Her face was delicately boned, like you would expect of someone from Asiatic descent, but her eyes were a clear and vibrant hazel. Curling brown hair framed her face, and freckles dotted across her nose. The city of Helsinberg could be seen in the background, along with the rest of the valley. It had been rendered as it had been before the war, in full sun from the star overhead. An inscription had been written in the bottom corner:

Ashley Fong

Born: July 17, 2436

Deceased: April 15, 2452

Abruptly, Emma recalled who she was. Ashley had been one of the older contractees in her training cohort. She'd been slated for Magi Caeli training, actually, given her ability to fire streams of plasma out of her hands. Renee had been unspeakably jealous, resulting in not a few spats on the training field. Their instructor had finally banged their heads together and made them get along.

"Did you know her?" asked a passing girl.

"I… not really," said Emma. "She had it out with a friend of mine though."

"Hah, yeah?" said the girl. "Bellamy or whoever?"

"Bellanger," corrected Emma, smiling. She looked over to the other girl. "Renee Bellanger."

"Ah, right," said the girl, who had been identified by Emma's nomenclator as "Elise Mandel", with a shrug. "Ashley used to complain about her all the time. I never understood what the problem was."

"You were friends with Ashley?"

"Yeah," said Elise. She sighed and reached out, brushing her fingers over the face painted onto the cement. "Yeah, I was."

"I'm sorry."

"Thanks."

The two of them stared at Ashley's portrait for a while.

"Well anyway," said the girl. "I need to go. See you around Emma."

"See you, Elise."

Elise wiped her eyes once before she got into her transport pod. Emma sighed again and went up the steps past the concrete blocks. The paint continued, trailing off a few feet from the steps just before reaching a second set of blocks for defense in depth. Past this was a small open space, then the first of many large pillars.

As Emma walked, doors opened to admit or emit a magical girl. Some of them were going to combat duty, either on the surface or for demon patrol. Magical girls were usually kept in reserve, however, so most of the girls were either going to, or coming from, the chuen.

The chuen was the commercial space next to the redoubt's production centers. Most everyone went there in order to relax and hang out with friends. Emma hadn't been by yet, obviously, but her TacComp had helpfully pulled up a catalog as she traveled from her evaluation to Block 4E. There were a variety of bars, restaurants, and coffee or tea houses she could visit. Hell, there was even a library, swimming pool, and a scattering of rentable private rooms.

But for now, as was typical of her, Emma fancied a nap more than anything else. She made her way to the pillar her TacComp had highlighted. The door opened automatically as she approached. A streak of color swung past with a whoosh of rushing air. Emma had a moment to take a breath before the gravity elevator lifted her in and let her drop straight down.

It was an exhilarating ride, heightened by the ability to pinwheel as she wished. The elevator pushed her upright, just before depositing her gently onto the landing of her room cluster.

Each pillar opened onto a hexagonal landing, surrounded by six rooms. Each door was numbered and had the resident labeled holographically on the side. Emma looked around. The first door was Rebecca's, with Varsha's to her left and Renee to her right. Emma followed around to the left, circling past Ayane's room to her own, and then…

…the room belonging to Tracy Geyeller.

Emma stopped short, blinking at the text hovering beside the door next to hers. The text blurred, and Emma hurriedly rubbed at her eyes. The indicator ring just behind the text was red, the room's occupant absent. She must not be out of the hospital yet. A search confirmed this, and said that she'd be elevated from a comatose state in two days, following successful body restoration.

Emma immediately sent a request to attend Tracy's reawakening. There was a momentary delay, before a voice call request came through.

"Hello?" asked Emma, sniffling and wiping her eyes again. Damn.

"Hello, my name is Megan Chavez, I'm a psychiatrist with the MHD," said the girl on the other end. "I just wanted to ask you a few questions about your relationship with Tracy."

Emma narrowed her eyes, confused. "I was her commander during the attack where she lost her body."

"Why do you wish to be at her reawakening?"

"What do you mean?" asked Emma. "Of course I have to be there!"

"That… may not be advisable," said Megan delicately. "While your motivation makes sense at face value, the MHD is very cautious about reawakenings. We would like to ask you a few questions to do a deeper analysis before we approve your request."

Emma flinched. That was- seriously? What, did they think Emma was doing this purely as a formality? She shot the girl herself! She wasn't going to just leave Tracy adrift after doing something like that!

But if Emma had learned anything from working with Ingrid, it'd been how to hold her temper and work the problem, not just yell at it until it stopped being frustrating.

"I understand," Emma managed after a moment. "I… I still want to be there. What questions do you need to ask me to make sure I, uh-."

"Your post-mission evaluator was Jessica Valenti, right?" asked Megan. "I've sent her a notice, and she will make an appointment with you within the next few days."

"Alright," said Emma. She rubbed her nose frustratedly. "I just- I just want to be there, when she wakes up."

"If it doesn't work out," said Megan. "You're allowed to be in the waiting room, where we send her out. It's just the immediate moment after waking that we're cautious about."

"Yeah," said Emma, voice strained. "Yeah, I- thank you for telling me that."

"You're welcome. Have a good day."

"Yeah."

The call ended.

Emma sighed unhappily and let her head clunk against the wall over Tracy's name. Goddess above, that had been annoying. It took a moment, but Emma was able to shove her frustration into a corner of her mind for later disposal.

With a frustrated huff, Emma turned and went into her room. It's interior was plain and laid out in a hexagon the same size as the landing. The walls were the same shade of lime-cheesecake-green that she'd set when she'd just arrived. Emma's backpack and armor plates had been cleaned and stacked to the side.

The majority of the room was taken up by the bed, which started near the center and then extended back towards the far wall and terminated in a table/desk surface. Four drawers were underneath the mattress, allowing her to store whatever she ended up needing to store. The blankets were black, oddly enough, but then black did match any color other than dark navy.

Emma sighed and sat down on the bed, then fell backwards with a thump. She closed her eyes, trying to sleep. That's why she was here, wasn't it?

...nope, not happening. A glance at her chronometer told her that yes, it had, in fact, only been one minute. Emma knew herself well enough to know that this meant she was never going to get to sleep, especially now that she didn't even need to. She sent out a quick telepathic ping.

"Heyhey, didn't you say you were going to bed?" asked Rebecca. "Couldn't sleep?"

"Yeah," said Emma. "I… I had an annoying conversation with an MHD shrink just now. Too annoyed."

"Hehe, well, if you need to blow off some steam~"

"Rebecca," broke in Varsha, sounding extremely unamused. "You are not starting a harem."

"Bleh, you're just jealous."

"Anyway," said Ayane, clearly rolling her eyes from her room. Her tone turned more somber. "Don't you have some stuff to catch up on about your company? I uh… well, I know that the infantry had a bad time of it."

Emma paused. She didn't really want to do that right now, but... "I guess, yeah," she said eventually. "I should do that."

"Do you… want to work on this in a group?" asked Ayane. "The rooms aren't that big, but the news might not be good, so…"

"I'll come find you later, if I need to," said Emma. "Thanks for the offer."

"Yeah. I… good luck."

"Thanks."

Emma licked her lips apprehensively, then opened her update queue. It had been stashed to the side, but now scrolled translucently across the right hand side of her vision.

…Goddess, it'd been complete destruction. C Company was down to only twelve percent of its maximum readiness, with no replacements available to bolster its strength. In fact, the entire 12th Division had effectively disappeared in the fighting. The remainder had been squashed together with the remnants of an armored division to form the 2nd Armored Cavalry Division. It was a frankensteinian thing whose command structure was still being sorted out.

A message caught Emma's eye. "C Company Command Restructuring."

That was… ominous.

Emma opened the update and immediately gasped. Mei Ling had died, burning into oblivion after she managed to stop a squid SpecOps raid on the mobile command post. Fatima was on temporary leave to mourn. She'd been fighting with Mei Ling for nearly a decade by now, it would be more alarming if she hadn't taken the leave.

That left Alanis as the only commanding officer available to lead C Company, meaning that Emma and Emily were the only magical girls on standby. Tracy was apparently going to be assigned as further fire support within a week, but Emma and Emily might be asked to block an enemy attack or something in that interim.

Of the mundanes under the command, the ranks had been filled with militia replacements. Their equipment was outdated, their training adequate, but their experience minimal. It was a far cry from the disciplined and well equipped troops that Ingrid had been working with, a few… a few days ago.

Goddess, they were falling like… hell, flies had a longer lifespan than the soldiers on Samsara.

Emma swallowed back rising anxiety. It would be fine. Or, well, it would probably not, but it wasn't as if magic could raise the dead. Emma would probably not even get much time to interact with the soldiers that were technically under her command, since they'd probably be deployed on the surface while she stayed down here, so she shouldn't worry about it too much.

…Dammit, now she felt guilty. Because if she was on the surface, maybe she could help, but no that was stupid. It was a waste, a massive waste, of her powers to just throw them about willy nilly. And the infantry had an experienced officer to lead them up there anyway. It would be-

"Hey, guys?" asked Emma, quickly sitting upright on her bed. "You, uh, feel like a vid or something down at the theater?"

"Sure, I'll come," said Ayane immediately.

"It is pretty boring in here anyway," said Renee. "Have you seen that new vid about the Shizuki and the Kuroi?"

"Oh Goddess, is it one of those horrible sappy romances?" asked Emma, laughing. "Am I allowed to laugh if we see it?"

"Hey, I like those movies!" scolded Rebecca.

"Do you want to go over anything?" asked Varsha cautiously. "If you want, I can help."

"Nah, it's fine," said Emma, pushing cheer into her telepathy. "I uh, I'd rather not dwell too long on it, when I'm not on duty. Thanks though."

"Okay," said Varsha. "We'll meet you up top?"

"Sure," said Emma. She headed out of her room, Ayane and Renee leaving almost simultaneously. The three of them lingered before the elevator. "Uh, any particular reason you two will be slower?"

"Our hair's stuck," said Varsha with a sigh. "Knots, you know."

Emma glanced at Renee and Ayane, all three of them grinning. "You sure you don't need any help?"

"No, thank you," said Varsha flatly.

Stifled laughter. "Right. We'll see you up top."

5. Lunch and a Show

The vid they ended up seeing was called A Tale of Two Gardens. It was set on a colony out on the fringe of human space, just before the Cephalopods had attacked. A classically structured tale, the vid featured two star crossed lovers fighting through family prejudices and forces aligned against them to find love and happiness in each other's arms in a Shakesperially rooted fantasy. As advertised, it featured the generally quiet and soft-spoken Kuroi Isamu, falling deeply in love with the fiery and talented Shizuki Mikoto. Unlike the great bard's tale, though, A Tale of Two Gardens seemed destined for a happy ending.

Emma restrained a sigh as Rebecca sniffled two seats over. Ayane sat to her right, slowly munching through a bag of popcorn. Renee seemed to be so engrossed with the vid, she might actually be taking notes. Emma really hoped that wasn't the case, as she was fairly certain that this was not how romance worked in real life.

"You're going to do what?!" asked Sister Amelia of the Cult of Hope. "Are you mad?! The matriarchs will send people after you! You'll never be able to stop, never be able to rest. Running, for the rest of your lives. Is that what you want?"

"Yes," said Mikoto resolutely. She reached over and took Isamu's hand tenderly, looking once into his eyes before turning to face Sister Amelia again. "Yes it is. Will you help us?"

"Oh for the love of the Goddess," groaned Amelia, slumping into a chair and pressing her palms against her eyes. "Save me, My Lady, from young couples with little sense and too much time in bed."

Emma rolled her eyes but couldn't restrain a small smile as Mikoto thwapped Amelia upside the head and Isamu flushed bright red. She pulled her attention away from the vid, not difficult to do, honestly, and returned back to the composition she was writing.

It was a message to Abigail, the chaplain for the Cult of Hope for 12th Division. Emma hadn't really been sure about the Goddess, back when they'd first spoken before the drop. Now, with recent events fresh in her memory, Emma's opinion had changed. She planned to join the Cult. When, exactly, was still a bit up in the air, but Abigail was probably swamped and would have to get around to her later. Emma had a while to stew on it.

"Fine, look, I can get you on a freighter out to Mugadishou," said Amelia placatingly, dodging another of Mikoto's swats from some ribald joke Amelia had made. "You're on your own from there."

"We can work it out," said Isamu. "Thank you, Sister."

"Don't thank me yet," sighed Amelia. "Meet me at…"

Emma rested her head on her right hand, reading back over her message. The details had probably been seen by Abigail plenty of times, but Emma felt like it was one of those things that needed to be done properly. Still, she'd been writing for the last twenty minutes. Emma's final read through didn't catch anything particularly glaring. She went to send it, then paused.

Should she…?

Maybe until later, Emma decided. The others seemed engrossed in the vid, and Emma didn't want to disturb them. She sent the message without CCing the others. While she was in her mail app, Emma also sent a message to Agapita. She'd promised to contact her earlier, after all.

This message was substantially less complicated. "Calendar looks free, want to meet up somewhere?" Emma attached her rooming assignment to the bottom and hit send.

"Where do you think you're going?" asked Shizuki Sayaka, standing only five and a half feet tall in the same form as when she'd contracted. Her body sparked with magic as Mikoto gulped but stared the Matriarch down.

"I'm leaving," said Mikoto, voice wobbling in fear as Sayaka crossed her arms.

"Is that so?" asked Sayaka. "And you'll be meeting that boy—," Sayaka spat the word like it was made of toxic sludge "—off somewhere? To 'make love', I presume?"

Emma doubted that Shizuki Sayaka actually spoke like that. Nor did she really think that something like this actually warranted the Matriarch's intervention. But the studio had decided to play up the drama, and apparently Sayaka-sama had seen the vid and approved.

Emma's interface blinked at her quietly. It was a response from Agapita. "Yo! I'm free for lunch, want to meet up?"

That was fast. Emma quickly responded: "Sure, will let friends know I have other plans."

"You can bring them if you want."

"A news dump about London Town? I doubt they'd be entertained."

"Hmmm, true. See you later then. :3"

Emma sighed and turned back to the vid.

"You're going to go no matter what I say, aren't you?" asked Sayaka, her "stare of the ages" not actually working, given that the actor, doused in CGI, was not several hundred years old.

"You'll have to kill me," said Mikoto. She gulped, but transformed with a ripple of color.

"You dare?"

"I do."

"…very well, you are free to go," said Sayaka. She sighed, and stepped to the side. "If there's one thing I've learned from these many years alive, it's that nothing can stand in the way of true love. Not even magic."

Emma stifled a gag. Goddess above, that was the cheesiest line yet. Shizuki Sayaka definitely did not talk like that.

"Here, it helps distract you," Ayane whispered telepathically. She held the bag of popcorn in front of Emma.

"Thanks," Emma replied. She reached in for a few kernels and crunched through them. "Oh hey, parmesan and garlic."

"Sorry, forgot to warn you."

"No, it's fine, I like parmesan and garlic," said Emma. She reached in for another handful. "Never liked super sweet things."

"Me neither," said Ayane. "Thoughts on the vid?"

"Way to cheesy," said Emma immediately. "How do people watch these things?"

"Healthy disregard for reality, I guess," said Ayane. She crunched into a mouthful of popcorn. "That line from Sayaka just now was awful."

"Ugh, yes," said Emma. "How did that magical girl noir thing go, earlier?"

"It was fine," said Ayane. "I slept through part of it, actually."

Emma swallowed a mouthful of popcorn half-chewed. That— what. "…Oh, okay," she said as casually as possible. "What'd you miss?"

"Not sure," said Ayane. She reached over to get more popcorn. "I was really confused when Chiaki— the main character — ended up shooting this one guy from the beginning of the vid."

"Did you ever figure it out?"

"Oh, well, as it turns out, he was the baddie's agent all along. Bit of a shock actually, he was quite the gentleman up till then."

"Huh," said Emma. Her imagination flitted, suddenly, to an image of her and Ayane cuddled together, Ayane raising an eyebrow at the vid as Emma snored into Ayane's shoulder. She remembered Ayane's warmth, the odd softness of her body, and—

—Emma whacked herself on the head.

"What are you doing?" asked Ayane.

"Nothing," said Emma. She shivered and ate a few more kernels of popcorn, then turned her attention back to the vid.

The two lovers were quietly making their way through the star port, going through back channels to avoid the security scanners. Sister Amelia licked her lips, then ushered the two of them through a door into the space elevator station.

"Blend in with the crowd and don't look out of place," said Amelia quietly. "You're on your own from here. If anyone asks, just say that you're on magical girl business. The hacks I installed will scramble the facial recognition software."

"Thanks," said Mikoto. She and Isamu gave Amelia a hug. "Thank you for everything."

"I'm pretty sure that hack doesn't exist," said Ayane.

"It might," said Emma with a shrug. "I mean, computing is just an infinite series of black boxes, you know?"

"Pfft," snorted Ayane. "You have no idea. Migration modeling software is such a pain to use."

"Yeah? What's it like?" asked Emma.

"Well it's generally pretty powerful," said Ayane, pulling up the application, called FlockPlot 2.2, to show Emma what it was like. "But someone decided to write a GUI."

Emma winced. Graphical user interfaces were often necessary for general user applications. For more technical work, even, a GUI often was extremely useful for understanding what your data was doing.

The difference between that and FlockPlot was that the latter's GUI was hard-coded, rather than designed and created by a graphical design specialist. Phoebusoft, for example, produced a geographical plotting application with an almost perfectly intuitive GUI. FlockPlot was… significantly less so.

"Yeah that's… pretty bad," said Emma. She nudged Ayane consolingly. "Can you even access the mental interface?"

"No, whoever wrote this didn't really use it," said Ayane, rolling her eyes. "I mean, the code is kind of fiddly, but it's really not that bad. All I have is a plug-in that lets me drop in some data, but if I change one parameter—," FlockPlot pinged and transitioned into a map of Japan, multiple data points scattered across it. Ayane's input immediately wiped them all out. "—Well look, see? I have to completely re-plot it. It's completely ridiculous, and I have to do at least fifty of these plots for each species!"

"Are there a lot of species in Osaka?"

"Emma, we get three hundred different types of bird, every year," said Ayane. "Half of those are migratory."

"Oh. That, that uh, that sounds fun."

"Well it is, sort of," said Ayane. "You get to see a lot of different birds, obviously, so if you like birds, it's a really great thing to see, especially if you get a breather. But when you're working…"

"It's a massive clusterfuck?"

Ayane sighed. "Yeah, basically. It's the middle of migration season, actually, so I got to test out my new powers a bit with the local fauna."

"How's that then?" asked Emma. "I thought your main power was flight?"

"It is, but uh, well," said Ayane, suddenly turning red and looking away. "I uh… I wished that I could just talk to the birds and figure out what was going on, so…"

Emma wasn't entirely sure how to respond to this.

"Uh, well, it's a good wish for your field."

"It was a stupid wish and I should have come up with a better one," said Ayane, frowning.

"Don't say that—."

"It's true though."

"Well, look, we can talk about it later, but this—," Emma mentally nodded at the vid and its finale moment. Rebecca was quietly hiccuping into Varsha's shoulder. Emma glanced over to see Varsha roll her eyes but pat Rebecca gently on the head. "This is probably not the best place."

"Yeah, sorry," said Ayane, sighing slightly and closing her program. "I'm not— well, my psychiatrist says I shouldn't be so down about my wish. She says all wishes are important."

Emma tread forward carefully. "I don't really know much about that sort of thing, but it sounds right to me."

Ayane looked over at her and smiled melancholically. "Thanks. I don't really believe it, but thanks."

"I— you're welcome," said Emma. She looked around. Varsha was still waiting for Rebecca to stop crying, probably telepathically cooing at the girl to cheer her up. Renee though…

Renee was giving her and Ayane an interested look.

"What's up?" asked Emma.

"Nothing," said Renee casually. She crossed a leg. "You have any plans for the rest of the day?"

"Mm, I don't," said Ayane. "Did you have an idea for something?"

"Really?" asked Renee, arching an eyebrow. "The way you two were engrossed in each other, I would have expected a date or something."

"Oh, no, nothing like tha— wait, what?" asked Ayane, flushing immediately. "R-Renee! What are you saying?"

"You make a good, if somewhat unexpected, couple," said Renee with maddening offhandedness. She got up and made her way to the door. "Do try and kiss once, before Emma goes back on the duty roster."

Emma and Ayane sat in stunned silence.

"Wait, hold on, Renee!" Ayane called, getting up and running after. "Renee, we are not dating!"

"You're not?" asked Varsha as she helped Rebecca up. "Wait, really?"

"No," said Emma, still in disbelief. "Where did you get that impression?"

"Are you kidding?" asked Varsha. "You were cuddling."

"Ayane had just been in the hospital!" protested Emma. "Everyone reacts to shitty situations differently. When it's like that, there's nothing romantic about— about cuddling."

"I guess," said Varsha thoughtfully. She rubbed Rebecca's head soothingly. "I mean, it's true that me and Rebecca aren't going to be making out in the next five seconds."

"S-says you," broke in Rebecca with a giggle.

"Stop it," said Varsha, tapping Rebecca on the head and leading the way out of the viewing booth.

"But seriously, me and Ayane are not getting together," said Emma.

"Yeah, whatever," said Varsha.

"I'm not even gay, it's not a thing."

"Uh huh," said Rebecca.

"I'm not going to, I dunno, throw her into bed and do things to her."

Varsha and Rebecca looked at each other.

"…Neither of us said anything about going to bed," said Rebecca. "Where'd you come up with that?"

"I'm just saying!" said Emma, waving her arms in distress. "I don't want a bunch of rumors about us!"

"You're really not helping your cause," said Varsha.

"Yeah? How would you know?"

"Because I'm dating the girl I was shipped with," said Varsha blithely, before turning and walking off with Rebecca.

Emma watched them go, jaw swinging loose in shock.

The view from the top of the chuen was surprisingly stunning. It wasn't what Emma would call a "large structure", especially compared to the endless depths you could fall if you jumped from the right building in Mitakihara. But it was quite large, nonetheless, and quite architecturally diverse. There was a large mix between architectural traditions across the ages, with Ancient Roman scattered amongst Ancient Chinese, and Ancient Chinese scattered amongst Ancient Roman. Colorful Russian Tzarist bulbs mingled with the sheer granite of Modernism, and, most interestingly of all, everything blended and merged into a multicolored riot that was often somewhat horrifying, but just as commonly stunningly beautiful.

It was easy to lose yourself in the sweeping lines and clean corners of the various buildings. It was certainly easier, lying there on your stomach on a roof near the cavern ceiling, than thinking about… things.

With a groan, Emma rolled over and stared up at the stone above her. Deep in the bedrock, there was a slight amount of groundwater leakage that was never really preventable. Water trickled downwards towards the sides, where gutters collected the water and ran it into the chuen's dedicated reservoir. No sense wasting the water, after all.

Dammit. What a mess. Actually, it wasn't even a mess yet, and Emma was already freaking out about it. Honestly, she was probably massively over thinking the issue. Renee had probably just been trolling, like she usually did.

Varsha and Rebecca made her pause though. Varsha was right, she and Rebecca had been the single most talked about couple, or potential couple, in training, and now they were together. What if Emma and Ayane were doing something similar? This was a terrible time and place to be starting any sort of relationship. Longstanding inevitabilities, like Rebecca and Varsha, were one thing, but this? This was horribly stupid. It was distracting, it could lead to unintentional gem burnout, and…

…And…

…Well the cold truth of the matter was that Ayane could be dead in two days. So could Emma. Combat duty was combat duty. You were going onto the surface, where there were millions of ways to die ranging from a sniper shot to slipping off a building. There was no guarantee that the girl you'd just got in bed with would return. Hell, it was dangerous for Rebecca and Varsha to be together, and it was a wonder that the MHD hadn't finagled something to get them separated. If Varsha died, Rebecca would know immediately. She might end up dying right then and there. It was a terrible, terrible risk, falling for a magical girl when you, yourself, were one as well.

Emma wasn't sure she could handle that. She knew she couldn't stand the idea of any of her friends dying, and didn't think about it much because of that. She knew that she felt a lot of responsibility, and that there were people counting on her to lead them well. She was responsible for enough deaths, in the past or in the future.

Emma didn't want Ayane's death on her hands as well.

Emma's TacComp pinged. It was time for her appointment with Agapita.

Hanegawa's Ramen Bar was a small storefront on the east side of the chuen. Tucked in a corner and relatively inconspicuous, it was run by Harold Hanegawa. True to its name, it was both a restaurant and a bar, serving both alcohol in abundance and hand made, custom to order, positively massive bowls of ramen.

"So, you been here before?" asked Emma telepathically. She sat on a high barstool before the main counter. The clank of ladles on stockpots and rapid thwacking of knives on cutting boards drowned out all attempts at verbal communication.

"Not really," said Agapita, pursing her lips as she scrolled through the implant-projected menu. Fragrant steam, heavy with the smell of slow-simmered meat and vegetables, wafted over the counter. "Mmm… smells good though."

"What do you think about the barbecue pork?" asked Emma. She glanced through the ingredients list. "Looks like it's Japanese barbecue they use, so can't be bad?"

"No, I don't think so, maybe try—?"

"Hello ladies!" shouted a cook. He swung a towel onto his shoulder and smiled dazzlingly at them. "Welcome to Hanegawa's! This your first time here?"

"Yes!" Emma shouted back.

"Great, welcome welcome!" replied the cook. "A bit of an intro then, here's how it works. Ramen at Hanegawa's comes either in prepped-bowls or A-la-Carte. Prepped-bowls are prepped-bowls, they're what they say on the label. You can add stuff from the A-la-Carte list if you like. Straight A-la-Carte starts with a choice of three different broths, then your meat, then your veggies. We cook the meat and veggies to order and combine everything together for your meal."

"What's a good prepped bowl then?" asked Agapita.

"Well, since you're both magical girls, I'd recommend our Mage's Special," suggested the cook. He gestured over the counter and popped up a graphics. "It's fairly simple, but a big hit with all the mages we get. We start by marinating steak in rice vinegar, Asian pear extract, and brown sugar, then sear it and slice it into strips. The broth we use is the Three Bone House, and the bowl comes with blanched carrot matchsticks and Asiatic broccoli. The garnish is finely sliced red onions and a scoop of butter. Sound good?"

Agapita and Emma glanced at each other.

"Brilliant," said Agapita. "We'll take one each."

"Fantastic, house beer sound good for drinks? I'd recommend it for this bowl."

"Yeah, house beer sounds good," said Agapita. "You okay with house beer, Emma?"

Emma shrugged. "I don't have much experience with this sort of thing, so whatever is fine for me."

"Excellent, here are your beers," said the cook. He placed two bottles in front of them with a clunk, the glass misting immediately in the humid atmosphere. "Enjoy your beers, ladies, your food will be up shortly." He turned and bellowed down the line: "TWO MAGE'S SPECIALS FOR THE COUNTER."

"Goddess, this is a bar?" asked Emma as a returning bellow echoed up the line. She twisted the cap off the top of her beer with an incredulous shake of her head. "That was better service than I've had anywhere on Earth. Sounds like better food too."

"Well you know, Hanegawa-sensei's got two Starline Stripes," said Agapita.

"Starline Stripes? What are those?"

"Oh, they're ratings given out by the Starline Association," said Agapita. "For people who go on holiday, to give them an idea where to eat and where to stay. Harold Hanegawa's gotten two stripes out of three for his restaurant in Downtown Helsinberg."

"Huh. I've never heard of the Starline Association."

"Really? They've got an office in London," said Agapita. "Although I guess it's part of that update I said I'd be giving you."

"Yeah? What else is new then?"

"Well, when were you in London last?"

The conversation was fairly long. Emma listened closely as Agapita described all the changes that had happened in the last two years, accompanied by an animation that updated itself based on what Agapita was talking about. It was startling how much had changed. The old Shizuki Business Complex had been remodeled. It was now an official MSY Finance center, with many of the businesses slowly being integrated into the MSY where applicable. Hashimoto and Sinclair Investments and Securities was apparently doing very well under the guidance of Emma's parents and Ami Hashimoto. The latter was even getting married, or so the rumors said.

"Ami's not that much older than me, is she?" asked Emma as she chewed through a strip of almost-totally-raw steak. It was absolutely fantastic.

"No, well, she's twenty," said Agapita. "So six years older than you, I think."

"But still, that's a bit young, isn't it?"

"Nah, matriarchies do it all the time," said Agapita. She waved her chopsticks dismissively. "It's not like you're expected to pump out babies as soon as you get married. This isn't the 1100s."

"I… guess. You think it was political then?"

"Oh, probably," said Agapita with a nod. "She's married to, hm, Shizuki Ryouichi. He's from around here, actually. There's a Shizuki family that's in charge of the local branch office for HSIS. His mum's name is Shizuki Hinata, dad's called Shizuki Akio, he married in though, and he's got a little brother named Shizuki Ryouta."

"How alliterative," remarked Emma.

"Quite."

"How do you know them?"

"Well, the Burnside-Sinclair family has a long relationship with the Shizuki Matriarchy," said Agapita. She pulled up a diagram in a shareview. "You see, our ancestor, Maria, was sort of adopted by the Shizukis way back before the Unification Wars. The Burnside-Sinclairs ended up building their own matriarchy for awhile, until, uh, ideological differences kind of made us implode." Agapita sighed. "We lost a lot of people. Good people. The family scattered. Some joined up with the FA, but a lot of us apparently ended up just keeping their heads down, staying away from magic and the like. The Shizukis stuck with us throughout, and we owe Sayaka-sama a lot. When I deployed here, Laure, our current matriarch, forwarded a contact list, in case I needed any help. Not that I needed it, since, you know, MagOps, but it was nice of her anyway. She tries to keep tabs on us, to keep us from getting lost like the others."

"That sounds very sad," said Emma. She pushed a piece of meat around on her bowl. "I uh… I'm sorry for your family."

"Ah, whatever," said Agapita, cheering up a bit. "Let's not worry about it. It's not like I was there, I'm only fifty-three."

Emma choked on a noodle. "Goddess, I keep forgetting," she muttered, coughing out the stray pasta. "You're old."

"Hey, you're only as old as you want to be!" said Agapita with a grin. "Us magical girls, we can be fifteen the rest of our lives!"

"Yeah yeah," said Emma, rolling her eyes.

"But actually, on that note," said Agapita. She tapped her chopsticks apprehensively against her bowl. "I did want to ask. Your last name's interesting, do you think I could get a DNA test done?"

"What do you mean?" asked Emma, slurping up more noodles. "You're not seriously suggesting I'm part of one of those lost families from the Unification Wars?"

"I mean, you could be," said Agapita seriously. "Having a family to count on is a big deal."

"What for?"

"Matriarchal politics, for one thing, so we want all the family we can get. But I also have way too few cousins who are also magical girls, and I'd really like another."

"…That's… a little creepy," said Emma, leaning away from the other girl.

"Oh pleeeeeeeeeeease?"

Emma rolled her eyes. "Ugh, fine, just don't get your hopes up. Sinclair's not exactly a rare last name. What do you need me to do?"

"Sure, sure, just hold on a sec," said Agapita with a grin. She hurriedly searched her pockets, before flipping out a hypo. "Gimme your arm."

Cautiously, Emma held out her arm. Agapita grabbed hold of Emma's wrist and pushed her sleeve up.

"This won't hurt a bit."

A stab.

"Ow!" yelped Emma, snatching her arm back. "You said that wouldn't hurt!"

"I lied," said Agapita blithely, tucking the hypo back into her pocket with a giggle. "That'll get processed eventually. Back to London then."

Emma gave Agapita a wary look as the other chattered on, before turning back to her ramen. The MagOps operative was clearly insane.

Hopefully, Emma wouldn't end up like that.

6. Reading With Friends

Lunch finished with little fanfare. Agapita had a team meeting to get to, so she left soon after they paid their tab.

"I'll call you up when the results come back," said Agapita. "I mean, it's really not that difficult a thing to do, but the hypo does some other stuff as well."

"I knew you jabbed me with it for kicks," groused Emma. It hadn't hurt her, but really. "Ass."

"Bah, you'll be fine," said Agapita. She whacked Emma on the back as she left, making Emma stumble and cough. "You're tougher than most greenies. See you around Emma."

Emma shook her head as Agapita disappeared into the crowd. The older girl was totally insane. She then turned her attention to her inbox, which had gotten several notes over the course of the conversation.

One was from Abigail, the chaplain. She was extremely excited to hear about Emma's conversion and wanted to meet as soon as possible to discuss it in more detail. The note was a little vague on the details, as Abigail had several meetings to get to and didn't have all that much time left to write. All in all, the note made Emma smile and feel better about her decision. An appointment came attached to Abigail's note, asking Emma to go down to the chapel at 1630.

The second was from Jessica, telling her to come by tomorrow morning for her interview. Emma frowned at this in distaste, but sighed and moved on.

The last note was from Ayane and Renee, about how they were at the library and she should come visit. It was just turning 1300 now, which gave Emma about three hours until she had to be at the chapel. She sent a reply to Ayane and Renee, telling them she'd be there shortly. Libraries were a historical curiosity, the last Emma had heard, so—

"Emma Sinclair! Hello!"

Emma winced as her train of thought was forcibly snapped in half by Senbey's piercing telepathy. A second later, something white and fluffy smacked her in the face.

"Oi!"

"Sorry, sorry," said Senbey hurriedly, grasping onto the front of Emma's hoodie and scurrying onto her shoulder. "Miscalculated again. How are you?"

"Well I was doing alright," began Emma. "But—."

"That's great! I've been following you since the suburbs—!"

"—then you hit me in the face and what do you mean 'following'?"

"Oh, you remember that I told you the Incubators wanted to observe your person, yes?" asked Senbey, tilting its head. "The data I gathered was incredibly interesting! I was not aware that humans could cuddle when they were not engaging in sexual interco—!"

"Oi, shut up!" said Emma, snatching at Senbey and flushing utterly red. The Incubator vanished with a puff of smoke. Various odd looks were sent Emma's direction as she twisted on the spot, both at her rather random motion and at the appearance of an Incubator on her shoulder.

"What? It's just an observation," said Senbey. It reappeared a few inches above the ground, and managed to land in a semi-coherent manner this time. "While it is true that there are several gaps in my knowledge, since I have spent most of my career working on entropic reactions, it really is a fascinating practice. Did you know that in Qing Dynasty China, same-sex consorts of the royal children were commonplace? It's true! The—."

Emma finally managed to grab Senbey and shook the Incubator to get it to stop.

"Right, listen here," she said, forcing herself to ignore the odd looks around her. "You are going to shut up, right now, about anything regarding sex. Do you understand me?"

"Oh fine, but it's really a very interesting topic," said Senbey cheerily. "What other things would you be amenable to discussing?"

Emma gave Senbey a narrow-eyed look for a moment, before letting it drop to the ground. She started walking towards the library silently, with Senbey trailing behind. A question soon came to mind. "Actually, you never really explained, why are the Incubators interested in me?" she asked, "I'm not exactly special."

"No, you're not," acknowledged Senbey. "In most respects, you are quite average."

"Most?"

"Your social skills are slightly below average," said Senbey. "Specifically, you have a tendency to be extremely irritating to authority figures."

Emma paused to give Senbey a very flat look. "Thanks. Great for my self esteem, that."

"You are very welcome!" said Senbey, it's voice breaking into a squeak at the end. "Self esteem has been statistically shown to have negative effects on group cooperation, did you know? Overly proud humans have a tendency to—."

"Ahem. Back on topic?"

"Oh, right," said Senbey. "In any case, your general averageness does not imply any strong indicators for delaying death, and statistical analysis indicates that you most likely would have died in the scenario prior to your rescue. As I said earlier, this implies a certain unusual gem resilience to grief, which has many potential implications for magical girl design and soul gem engineering. The data you provide could help millions of magical girls in the future be less susceptible to gem corruption!"

Emma stopped in the hallway and looked down at Senbey. "Did you just say 'magical girl design'?"

"Yes!"

"What exactly do you mean?"

"Didn't you know?" asked Senbey, cocking its head. "Human physiology is not capable of channeling magic or performing the feats that magical girls are capable of. Part of the process requires us to reimplement your physical body and replace it with one that is compatible with magic! Of course, the same is true with your soul, which we condense into crystalline form. It's all very complex, but I thought everyone knew, even if your government keeps it secret for some reason."

Emma began to feel slightly ill. "You're saying that the original me doesn't exist?"

"Of course not!" said Senbey, cocking its head the other way. "There was no 'original you' in the first place! Physical forms are transitory and change constantly! The only thing that's originally 'you' is your soul, and you have that in your gem already."

Emma screwed up her face as she tried to understand what the Incubator was trying to say. "So… so you're… you're basically saying that Incubators view the physical as a sort of passing thing that doesn't really matter?"

"That's not entirely true either," said Senbey patiently. "The physical universe is something that all matter based consciousnesses must interact with. The form chosen by the First Surveyors was specifically based off of observed human psychology, for example. We do not ignore the physical universe, but rather seek to transcend it. Is this not also what humans do?"

"What do you mean?"

"Historically, humanity has often turned to recreational chemical agents to seek an altered state of consciousness," said Senbey. "And when that became dangerous and-or unnecessary, humanity started augmenting itself. You have no serious issue consisting, on average, of about 15% artificial constructs. Consider, however, that your ancestors in the 18th Century would have considered you an abomination to be exterminated within the fiery inferno of a primitive blast furnace! Human soldiers transcend the physical limits of the human design regularly. Incubators do the same thing with magical girls. We simply are better at it."

Emma considered this.

"I… guess…?" she said eventually. "In… in general, you're saying that you, uh, you basically just super-implanted me?"

"Well, I didn't personally, but yes, that is a sufficient, very low level summary of what occurred when you contracted," said Senbey with a cheerful nod. "The reality involves complex metaphysics and requires a deeper understanding of the warped non-continuous antispace."

Emma squinted at Senbey, unsure if she was supposed to be complimented or insulted by Senbey's evaluation of her conclusions.

"Well whatever," said Emma. "I'm going to meet up with some friends."

"May I come with?" asked Senbey. It leaped up and perched upon her shoulder again.

"You have to promise to stop being so squeaky," said Emma. "And not to comment on things awkwardly."

"Does this sound better?" asked Senbey. Emma flinched. Senbey's voice suddenly resonated in a deep, round bass that echoed in her mind.

"Uh, no," said Emma. "Just, stop being so hyper."

"Oh, I think I understand," said Senbey. It made an effort to speak more slowly and at a slightly lower pitch. "Like this?"

With a cautious nod, Emma set off for the library.

The library had a very unassuming, but very unusual door. Somehow, it was easily looked over, the geometric shapes on its face making it fade into the wall. Yet, it was clearly manufactured to imitate an oak-paneled door, impossible to miss normally given the sheer lack of wood in the redoubt. Emma walked right past it while looking for the room, before doubling back.

"How did I miss that?" Emma wondered, tapping the door experimentally. It creaked open slightly, a ripple of light seeping past the crack.

"Are all human rooms this theatrical?" asked Senbey.

"No, this one is just weird," said Emma. She pushed the door fully open and stepped through into a bright, spherical room, with a Persian rug laid out in front of a desk. A single round window was behind it, illuminating, with simulated sunlight, the wood-paneled room and a set of wrought iron spiraling stairs off to the left A thin, bespectacled female figure sat behind the desk, writing something down with what looked like an ornate stylus. She looked up as Emma walked in.

"Good afternoon," said the figure. "Welcome to the Helsinberg Redoubt Public Library. I am the Librarian VI for this installation. How can I help you today?"

"Uh, I'm looking for Ayane Nakamura and Renee Bellanger?" asked Emma, somewhat taken aback by the intricate attention to detail in the atrium.

"Oh yes, the two magical girls," said the Librarian. "You'll want to climb to the next floor."

"Thanks," said Emma, nodding, before making her way up the stairs. Her steps clanked as she went up. The door was oak-paneled, just like the door to the atrium. Emma knocked twice.

"Come in!" called Ayane.

Emma peered in through the door, Senbey peeking in with her.

"Whoa," said Emma. She looked up, and then kept looking. Bookshelves reached all the way to infinity, while a set of four cushy, overstuffed arm chairs sat about a coffee table. A wide, round window looked out over the chuen, although Emma suspected it was a simulated projection.

"Cool, isn't it?" asked Ayane. She was lying across one of the arm chairs, curled up at an improbable angle. She gestured at the ceiling. "It's an optical illusion, of course, but the spherical room makes it difficult to remember that. It makes my arms itch."

"I still do not see why you are so enthused by this," said Renee blandly. She was seated in a much more ordinary fashion, legs crossed on top of the coffee table.

"It looks cool," said Emma. She kept looking as she stepped further into the room. "You wouldn't get it, being in concert halls all the time."

"Yeah, big rooms that keep going up aren't a thing in Japan," said Ayane. "At least, not for people like us."

"Then clearly you are insufficiently cultured," said Renee, shaking her head with a sigh. "I must take you two to the opera one day. It will be an experience."

"We could VR it," said Emma, still looking up.

"Bah, it is a pale imitation," said Renee. "You would not understand, you do not dance."

"Well if it helps, I have been in Stadium One in London," said Emma, looking down finally. "It's a pretty huge place. Being inside is an experience, that's for sure."

"Yes exactly," said Renee, snapping her fingers. "There is something intangible that the sim cannot capture."

"Improbable romanticism aside," said Ayane, rolling her eyes at the two of them. "Stay awhile, Emma. Read with us, it's kind of fun."

"What, does the place have actual books?" asked Emma.

"No, it's some sort of live VR sim," said Ayane. "All you have to do is ask for a particular book, and the library will simulate it in your hands."

"Okay, so…" said Emma. She held out her hands and thought for a moment. "Uhh… how about A Study in Scarlet?"

The tome materialized in a flicker of light and words, dropping heavily into Emma's hands.

"Holy crap," said Emma. She ran her hand over the cover. It certainly felt real enough. "That's really cool. What happens if I squeeze it too hard?"

"Nothing interesting, unfortunately for you," said Renee. "It just vanishes."

"Really? That's too bad."

"I do not see anything," interjected Senbey. The group jumped. They had forgotten the Incubator was there.

"Ah, sorry, I should introduce you guys," said Emma. "Senbey, this is Ayane and Renee. Guys, this is Senbey, the Incubator who has decided I am the science experiment of the month."

"Hello!" chirped Senbey.

"Hello!" greeted Ayane. "How are you?"

"I'm fine, thank you for asking!" said Senbey enthusiastically. It immediately jumped off of Emma to land on Ayane's chest, purring and rubbing itself against her chin. Ayane yelped and giggled as she scratched Senbey behind the ears.

"So what is this about Emma being a science experiment?" asked Renee.

"It says that I'm apparently weirdly resilient to gem corruption," said Emma, folding her arms as she watched Senbey and Ayane play. "I'm under observation to see what happens, I guess. Not, apparently, that Senbey's taking it all very seriously."

"On the contrary, studies show that bonding through cuddling is extremely effective at facilitating good data collection!" said Senbey, popping immediately into sitting position. "Of course, there are other benefits too, such as temporary increased resistance to gem corruption. An excellent example, again, is the time you and Ayane—!"

Senbey broke off, cocking its head to one side as Renee began to giggle.

"Is something the matter?" it asked.

"E-Emma and Ayane," managed Renee. "Goddess, I knew I wasn't the only one."

"S-shut up!" said Ayane. She rapidly turned red as Renee's meaning became clear. "I told you already, it's not like that!"

"Maybe we should leave you alone for awhile to find out," said Renee, still fighting through giggles. "Do you think it would be a good experiment, Senbey?"

"Undoubtedly!" said Senbey enthusiastically. "I can set up the measuring equipment—!"

Ayane threw Senbey across the room at Renee's head, who caught the flailing Incubator and laughed at Emma and Ayane's distress.

"I am sorry, you two," said Renee eventually, with a mirthful sigh. "It is simply too easy."

Ayane sank deeper into her armchair and hid behind her book about eagles. "Meanie…"

"Anyway," said Emma primly. "Have you two been up here ever since the vid?"

"Yeah, it's been fun," said Ayane, sitting up again to look at Emma properly as she spoke. "Well, it has for me. I haven't been paying attention to Renee."

"I have been doing ballet sims," said Renee. "I found an interesting book and wanted to try some of the routines it outlined. They are very complex, but I am making progress."

"That's good," said Emma. "Maybe you can show us some time?"

"Perhaps, but I am not certain," said Renee with a shrug. "They are very complex, as I said."

Emma nodded. "What about you, Ayane? What are you reading?"

"I've found this interesting book about eagles," said Ayane, holding up the very large tome. "It's the collected works of this guy Shen Bergmann, and I've found this fascinating section about the feeding habits of this one population in Spain. Do you want to see? It's really very interesting."

Emma was dubious. "Ehh, maybe later."

"Well go on, have a seat," said Ayane. "Do you like Sherlock Holmes?"

"It's not bad," said Emma as she sat down in one of the armchairs. Wow. That was very comfy. "It was the first thing I thought of. I guess, for a long spaceflight, it'd be a good choice to bring with."

"Is A Study in Scarlet your favorite?" asked Ayane. Renee went back to her sims, realizing that the conversation was going to continue to be uninteresting.

Emma nodded. "Though, to be fair, it's been awhile since I last read it, but I remember enjoying it more than the others at least."

"That's cool. I preferred The Adventure of the Speckled Band," said Ayane. "It's my favorite, especially about how the guy has a cheetah."

"I suppose," said Emma. "I don't remember it very well though."

The two of them turned to the books they held. It really had been awhile since Emma'd read any Sherlock Holmes. It was engaging at first, but she quickly remembered why she didn't find it that compelling. She could never get used to the Victorian syntax, and it made for rather dull reading in her opinion. Her thoughts soon drifted.

She wound up thinking about the appointment she had with Abigail in a few hours. Well, two and a bit, by now. It was a big step. She'd felt completely sure about it in the field. Hell, she had been completely sure about it when she'd sent Abigail that message. But actually having the appointment on her calendar had triggered a strange nervousness.

Or more accurately, she was suddenly starting to have second thoughts about this. It wasn't that she suddenly had doubts about her beliefs. That bit right after getting out of the IFV was potentially born out of being extraordinarily high on neurotransmitters, but the dream, or vision, or whatever the hell it was, formed quite a good counterpoint.

No the problem was, Emma was just now realizing that she'd never gotten around to telling anyone about her decision. There was a big difference between briefly considering CCing people in a message and realizing that, wow, this was a very important moment but most people were actually quite secular. There was no guarantee in any way that anyone would understand or accept Emma's decision.

But, that had to be irrational on her part. A pretty basic part of primary and middle school ethics class had been discussing accepting other people for who they were. Granted, it had most recently been framed in the context of gender and sexuality, but really, the principals still applied here, right? It wasn't like there was an entire unit about ideological conflicts back in civics that generally implied that religion was not a great thing, really. And there were lots of magical girls in the Cult, so… so….

Emma suddenly felt very, very small and alone. She hadn't ever considered this. What was going to happen? Should she keep it a secret and never tell anyone, ever? Should she try and downplay it? Maybe… maybe she should cancel her appointment with Abigail…

"Emma?" asked Ayane. "You okay over there?"

"Ah-wha?" asked Emma, blinking. "Yeah, what's up?"

"You've kinda been staring at that page for the last few minutes," said Ayane, eyebrow raised.

Emma licked her lips nervously. "Oh, uh, right. I was just… thinking."

"About what?"

"Um… stuff?"

Ayane raised her eyebrow higher. "How vague."

"Honestly though, it wasn't anything that interesting," said Emma hurriedly. "Just… just stuff."

"Well, now I'm curious," said Ayane, setting her book aside. She shifted to lean against the arm of her chair. "Come on, tell me! I promise I won't laugh if it's embarrassing."

Emma shifted nervously. "Well, I mean, it uh, it was uh…."

Ayane tilted her head curiously, then blinked and slowly began blushing. "You… you weren't thinking about… about us?"

"No, nothing like that," said Emma hurriedly and waving her hands. "No, it was… it was something else. Something more, uh, well, not more important, but…"

Awkward silence descended. Emma shuffled her feet nervously, refusing to meet Ayane's eyes. She glanced left, at the book case behind Ayane, and fiddled with the hem of her hoodie. Ayane waved a hand in the space with a pout, making Emma quickly look the other direction. Now Ayane just stared at her, growing steadily more peeved. Seriously?

The silence wasn't broken until Renee came out of her sim and replayed the recent conversation.

"Ugh, what could possibly be so difficult to talk about?" asked Renee. "Just spit it out already. We are all friends here. Unless you are about to confess your undying love in which case-."

Ayane threw her book at Renee. The simulated object passed through Senbey, who vanished with a small squeak, and de-rezzed just before hitting Renee in the face.

"Annoying as Renee is," said Ayane, scowling. "She's right. We're all friends here."

"I… I'm…," Emma closed her eyes and took a deep breath. "I've decided to join the Cult of Hope."

A moment of utter silence.

"Why?" asked Renee, arching an eyebrow. "It is an unusual thing to do."

"I… I had a… a vision, I think," said Emma.

"You think," said Renee. "I… see."

"You don't believe me?"

"It is not as if visions are commonplace," said Renee. "Usually, it is a result of implant malfunction. You probably hit your head very hard at some point."

"Well I did but that's not the point-."

"So as I said. It's probably worth a second trip to medical," said Renee. "But the Cult of Hope is very relaxed about these things, I suppose, so it could be worse. Good luck and have fun, I guess."

"I will, thanks," said Emma, sarcastically. Renee was really, really annoying sometimes. She turned to Ayane. "Ayane? What do you think?"

"Well…" said Ayane slowly, staring at the top of the armrest. "I… do think it's a little weird, and I'd like to know more about this vision, but... since it's you, I will support your decision."

"What do you mean 'since it's me'?"

"I know you well enough that it's probably something you thought about and is important," said Ayane. "So, even though I don't agree, I'll support you."

"Well I don't know about 'thought about'," admitted Emma. "I… it's not like I sat down and thought out all of the implications about this."

"But you didn't just decide to do it for kicks, right?" asked Ayane.

"No, of course not—."

"Then that's good enough for me," said Ayane with a nod.

There was a brief pause.

"Well, I am going to go get a drink," said Renee, standing up and stretching. "There is a cafe nearby that seemed interesting. Anyone coming with?"

"I'd like to read some more, thanks," said Ayane.

"Same here," said Emma.

Renee glanced between the two of them. "...Well alright then. I will see you two at a later time. Au revoir."

She exited quietly, still giving them an odd look.

Emma flipped the pages of her book restlessly. Really, she wasn't wanting to read very badly, but Renee was… Renee, sometimes. She was honestly a great friend, someone you could depend on, but Emma needed some time away.

"So, for this… thing, with the Cult," said Ayane. She was still leaning on the arm of her chair. "Do you need to do anything for it?"

"Uh, well, I'm not sure actually," said Emma. "I'm supposed to meet with Abigail, the chaplain, in a few hours."

"Oh, I remember her," said Ayane. "She's very nice."

"Yeah. Did she tell you about her friend?"

"She did. I… I can't help but think that it was a hallucination."

Emma licked her lips. "Well, I mean, it seems really specific for a hallucination."

"But she was dying," said Ayane. "You've died in the sims before, it's not a time where you're clear minded."

"Still, it's really, really specific," said Emma. "I mean, that's a really odd sort of specificity, you know?"

"Emma," said Ayane patiently. "It's not— this doesn't make sense. Think about it."

"I am!" said Emma. "It's— ow!"

Emma grimaced as she waited for her bit tongue to stop hurting.

"Listen to us," said Ayane, shaking her head. "Look, forget I said anything. I said I'd support you, so I won't question your faith like this. I'm sorry."

"It's alright," said Emma quietly.

"I… I'd still like to hear about your, uh, your vision," said Ayane. "If… if you'll tell me?"

"Later," said Emma. "I… I don't really feel like it right now."

"Oh. Okay."

Emma turned the simubook over in her hands, looking at it pensively. That could have gone worse. At least… at least they hadn't really minded. But they hadn't understood. Not at all. It hadn't been expected, no, but Emma had hoped that they might have some idea, after everything she'd gone through, about why she found it so compelling.

Emma took a deep breath and sighed. Well on the bright side, now that Emma had done it once, telling Varsha and Rebecca didn't seem all that bad. The meeting with Abigail would be whatever it would be. There wasn't much chance of it going badly.

Things would be alright.

7. Partaking of the Fruit

Emma lingered on the rapid transit landing before the Cult of Hope's chapel in the redoubt. The walls were still colored pastel lime green. It clashed rather hilariously with the aesthetic of the door before her.

It was a round, white disk of a portal. In the center was a stylized soul gem. Rippling lines branched out to five diamonds, arranged in an inverted starburst about the gem. The door was recessed slightly into the wall, with part of the bottom cut off to make a better pathway. On the bottom right, a pinwheel of intersecting polymer rings was embedded into a second disk.

This was it. This door, that Emma had been staring at for nearly a minute now, was the last thing that separated her from the second most important decision in her life. She still had a chance to walk away. It was… acceptable to believe in a supernatural higher being and not be religious.

But that seemed cheap, to Emma. Sort of a cop out. If you believed in something, you should pursue it with everything you had, right? Or at least, that's how it was for her. It didn't sit right with her, the idea of pulling a cop out like that.

Emma sighed. She still hadn't told Anna. She should probably do so, before going through. But Anna would understand, she was Anna. It was impossible that she wouldn't. Telling her now or later wouldn't change that.

Steeling herself, Emma stepped forward. The pinwheel lit up, glowing blue, before the door rotated itself about the pinwheel to fold away into the wall. A moment later, the pinwheel retracted into the floor.

The room beyond was a small atrium, dimly lit with sconced lamps. The walls were the impossibly dark blackness of deep space, with a cascade of stars falling across them like dust swirling across a desert plain. Each sconce was a small sun, the stars swirling around them in gravitational patterns that pulled and ejected them in an ever perpetuated loop.

With a quiet clunk, the door closed behind Emma. The oval of light on the floor disappeared, and Emma instinctively breathed in sharply. Without the grounding of that oval of light, it looked, and almost felt, like she was suspended in space.

Another door opened in front of Emma. A figure stood in front of it, a shawl smoothing out the shoulders and torso. Bright light glared out from behind.

"Emma, welcome," said Abigail. She stepped back into the light, letting the lamps overhead shine onto her face. "Sorry for the theatrics. We have a lot of artists who contributed to chapel design."

"It's fine," said Emma, moving quickly out of the somewhat unnerving atrium. The brightly lit main worship hall expanded before her, arrayed to focus upon the altar placed in the center. A vague, ephemeral figure stood atop it, carved out of white marble with small mementos scattered about its base. A basket of apples held the place of honor, before the statue's feet. Steps led down the center towards the figure, with long aisles of dark polywood pews stretching beside.

"Is that Her?" asked Emma, looking down the steps at the marble sculpture.

"It's the best we can accomplish," said Abigail. "The Goddess is mysterious. She stays out of sight of those who would portray her, and many girls who received visions see her but cannot remember, or are told not to speak of her appearance."

"Do a lot of girls have visions?" asked Emma.

"Some," said Abigail. She led the way down the steps. Her costume's heavy boots clunked as she walked, but somehow the sound did not seem disrespectful. "Most don't though."

"Oh," said Emma. "How do you get a vision?"

"You have to visit the Ribbon," said Abigail. "Most of us, at least. Homura was different, of course."

"Homura's the prophet, right?" asked Emma.

"That's right," said Abigail. She paused in front of the altar. "Have you learned anything about the Cult since we last talked?"

"No, this is actually a bit of snap decision," said Emma, blushing as she looked away. "But, you know, you hear things from others during training. Nothing concrete though, and lots of contradictions."

"I see," said Abigail. She reached forward and took Emma by the hand. "There's nothing to be embarrassed about. The Goddess cares about everyone, even if they don't really know what they're getting into. Goddess knows I didn't when I joined."

Emma bit her lip, but nodded. "Thanks. It's just, I just told my friends, from Earth, and they didn't really get it, and I still have to tell the others, and I keep thinking that maybe I should have waited longer."

"I'm not going to push you into this, Emma," said Abigail. "It's a big decision. If you need more time, then you need more time. We can just have a cup of coffee and talk if you want."

A long moment passed while Emma tried to gather her nerve. She failed.

"I… I'd like that, actually," said Emma. She gulped. "I…"

"Shh, don't worry about it," said Abigail with a smile. She pulled Emma towards a side door, letting go of Emma's hands once she started to follow. "Come on, I snuck some specialty coffee beans in with my stuff. Don't tell anyone, okay?"

"Uh, alright?" said Emma. "Why would anyone care?"

"Oh, it's not that I think I'll get into trouble," said Abigail. "It's just that anyone who's been in the 12th for awhile knows that I get really good coffee." She opened the door. "Come in, this is my office."

The interior was decorated much like the worship hall. Brightly lit, with dark polywood for furniture and accents. Emma took a seat in front of Abigail's desk, while the chaplain went about grinding the coffee beans, pulling the equipment from a hideaway disguised as a standing set of drawers.

"That smells really good," said Emma, leaning forward as Abigail opened the container of beans.

"Thanks," said Abigail, grinning as she scooped the beans into the grinder. "Specialty stuff I got from our last station. Gene-modded coffee beans can grow in a lotta places, but the closer the conditions are to Earth, the better."

"I see," said Emma. She licked her lips and folded her hands. Dammit, this shouldn't be so difficult to do. She could lead football teams when she was twelve, for the Goddess's sake! This was nothing compared to that.

"I don't mean to pry, but how have things been?" asked Abigail.

"It's been… tough," said Emma. She looked down at the top of the desk, tracing a pattern on top with a finger. "I nearly died."

"Really? Are you alright?" asked Abigail, pausing as she poured hot water into a flask that the grounds had been poured into.

"Yeah, the MHD checked me out," said Emma, waving a hand. "Jessica, the psychiatrist who evaluated me, said I should be fine."

"Well that's good," said Abigail. "Do you… want to talk about it?"

"I… I guess should," said Emma. She kept tracing loops and circles on the table. "It was… it was pretty bad, actually. I was retreating in an IFV, but it got hit by an AT missile or something. The vehicle flipped and I remember seeing the bulkhead fly towards me. Everything was quiet when I woke up and crawled out of the wreckage. I…"

Emma fell silent. Abigail placed a mug of coffee in front of her.

"Thanks," said Emma. She took a sip of the coffee, then smiled. "It's good."

"Spared no expense," said Abigail quietly. "What happened next?"

"I… well, I decided to join the Cult then," said Emma. She watched the steam wafting out of her mug. "I'm not sure it was a rational decision, honestly. I was probably pretty high on neurotransmitters."

"Did you reason it out?"

"I did. I remember thinking that there was no chance I'd have survived the wreck. The squid should have just shot the IFV again, to make sure I was dead. But they forgot or something, and I decided that this had to be the work of the Goddess, since there's no way that something else didn't intervene to save my life."

"Why don't you think that's rational?"

"Well, there's lots of things that could have distracted them," said Emma. She took another sip. "The rest of the forces that were being encircled could have hit the line, or maybe another MG squad attacked. I dunno."

"Perhaps," said Abigail. "Believe what you will about it, I guess. My interpretation of the Goddess is that she doesn't sit idly by, and that she intervenes whenever she can. There's a lot of people who disagree with me, but for what it's worth, I'd believe the Goddess saved you."

"I guess," said Emma. She blew on the top of her mug, watching the steam blast away, then slowly return to its original patterns. "Well I kept walking, you know. I remember feeling really happy. Then I… Then I found the position my platoon had been holding, at the time. They'd… they'd all died."

Abigail winced and took Emma's hand again. "That must have been difficult. I'm sorry."

"Thanks," said Emma. She glanced up at Abigail. "Have you… have you ever lost a platoon like that?"

Abigail nodded. "I've had worse, actually. When I contracted, the war was going really badly. I watched as entire battalions were consumed. It was horrifying. I don't know how I survived."

"How do you stay happy?" asked Emma. She sniffed. "I— just remembering it, finding their bodies—."

"The way Kyouko-sama teaches it," said Abigail. "We need to make sure we live our lives protecting humanity. Take from that what you will. For me, it means that I have to keep my gem clean and move forward, not dwell on the past. I made a lot of mistakes as a greenie, but I learned from them. It's going to be better, Emma, I promise."

Emma gulped. "It's so hard though. I'm not— I'm not good enough for this yet."

"But you will be," said Abigail. "Just stay alive."

"I… I guess," said Emma. She looked at Abigail directly. "It's— it's hard to do."

"Yeah," said Abigail, nodding. "There's a lot of ways to cope. For me, I take solace in the Goddess. I just have to do my duty as best I can, and when the time comes, I'll be alright. But I've been in the rear for a while, not on the line like you, so…"

"Take that with a grain of salt, right?" asked Emma, smiling slightly. "Yeah, it's… it's been different, down in the redoubt. They take a lot of steps to make it comfy."

"That they do," said Abigail. She let go of Emma's hand and raised her mug. "Been down to the chuen yet?"

"Yeah, I went and had lunch with a friend," said Emma. "And I've been to the theater, and the library."

"Oooh, the library is cool," said Abigail. "It keeps going and going…"

"Yeah, it made Ayane's arms itch," said Emma, grinning. "She's a flier, but even so."

Abigail shook her head, smiling as well. "You can put a flier underground, but you can't remove her instincts. That was when you told her? Ayane's from Earth, right?"

Emma nodded. "She doesn't really believe," said Emma. "I… well, I didn't try very hard either. She wanted to know about the vision I thought I had, but…"

"You think you had a vision?" asked Abigail.

"Well, I'm not sure," said Emma. "I told you I almost died. What happened was that I found my platoon and… and I think I let my gem go critical."

Abigail sucked in a breath. "And then?"

"I fell asleep. I… I don't know what happened, not really. I woke up just as my gem started to collapse. I ended up using all my cubes to survive. It hurt. A lot."

"Oh Emma," said Abigail. She rounded the desk and gave Emma a hug. "You're very strong to have made it through that. Goddess knows I would have faded then."

"I dunno, you're pretty old," quipped Emma, letting herself lean into the hug. It was a nice hug.

"Oi, hush," said Abigail, rapping her knuckles against Emma's head. She held the hug a moment more, then returned to her seat. "Do you still want to talk about it?"

"It helps a little, actually," said Emma. She smiled at Abigail, genuinely. "It's easier talking to you than Jessica. Dunno why that is."

"Well, I suspect it's because you know that they're there to try and evaluate you," said Abigail, shrugging. "I always had an easier time talking to my CO rather than the psychiatrists. If you want to continue then…?"

"Ah, well, actually, there's not much more," said Emma. "All I remember is a dream. It's faded a lot, and I can't remember much, but…"

"…But?"

"You're… you're going to laugh at me, but the thing I remember the best is… is being tucked in, and feeling really, properly safe for the first time since I contracted.," said Emma. "It was… it was really nice."

Abigail leaned back in her chair and whistled. "Wow," she said. "…Wow. I… I don't know what to say to that."

"You believe me?"

"Well of course," said Abigail. "I mean, it's the first time I've heard of it, and visions only are supposed to happen at the Ribbon, back on Earth. But my friend died seeing something, so I can believe you nearly dying and seeing something."

Emma smiled again. "Thanks for believing me," she said. "It felt real. Maybe it was just my gem making me hallucinate, but I think it was definitely real. And after something like that, I can't ignore it. That's the reason I'm still here."

"Then what's stopping you?" asked Abigail. "I mean, don't get me wrong, this is still your decision, but if that's what's convinced you, then why not go for it?"

Emma frowned at her coffee. "I'm… not sure. There's no reason to be. I've faced down worse."

"Well, maybe it's because you're a footballer," reasoned Abigail. "You're used to facing things in the field that you can outrun or outfight. This isn't something you can deal with that way."

"I guess," said Emma. She sipped her coffee thoughtfully. "I never thought of it that way. Different tactics for different missions, right?"

"Exactly," said Abigail with a nod. "It's different for everyone. I find that it's best to try and think through what's bothering you, and figure out the mental block."

Emma swirled her coffee in its mug and considered this. She should probably try harder to face things in her social life, it sounded like. Anna's advice about Ingrid had actually basically told Emma to confront the situation thoughtfully.

"So, for the Cult…," said Emma slowly. "What bothers me is… is…"

Emma stared at the coffee in her mug as she mulled things over. The surface of the coffee had small bubbles strung along the edges, clinging to the interior of the mug even though Emma had drunk some of the contents.

"…I think, my problem is that I'm still afraid," said Emma. She looked up at Abigail. "I don't know what will happen if I join the Cult, and it scares me."

Abigail nodded. "The future is unknowable and frightening," she agreed.

"But…," continued Emma, thinking aloud. "But… the best way to confront this… is to move forward, isn't it? To see what happens and adapt accordingly?"

"On the battlefield, sometimes, yes," said Abigail cautiously.

Emma looked back down at her coffee. She swirled the contents in a circle, watching the bubbles race along the sides. She stopped and placed the mug on the table, leaning forward onto the table and still watching the bubbles. Slowly, the spinning bubbles span into the center of the mug, clumping into a ball.

If Emma never joined the Cult, she'd be stuck here, at this point, forever. Hovering on the edge between committing to something she believed in and effectively pretending it didn't exist. There was no turning back from the Goddess, not after everything she'd seen and done. Nothing left to do, in the end, except move forward.

"I've decided," said Emma, standing up. "I'm going to join the Cult."

Abigail seemed slightly taken aback, but rallied quickly. "Are you sure?" she asked. "This is a big step."

"I'm sure," said Emma. A sense of finality and elation began to spread through her chest, starting in the middle and bubbling outwards. Unbidden, a grin sprang to her lips. She believed in the Goddess, and She deserved Emma's gratitude and worship. It felt good to be committing to that. Properly, and without hesitation.

"Alright then," said Abigail. She breathed out and stood up, gathering the shawl around her. A moment later, she smiled at Emma and stepped around the desk. "Come on, we need to do this in the worship hall."

The lights turned down as Abigail entered the hall, Emma following close behind. The statue of the Goddess shone brightly as the lights shifted to focus upon it. Abigail stood before the statue, gazing up at the obscured face proudly and confidently.

"Blessed Lady," she began. "We come before you today to welcome a sister into the Cult founded in your name." She turned, still standing before the altar, and gestured towards Emma. "Her name is Emma Sinclair, and is from Earth. Emma, could you please transform?"

Emma licked her lips, jitters coming on despite her decisiveness earlier, and stepped forward into the ring of light around the altar. Light sparked from the ring on her finger, billowing out in a cloud. As Emma passed through, the weight of her costume's armor settled itself onto her body. She brushed her hair back, letting the earring her soul gem changed into glint in the light shining upon the statue.

Abigail knelt before the altar briefly, picking up an apple from the basket standing in front of it. She held it up to the statue.

"My Lady, while we know little of your nature and your being, we know one thing in certainty," said Abigail. The apple shone in the light, a radiant and bright red that almost glowed. "We know that you save us. Each and every magical girl, when her time comes, may count upon your presence to bring her out of despair and into the light, so that she may pass on and leave her suffering behind her."

Abigail bit into the apple with a crunch. She chewed and swallowed. "This apple, I say, shall represent my wish, and the wishes of all magical girls. I have taken my bite from this apple already, and stand before you as a torch bearer, trusting in you and performing my duty to save and protect humanity from those that seek its end."

Abigail turned to Emma, and held out the apple. "Emma Sinclair," she said. "You too, have made a wish. Will you partake of this fruit? Will you pledge yourself to the service of humanity, in the darkest of nights and in the most blinding of days? Will you trust in the Goddess on high, to save you in the end?"

Emma blinked. She realized she was crying. Memories sprang up. Memories of Anna, who looked so sad, but somehow proud, when Emma showed her the gem that was Emma's soul. Memories of her platoon, dead and strewn about their position, defiant to the last. Memories of Tracy Geyeller, and her fear as she lay in the dirt, believing she was going to die.

Much had passed, and still more lay ahead. Emma didn't know what would happen, nor did she know how she would react. There were few things that were certain. But, whatever happened, Emma knew that she would fulfill her duty. That she would make the best of the situation given to her, so as not to let anyone down. And that when, inevitably, Emma one day died, she would be able to rest in safety and peace, forever.

"I will."

Emma took the apple. Without hesitation, she bit into it. The flesh was crisp and sweet. Juice ran down it and onto her gloves.

Abigail nodded at her, and turned back to the statue. "My Lady, I now ask for your blessing. Since we still live, I ask that your wisdom light Emma's path, so that she may not despair, but serve and protect humanity for all the days that are allotted to her. Since all must eventually pass, I ask that your mercy and grace catch Emma as she falls, so that she may pass with a glad heart, sure of purpose and free of fear."

Abigail paused, as if listening to the Goddess whisper in her ear. Then she turned, smiling, to Emma.

"Welcome, Emma Sinclair, to the Cult of Hope. May kindness and mercy follow you all the days of your life, and may you dwell in the light of the Goddess forever."

8. Cups That Runneth Over

The last thing Abigail did before Emma left the chapel was press a gold brooch into Emma's hands after she'd untransformed. The Cult's symbol was etched into the brooch's metamaterial face, the material rippling in the light as Emma tilted it. It changed into a deep, subdued, red after Emma pinned it onto the front pocket of her hoodie.

"There's also classes, discussion meetings, and other Cult activities you can participate in," said Abigail, forwarding the relevant information.

"Classes?" asked Emma, wrinkling her nose in distaste.

"Well you've got to find out about what you've just joined somehow," said Abigail, chuckling. "Come on, it's not that bad."

"I… guess," hedged Emma. "At least it's not economics or something…"

"Just make sure you know the basics," said Abigail. "After that, you can just do the fun stuff if you want. Take a look at 'ministry activities'."

"Oh, you've got football matches," said Emma, grinning as she scrolled through the list. "That's great, I haven't had a chance to play in a long time."

"Bring your friends," suggested Abigail. "There's not enough girls available, usually, to get a really good game going, and we like to try and spread the word to whoever we can reach."

"Yeah, alright," said Emma enthusiastically. "I don't know what my schedule's going to be like though, but I'll try to get them to come when I can."

"Great!" said Abigail. "Do you have anything else you'd like to talk about?"

"No, not really," said Emma. "Thanks. For everything."

Abigail nodded. "Of course," she said. "Any time you need to speak to someone who's not a shrink, feel free to come by, alright?"

"Yeah," said Emma. "I'll see you around then."

The ride back to Emma's residence block seemed extraordinarily short. Emma's mind was still buzzing with what had just happened, and it kept her preoccupied. Varsha and Rebecca were in the latter's room, going over a map, when Emma returned.

"Oh hey Emma," said Rebecca. She gestured at her room. "Come in. You'll have to sit on the bed, but it's clean, I promise."

Varsha punched her in the arm, blushing. "A-anyway, what's up?" she asked, ignoring Rebecca's collapse into giggles.

"Well, I've got some important news that I wanted to share with you guys," said Emma. She stuck her hands into the pocket of her hoodie. "Have you got a minute?"

"Sure," said Rebecca. The floating map was pushed to the side, and the couple scooted to the side to give Emma space to sit. "So, what's happening?"

Emma took a deep breath, held it, and breathed back out. Here went nothing. "I joined the Cult of Hope. I thought you ought to know."

Varsha and Rebecca blinked at her.

"Do you… do you have any questions?" Emma asked.

"What did joining the Cult entail?" asked Varsha. "Was there a process?"

Emma nodded. "Let me just send you the memory," she said. "It's probably easier than trying to tell you verbally."

"Alright."

Emma fiddled with her brooch nervously while she waited for them to finish watching. She recalled suddenly that she had started crying part of the way through, and hastily squashed down a squirt of embarrassment. She still wanted to tell them about her experience, though. It was important to her, at least, and it seemed like the sort of thing that others in your social circle needed to know when it happened. And besides, despite Ayane and Renee not having a clue, Emma wasn't ashamed of her faith. Varsha and Rebecca finished the memory a moment later.

"So is that it then?" asked Varsha.

"Uh, yeah," said Emma. She shifted slightly in her seat. "There's not much to it, honestly."

"Huh," said Rebecca, blinking at the last frame of the memory Emma had forwarded to them. "I was expecting something more… involved, I guess."

"Honestly, I thought the Cult would be kind of creepy," admitted Varsha. "But that's a lot better than I thought it would be."

"What do you mean?" asked Emma.

"Well, there's this group of Christians that are in my hometown," said Varsha. "It's uh… well…"

"Oh come on, they're not that bad," said Rebecca. "There are some out where I live. They're really nice!"

"Different planets, different Christians," said Varsha, shrugging. "The ones I have go around in this pack. Matching clothes, matching facial expressions…"

All three of them shivered simultaneously.

"Well I'm sure there are some members of the Cult who are like that," said Emma, scratching her head. "But Abigail's not like that. I'm not like that."

"Of course," said Varsha. "It's better than I expected. As long as you don't start doing the creepy dance, congratulations and stuff, I guess. Is that something you congratulate people on?"

" 'Course you do," said Rebecca, rolling her eyes at Varsha. "Congratulations Emma. It's a big step, and I'm happy for you!"

"Thanks," said Emma, smiling. "It means a lot. I told Renee and Ayane earlier, but it… didn't go so well."

"Ah, yeah, we heard," said Varsha sympathetically. "Ayane and Renee were talking about it when they got back. I can't say I don't share their views, honestly, but—."

"What Varsha means is we get where you're coming from and think you're not crazy," said Rebecca flatly, punching her girlfriend in the arm. "Jeez, Varsha, be better at social interaction."

"Hey, ow!"

Emma smiled at them. "It's fine," she said. "It's just nice to know that somebody gets where I'm coming from."

"Well we've known people who are religious," said Rebecca. "The colonies have a lot of them, you know. I'm good friends with a few, actually."

"I'm not…" said Varsha, rubbing her arm.

Rebecca thumped Varsha in the shoulder again.

"Ow!"

"So what were you two doing before I showed up?" asked Emma, hiding her smile at Varsha's pained expression. Totally whipped, that girl.

"I've got a mission down by South Metro," said Rebecca, sobering quickly. With a gesture, she flicked the map she and Varsha had been examining back into view. "I'm supporting MagOps Team 9 to gather intel on enemy logistical dispositions. You know the squid still haven't restarted the attack? It's just skirmishes right now."

"It's been, what, a day already?" asked Emma, raising an eyebrow. "They usually react faster than this. What's happened?"

"We've no idea," said Varsha. She traced out the space battle overtop of the ground battle. "The squid fleet's pulled out of position though, here and here. They're still able to cover orbital bombardment, but they've grouped more defensively to cover the rear."

"Logistical difficulties then," said Emma, frowning. She pulled the map so that it zoomed out and looked at the supply line, stretching from the plains in the center of the continent and spreading out to maintain contact with all squid forces. "Show me the plots across the last four days."

Emma's TacComp overlaid the plots in sequence. The supply chain started out moving in relatively straight lines, with consideration to any terrain changes. On day three, however, offshoots began to appear.

"That's odd," said Emma, pointing out an offshoot in the region of the aerodome, several kilometers west. "Look, there's no reason to send a line out to that area. It sort of stops too. Can we get images of that area?"

"Can you wait until later?" asked Rebecca. "Mission. I have one. Remember?"

"Oh, right, sorry," said Emma. She pushed the map to the side, saving it into her memory for later. Rebecca's map for her mission reappeared.

"Right, so I'm moving with Team 9, they're called the Teenage Scare, by the way—."

"What a terrible name."

"—I know right? Anyway, we're going pretty deep into the enemy's rear. We were looking at escape routes, in case things went ugly."

"Ah," said Emma. She winced. Being at the back of the enemy line was very counterproductive to that sort of thing. And on top of that: "It… seems kinda early for you," said Emma. "I mean, you're good, but MagOps teams are just so much better than us."

"Yeah, I dunno, I guess I'm flattered?" said Rebecca. She twisted the sheets under her hands. "I'm nervous too, of course, but either there's literally no one else or I'm a lot better than I thought I was."

"No way you're the last mind controller in Helsinberg," said Emma, shaking her head. "You guys get the easy jobs and don't— ack!"

Emma ducked, laughing, as Rebecca took a swing at her. "Shut up, we do not!" protested Rebecca, grinning. "Just 'cause we're more important than you AOE fighters doesn't mean you get to be jealous, Emma."

"Who says I'm jealous?" asked Emma primly. "I don't need validation."

Rebecca stuck her tongue at Emma. They all laughed. It was a much needed drop in tension.

"You'll be fine," said Emma confidently, getting up to go. "Besides, you've got Varsha to get back to, right?"

Rebecca blinked at Emma, before flushing bashfully. "Well… yes."

Varsha covered Rebecca's hand with her own, bumping their heads together. "I'll be waiting for you," she said. "Come back safe, 'kay?"

"Mmm," said Rebecca, leaning against Varsha, hiding her face in Varsha's hair.

"Hey, what are you embarrassed about?" asked Emma, raising an eyebrow. "Aren't you supposed to be the open one in this relationship?"

"D-don't make it into a thing like that," said Rebecca, still hiding. "You make me think too much about it and I get embarrassed."

Emma looked at Varsha, who shrugged minutely.

"I'll just be going then," said Emma. "See you later."

Varsha and Rebecca waved. The door clunked shut behind Emma. She walked to her door, pausing in front of Tracy's vacant room briefly on the way.

Emma lay down on her bed and stared at the ceiling. It really had only been a few days since she'd landed on Samsara. Two days of fighting, another day of hiking, and a day of recuperation. It felt like months had passed. Maybe it was the time dilation that came with combat. Psychological fatigue, too, from the stress. It was a good time for that nap she'd been planning on. One last thing to do before that though.

The long distance vid call took a moment to authenticate. Emma hurried double checked the time on Earth. Ah, good. Anna was out of class.

"Emma!" said Anna excitedly. "Oh it's so good to see you! How is everything?"

"It's fine," said Emma, grinning. It could be odd, being a twin. Anna's facial structure was so close to Emma's that people would have gotten them mixed up without nomenclators. But the little differences stood out. Anna's nose crooked a little differently, and her eyes were a little more sharply formed than Emma's. It was like looking in a mirror except not. "How are things at home?"

"Oh, it's been alright," said Anna, yawning. "Guh. That assignment I was working on was due today. Stayed up all night working on it, only got like half an hour of sleep."

"Jeez, you okay then?"

"Nah, it's nothing we haven't done before," said Anna, waving it off. "Remember?"

"Oh yeah, that was a great experience," said Emma, rolling her eyes. "Totally worth the grade we got too."

"Well, Professor Spellmeyer was…"

"An ass?"

"I wouldn't put it that way, precisely, but something of that nature, yes," said Anna, looking to the side.

"But well, if you're okay, I guess try to get some extra sleep tonight," said Emma. "Or just don't show up to class, that's always a plan."

"Emma, only you skive off class to go napping," said Anna, giggling. "There was always rampant speculation when you and anyone else would go missing at the same time."

"Oh Goddess, don't even remind me," groaned Emma, covering her eyes. "You know it's happened again here? I fall asleep with a girl this one time in the hospital…"

Anna's eyebrows shot into her hairline. "What? That's kind of fast, isn't it?"

"Dammit, Anna, not you too!"

"But really, what did you expect?" asked Anna. "Come on, Emma, you slept with her."

"Not like that!"

"Well of course not, you were in a hospital, but even so—."

"No, I meant I literally accidentally fell asleep," said Emma exasperatedly. "She needed a hug, and medical had drugged me pretty heavily. That's all."

"…that would require some very intense drugs," said Anna with mild dubiousness. "But I'm not familiar with military medicine, so if you're sure…"

"Yes, I'm sure," said Emma. "Look, you can even meet the girl if you really bloody want to. She'll tell you the same thing."

"Sure, that would be nice," said Anna. "Do I know her already?"

"I've told you about Ayane, haven't I?" asked Emma. "We met during orientation."

"I think so," said Anna. "Um… Japanese, flying mage?"

"Yeah, that's right," said Emma. She sent an image of Ayane from one of the sims, transformed and getting ready to jump into the air. Her cloak and hair rippled around her as the magic built up, crackles of amber flickering in the air. "That's her."

Anna looked at the image for a moment, her eyes flicking to the left. "I see… she's cute."

Emma gave Anna a very flat look.

"Sorry, sorry," said Anna, smiling and filing the image away. "Anyway, that sort of thing aside, what else is new?"

"Well…" Emma hedged, considering what had happened and how much she should talk about. "…It's been… rough, I guess, but nothing I couldn't handle."

Anna narrowed her eyes. "You're hiding something."

Dammit. "Well yeah, but I don't want to worry you."

"You hiding things from me worries me," said Anna. "Just tell me how things are going, Emma, please."

Emma grimaced and stood up to pace in the narrow space, thinking over what she might say. It would be a horrendously bad plan to tell Anna directly that she'd almost died. In fact, telling her about the situation in any detail was inviting a massively worried and upset reaction that Emma neither wanted to cause nor deal with. On top of that, since the battle was still on going, there were issues with what could be released, for PR reasons.

"It's been… been… problematic," Emma eventually managed. "We're not supposed to talk too much, since the situation's still evolving, so I can't tell you everything."

Anna's brow wrinkled unhappily. "Have you been staying safe, at least?"

"I've been trying," said Emma placatingly. "It hasn't been easy, but I've been doing my best."

Anna looked at Emma with a small frown, and sighed. Her head tilted slightly to one side, letting some of her bangs fall across her eyes. She looked down at the ground, biting her lip, and rocked back and forth twice.

"I… I'm sorry, Anna," said Emma guiltily. "I know you worry about me, but I have to do what's… what's required, on the field."

"I know, I know, but it's really difficult," said Anna. She didn't look up at Emma. "I just wish that you didn't have to fight in a war, if you contracted."

Emma chuckled grimly. "Yeah, well, I have an Incubator handy, so if you want to give it a shot…."

Anna shook her head. "No. I… I would, but I'd wish for something that would involve you, and I don't want to mess up your life any more than it already is."

"…Well look, you shouldn't contract period," said Emma, blinking rapidly. "I don't want you in the line of fire."

"Well that's easy for you to say!" said Anna hotly. "You're not sitting around hoping your sister doesn't get killed, light years away from you!"

"That's totally irrelevant—!"

"It isn't!" said Anna, blinking away tears. "It's not irrelevant! You know what's happening and can deal with it! Me, I'm sitting here without a clue!"

Emma opened her mouth to retort, then snapped it shut and looked away. Goddess damn it, this was not how this was supposed to go. This was supposed to be a happy call. Emma was supposed to catch up on Anna's life, tell her about the Cult, and they'd all move on. Yelling at each other was not supposed to be in the equation.

"Look, I'm sorry for being… insensitive, and stuff," sighed Emma. "I just wanted to see you, is all. It's been a while."

Anna was quiet, wiping her eyes, before replying. "…Yes, it has."

"And um… and I wanted to tell you about something else."

Anna looked up at Emma, swallowing. "What is it?"

"I… I joined a religion," said Emma, licking her lips. "I went to the chapel of the Cult of Hope a few hours ago, and I thought you would want to know."

Anna blinked at her. "…What? You… you joined a cult? Wha— why?"

"Not 'a' cult, 'the' Cult," emphasized Emma. "The Cult of Hope. It's a magical girl religion. I… I had an… experience, in the field, a couple of days ago."

"What kind of an experience?" asked Anna.

"I'm… not sure I should say," said Emma. Anna would absolutely react badly to any details.

"Why not?" asked Anna, temper flaring again. "Why do you have to hide this from me as well?"

"It's just because of policy," said Emma quickly. "I would tell you if I could, but it's an evolving situation and I'm not supposed to talk about it. I'm sorry."

"…and this… experience, convinced you to join a religion?" asked Anna, raising an eyebrow. "You're the least philosophical person I know, Emma. What could have possibly convinced you?"

"I— that's not fair," said Emma, frowning. "I'm not philosophical, but you don't need a philosophical argument to convince someone of the existence of the Goddess. You just need empirical evidence."

"So you saw a supernatural being."

"Yes."

"…How?"

Emma frowned. "I've just told you I can't tell you."

"That's completely ridiculous!" said Anna. "That's not even part of the military!"

"It's related to—!"

"It is not related to combat and you know it!" Anna fired back. "Damn it, Emma! When did you start cutting me out of your life?!"

Emma reeled. "I am not cutting you out of my life!" she yelled. "Do you want to hear every detail about what I do now?! How much it scares me, how much I've had to fight to survive?!"

"Just tell me something more than 'it's classified'!" Anna shouted. "I need to know—!"

"I almost died, alright?" Emma asked angrily. She ignored Anna's shocked gasp. "I found my platoon, and they were dead, and I despaired and nearly had my gem go out. That's what's happened to me, okay? And I lived, and I saw the Goddess when I was dying, and that's why I joined the Cult."

Anna's hands were clasped to her mouth, tears tumbling down from her eyes and across her hands. Emma blinked, rapidly increasing horror cascading as she realized what she'd just said.

"Oh Goddess, Anna, I'm sorry I didn't mean—."

"I have to go," said Anna shakily, rubbing at her eyes. "I'm sorry, Emma, but I have to— I can't—."

"Anna, no, please, I'm sorry, wait—!"

"I'll— I'll talk to you later," said Anna.

The line closed.

"Anna!" Emma shouted desperately, immediately rekeying the call. It came back refused. "Damn it!"

She turned to her right, stepped once, and aimed a kick into the wall. It hit with a loud thud and a crack, making Emma sit down heavily, cursing as she cradled her foot. She'd forgotten to reinforce her foot with magic, and it sounded like she'd cracked the bone.

This was not supposed to happen. Emma had thought that Anna would be alright. That she would understand what was happening, the things that Emma was doing. That she was seeing things that nobody her age ought to see, and that it was dangerous and risky and yes, Emma could very well die. Anna had always been good at this. Being empathetic and understanding other people. Why not now? Why, when Emma needed support from Anna the most, did she suddenly no longer get it?

Emma's door slid open.

"Emma?" asked Ayane, stepping into the room. "Are you alright? I heard something hit my wall…"

"Y-yeah," said Emma, sniffing. "I-I'm fine. I j-just needed to b-blow off some steam. Forgot to reinforce my f-foot. Stupid."

Ayane closed the door behind her, then slowly stepped closer to Emma and sat down. The room was small enough that the two of them on the floor was slightly cramped.

"Did… you get some bad news?" asked Ayane.

Emma shook her head. "I c-called Anna. We… talked."

Ayane blinked at this. "That's… good, isn't it?"

"It's supposed to be," said Emma. "She… she's really worried about me."

"And?"

"And she doesn't get it," Emma said with a low laugh, letting herself fall backwards onto the floor. She was crying. "She has no idea what's happening, and I can't tell her or she'll just get worse. What am I supposed to do?"

"Oh, Emma," sighed Ayane. She pulled Emma back up and into a hug.

"What am I supposed to do, Ayane?" Emma repeated, voice hollow.

Ayane sighed again.

"I don't know."

The waiting room of the medical bay Tracy was being revived in was low-vaulted and circular. Lamps had been recessed down the length of the pillars that supported the ceiling, their light a slowly shifting array of blues and purples and greens rendered pale against the white walls. Chairs with black cushions were arranged in neat rows within the center, and a drinks dispenser stood in the back. It had a holographic label beneath, informing users that alcoholic beverages were not installed on this device, due to limits imposed by the Surgeon General's Office and the Mental Health Division.

Emma sat alone, facing the entrance, elbows braced against her knees and a cup of water in her hands. She took a sip. It was still fairly cold, due to the insulating qualities of the cup. She would have preferred alcohol, but circumstances conspired against her.

She pulled up her deployment orders to look over them again. Agapita had failed to mention that Hinata Shizuki was garrison commander of Helsinberg's magical girl compliment and the military units stationed there. Emma was to report in to her, but not for a combat mission as had been previously planned. Her conversation with Anna was affecting her mood, and the MHD was just worried enough to want her to spend some time hunting demons before going back into combat. It was a reasonable order, honestly, but she would have preferred to deal with things by blowing something up. By now, everything had knotted into a ball of frustration, and what more cathartic way to deal with that than to smash and destroy? Then again, that was probably the issue.

This wasn't the time for such thoughts though. Despite their reservations about her immediate combat readiness, the MHD had determined that it was perfectly reasonable for her to be at Tracy's reawakening. She'd been the last person Tracy had seen, after all. A review of Emma's memory on the event made it seem unlikely that Tracy would remember that Emma had pulled the trigger on her.

The door to Emma's left opened. A magical girl wearing a lab coat over her costume stood outlined in the bright lighting of the medical bay.

"Emma, we're ready to begin," said the girl. Emma's nomenclator labeled her as Nikol Kardos. "If you'd follow me."

Emma stood and followed Nikol into the decontamination chamber. The polyglass walls gave her a good view of the medical bay's layout, or at least those areas that had not been rendered opaque for privacy reasons. It was a sharp contrast to the waiting room, the hallways clean and brightly lit.

"So, what's this going to be like?" asked Emma as the sanitation process began.

"We'll take care of most of it, but you'll be her first touchstone," said Nikol. Her costume, a strangely feathery affair, fluttered as the drones made their way up her body. "That means you'll be her first psychological anchor after awaking. We'll need you to be ready for when she wakes up."

"Do you know how she's going to wake?" asked Emma, swallowing quietly. That wasn't a big responsibility at all.

"Probably violently, in all honesty," said Nikol. "Her last memory will have been being in combat, so her combat instincts will probably fire instantly. Her TacComp will help some, but we've seen girls over-ride the TacComps in these scenarios."

Emma nodded, biting her lip. This would be tricky.

"There's some magic tricks I know that will help," added Nikol, leading the way towards Tracy's room. "And of course, the technicians will be present to do what mundane things they can."

Emma transformed as she walked. "You've done this a lot then."

"Well, I'd only been contracted for a month or so when the first reawakenings started being performed," said Nikol. She glanced over at Emma, grinning in amusement. "You hadn't even been born, you know."

Emma rolled her eyes. She'd started getting used to girls who looked her age being much, much older. "Yeah, yeah."

"Anyway, we're here," said Nikol. She gestured for Emma to enter the polyglass cube.

Tracy's body lay on the examination table. A single white sheet was laid on top of it. Various lines and cables ran down into the base of the table, with a large bundle running out to a console where a technician was standing. He nodded at Emma as she entered. The only other person there was a doctor, there to ensure that everything went smoothly.

Emma didn't bother to nomenclate anyone else. She moved to stand next to the table. At first, the body didn't seem to be functional. It took a moment for Emma to realize that it was just breathing very slowly. Tracy's body was probably swimming in drugs.

The doctor lifted the sheet to double check the leads. "Everything looks good here," he said, and turned to the technician. "Everything green on your end?"

"Yes," said the technician. "Ready to begin activation sequence."

"Mrs. Kardos?"

"I'm ready," said Nikol, from where she was standing in the corner. She'd shed her lab coat. A dim layer of aqua-colored magic hovered over her hands.

"And how about yourself, Miss Sinclair?" asked the doctor. "I'm sure Mrs. Kardos has briefed you on the situation?"

Emma nodded, licking her lips. "She has."

"Very good," said the doctor, nodding. "We have decided to prep Ms. Geyeller while her body is till in a comatose state, to smooth the transition. Your role will be to provide support, should she react badly after passing through the sleep-like phase. Do you have any other questions before we begin?"

"No."

"In that case, Renard, if you could please begin the activation sequence? Thank you."

It was a strange phrase, Emma thought as she waited. It was almost as if they were treating the body like a drone to be flipped on. As if it were a mechanical being that need only have a component added in order to be fully active. Then again, according to Senbey, there was some philosophical basis for that.

Tracy woke up slowly. Her body twitched once as the Renard brought her out of the induced coma and into a REM-like phase. Tears formed and trickled down her face.

"She's only dreaming," said the doctor calmly as Emma looked at him in alarm. "It's a good sign. It means that her gem has integrated well."

"Well wake her up!" said Emma. Tracy whimpered in her sleep, pushing at the table with her hands as if trying to escape. The sheet covering her body constricted, clinging to the table and to Tracy's body to keep her from struggling too much. This only seemed to worsen her nightmare.

"Finishing REM-phase sequence now," reported Renard. "Bringing out of sleep in three, two, and—."

Tracy snapped awake with a gasp. Her TacComp paralyzed her muscles before she could jerk upright. It took a second for her to process what was happening, her eyes flicking across the room before focusing on Emma.

Emma grinned at Tracy. "Hey there. How you feeling?"

Tracy's expression flicked from shock to surprise to sheer joy in the span of a second. Then she practically leaped from the table, grabbing onto Emma with a happy shriek.

"I'm alive!" Tracy shouted. "I'maliveI'maliveI'malive!"

Emma laughed, hugging Tracy back. "Told you so," she said. "Welcome back, Tracy."

They stayed there for a moment, laughing together and celebrating Tracy's return from the dead. A feeling of lightness swept over Emma. Latent guilt she hadn't realized was pressing down on her now faded, leaving her with only sparkling happiness.

"How are you though?" asked Emma once their laughter had died down. Elation still made her grin stupidly as she stepped back a bit, holding Tracy by the shoulders. "Can you sit up?"

"Yeah, I think so," said Tracy. She braced her arms against the table. "I feel kinda weird though."

"That's normal, I think," said Emma. "Did you get anything in training about body loss?"

"Kind of?" said Tracy. "They just told us that medical could, uh, restore us from gem. It was really vague."

"Well… that's about everything I remember," said Emma sheepishly. They shared another moment of laughter. "Other than that though?"

"Other than feeling weird, yeah, I feel good," said Tracy, grinning brightly. "Did anything happen afterwards? The last thing I remember is you telling me I'd be okay."

Emma sighed in relief. She didn't remember getting shot then. "No, nothing for you to worry about. Everything went well, and we kicked ass."

"Cool," said Tracy. She held up her hand, examining the line coming out of her wrist's access point. "Jeez, I'm all wired up like some sort of drone."

The doctor reappeared. "We can take care of that now," he said. "My name is Dr. Masozi Laevesque. All your diagnostics check out, Ms. Geyeller, so if you don't mind, we'll start unhooking you now."

"Oh, uh, sure," said Tracy.

"I'll wait outside," said Emma as Dr. Laevesque and Renard began to unhook the cables on Tracy's arms and back. "They've, uh, got some cables under the sheet, so I'll see you in a bit."

"Ah, right," said Tracy, flushing slightly but nodding. "See you outside."

9. Marching Orders

With the leads removed, Tracy was able to get dressed. She received a pair of loose-fitting pants and a t-shirt from the military's apparently extensive store of teenager-sized clothing. The pants were colored "jungle combat green", while the shirt was plain black. Unfortunately, there wasn't anything else available, something that had Tracy grumbling over telepathy as she changed behind the privacy screen, deployed from the ceiling.

Afterwards, Dr. Laevesque gave Tracy an hour-long examination via implant-diagnostics. Then he had Nikol guide Tracy through some basic magical girl exercises. It wasn't until both Laevesque and Nikol were fully satisfied that Tracy's soul gem had integrated with her new body that they had let her go, under the provision that she come back for a checkup tomorrow. Normally, the mage in question would have an R&R period of several weeks, but they didn't have time for that now, so Tracy would be re-deploying as soon as she could.

"At least they got my personal things moved," said Tracy as she and Emma landed at their rooms. "I've got a change or two of clothes in there."

"Well, the military's efficient about that sort of thing," said Emma. "Your room's over here."

Ayane was just leaving as the two walked around to Tracy's room.

"Oh, hey there," said Ayane as she caught sight of them. "You must be Tracy! Welcome back!"

"Uh, thank you," said Tracy, blinking. "Um… have we met?"

"No, but there's only the one unoccupied room," said Ayane, nodding over her shoulder. "That, and Emma's told us about you."

"Oh, okay," said Tracy. "Nice to meet you then, Ayane!"

The two of them shook hands.

"What're you up to, Ayane?" asked Emma.

"Mission," said Ayane, shrugging. "Nothing complicated, just an air support patrol. Rebecca's mission got back last night, but they're sending out a SART patrol to confirm."

"A what?" asked Tracy.

"Strategic Assault and Reconnaissance Troopers," explained Ayane. "Human SpecOps. They do the jobs MagOps is too valuable to do."

Tracy grimaced. "That's so dehumanizing."

"It is what it is, don't think about it too much," advised Emma. "The military treats people like objects. It's best to think that way too, at least when you're on duty."

"But—."

"In any case," said Ayane, cutting off any argument. "It's sounding like there's going to be a push of some kind. Keep on your toes."

Emma nodded. Confirming recon by a MagOps team wasn't usually necessary unless you were about to act on that intel. "I'll be doing demon patrol, so here's hoping they don't start anything too soon."

"Ah, yeah, you got an order change didn't you?" asked Ayane sympathetically. "Sorry about… stuff."

Emma grimaced but waved the topic away. "I'm ignoring it until we get some more down time."

"Wait, so you're leaving?" asked Tracy, looking askance at Emma. "I thought you were going to be around?"

"Sorry," said Emma. "I was actually supposed to report in this morning, but they gave me an extension to attend your reawakening."

"Speaking of which, I need to get going," said Ayane, checking her chronometer with a small start. "See you guys later."

"Bye."

Tracy and Emma waved as Ayane stepped into the elevator. Emma turned and walked to Tracy's door, opening it and waving at the inside.

"Well, this is it—."

Emma blinked as Tracy wrapped her arms around Emma and hugged her tightly.

"Um."

"I don't want you to go," said Tracy. Her voice quavered slightly. "I… I'm scared."

Emma blinked down at her again, then returned the hug. "Jeez, Tracy," she said, patting Tracy on the back. "When did you turn into such a wimp? Weren't you all eager a few days ago?"

Tracy sniffed and laughed. "Screw you Emma. 'M not a wimp."

"Yeah? Who's the girl getting all clingy then?"

Tracy huffed and gave Emma a light shove. "Ass."

They spent a moment chuckling, Tracy using the time to reign in her emotions. Both ignored the tears dotting the shoulder of Emma's hoodie.

"Seriously though, you're going to be okay," said Emma. She patted Tracy on the shoulder. "You can do this."

"…thanks," said Tracy, looking down and rocking back on her heels. "It's just… I've already screwed up badly enough to nearly get myself killed. I… I don't want to… to…"

Emma shook her head. "Hey. Look at me."

Slowly, Tracy looked back up at Emma.

"You. Will. Be. Fine," said Emma slowly, enunciating each syllable. "You've got enough talent to charge into combat and survive long enough to get killed. And that's saying something."

"The fuck does that mean?"

"There were a few girls in my training cohort that never made it onto the field in the sims," said Emma seriously. "They just got blasted immediately."

"Then why didn't I—?"

"Because you've got some idea of what's going on," said Emma, standing back. "New girls will be new, but all things considered, you did well. Spend a few days resting up, then get back into the sims, and you'll have nothing to be worried about."

Tracy looked at Emma for a long moment, biting her lip, then nodded. "Alright. I'll, um, I'll look up something to read while I wait."

Emma nodded. "Good idea. They'll probably put you on demon patrol afterwards. Did you get any training on demon containment?"

"No, they saved that for the younger girls," said Tracy. "There's a text file on it though, right?"

"Yup. I'd give that a read."

"I'll look it up," said Tracy. She nodded, more confidently this time. "I'll figure something out, don't worry."

"I believe in you," said Emma. She gave Tracy another smile and pat on the shoulder, then headed for her room to grab her armor and backpack. "See you later, Tracy."

"Bye Emma," said Tracy. She leaned against the side of her door, watching Emma walk away. "See you later."

Emma seemed to be making a habit of being early to her appointments these days. Since she had been needed for Tracy's reawakening, Emma's deployment had been rescheduled to 1100 hours, but she was twenty minutes early. She wasn't entirely sure why, especially given the sheer number of times she'd skipped class in Mitakihara. Then again, maybe she was just reverting to type, since she did recall being very punctual to football events. Her backpack and combat gear had been sent to the relevant bunker by drone.

Specifically, Emma was set to get a briefing and assignment from Hinata in Bunker 1-East. It was a good choice of command post, since it's location in the rear and near the Trichonopoly MetroRail Station, a major hub for transport into uncontested territory, allowed Hinata to keep them mostly out of harm's way and easily evacuated if necessary.

By default, all magical girls stationed in an area were considered part of the area's Daemon-veneuer, French for "demon hunter", Units. For those above the age of thirteen, participation in DV activities depended on whether or not it was a high priority for them. Normal mages like Emma usually cycled in and out of active DV status. Conversely, all of the city's youngest contractees were automatically assigned to the garrison as members of the DVU, and were moved out of DVU only if necessary.

The invasion had caused a surge in contracts across the entire population of Samsara. Emma had no idea why that was the case (it was a potential topic for Senbey when it decided to appear again) but the end result was a rather large glut of young mages in the city. Keeping them safe and alive until they could get more training and experience was Hinata's responsibility.

Emma sighed. The command post was some odd combination of extremely busy and absurdly quiet. The vast majority of the work being done within the structure was either computing work or automated, which resulted in a great many drones scurrying around in a quiet electrical hum. The only actual people there were Hinata's immediate staff and anyone who, like Emma, was getting briefed on a mission.

Someone sat down in the seat next to Emma. She glanced over and saw a boy her age, looking cheerful enough that he was probably committing a crime from sheer over-enthusiasm.

Wait, a boy?

Emma did a double take. The boy wore, loose, khaki, multi-pocketed trousers and a button-down shirt with the sleeves rolled up. A knapsack sat on the floor beside his booted feet. His hair was a sandy brown, parted neatly to the right, and he had dark brown eyes.

Sensing that someone was watching him, the boy looked over at her, then raised a quizzical eyebrow. "Uh, hi?"

"…You're a boy."

"Yes…"

"What are you doing here?"

"I've got a briefing."

"What, at 1100?"

"Yeah."

Emma squinted at him in confusion. The boy responded by raising his other eyebrow and leaning away from her. At this point, Emma's TacComp helpfully ran the nomenclator results across her vision.

The boy's given name was "Ryouta". His family name was "Shizuki." This sounded familiar, and Emma's TacComp quickly supplied a factoid from Emma's conversation with Agapita. Ryouta was Hinata's second son, and apparently currently employed by—

"Governance Public Media?" Emma asked. "You're kind of young to be a War Correspondent."

"Photojournalist," corrected Ryouta. "There's a difference. War Correspondents write the stories and arrange interviews and stuff. I'm just here to take stills."

"Uhh, I don't mean to be insensitive, but can't they get a drone for that?" asked Emma. "It'd probably be easier and cheaper."

"Sure, but you can also get synthesized food," said Ryouta. He seemed to puff up slightly. "My job's not just to get the right exposure and stuff, it's also to try to tell the story, as it is, in images. It's more than just getting a bunch of photos."

Emma wrinkled her brow. "I… guess. I was never really big into journalism or stuff like that, so sorry if I'm kind of dubious."

Ryouta sighed and rolled his eyes. "Nobody really gets photography anymore. Oooh look, perfect lenses, you're all so outdated. Pff."

"I… didn't mean that," said Emma, slightly taken aback by Ryouta's level of annoyance. "It's uh, just that, I mean, uh…" Emma was left in the awkward position of actually having the stated opinion. Damn. "Um… why don't you show me some stills you've taken then? I'd like to see some."

Ryouta gave her another skeptical look.

"Seriously!" encouraged Emma. "Think of it as… proving me wrong. Or something. Not that I think you're wrong."

"…well alright," said Ryouta. "Let me show you something I did on the City."

It took a moment for Ryouta to get things set up. Civilians didn't have the ability to swap files directly like the military did, so he had to use an app, called Showcase, to let Emma see his work.

"Here, take a look," said Ryouta. He handed an instance of the app off to Emma in the form of a glowing sphere.

Emma took it and accessed it through her retinal interface. At first, it looked like a shot of a granite floor, but then— "Whoa."

The first image was a panoramic shot from the top of one of Helsinberg's penthouse suites.

Rendered as if it were laid on the inside of a sphere, the image had been taken with a long exposure time. Each building stood monolithic in the night, Samsara's moon full enough to cast the city in a dim haze resembling dust or fog. Sporadic lit windows shone like lighthouse beacons or, perhaps, like soul gems from within a miasma: bright lights that promised hope and salvation, for when despair hung heavy and no escape was in sight.

Great sheets of flame leaped up the sides of the monoliths from the burning streets, grasping at the gems that glowed in their stone and metal settings, trying to pull them down and consume them, as if those sparks of light were undeserving of their place.

And yet, in the same motion, these flames cast each point of light up into the night sky. Free to soar higher and higher into the darkness and shine on their own, bright and beautiful and, in the frozen moment of the photograph, everlasting.

As she looked around, Emma felt like she was perhaps, for the first time in her life, able to reach the stars.

A moment of breathlessness, uncomprehending, and then Emma was able to grasp herself again and close the presentation to look at Ryouta.

"That was amazing," she said. "That was… that was completely amazing."

Ryouta blinked, slightly taken aback. "Uh, thank you."

"I can't— I'm so— How did you do that?" asked Emma, still somewhat stunned.

"I mean, it's just a basic panorama," said Ryouta, beginning to look embarrassed, if pleased. "I toggled with the exposure, but honestly, it's just finding the right place at the right time."

"That's it? But how do you know what's the right place?"

"Well, a lot of it is just good guesswork," said Ryouta. He shrugged. "I'm not the best at this, of course, but talent and experience lets you judge where and when and how."

"So that's why you need a human then, right?"

"Yeah, exactly."

"Wow."

A brief, somewhat awkward, pause followed. Emma blinked down at the floor, lost in thought, while Ryouta did something similar, basking in the praise.

"Can I keep this?" Emma eventually asked. "I mean, I can transfer you allocs or something, but I'd like to have a copy."

"Keep it, it's fine," said Ryouta, smiling at her. "I'd normally charge you, but, well…"

"Well look, how much does it—?"

"No, honestly, it's fine, don't worry about the cost," said Ryouta. "Not a lot of people can appreciate good photography these days, especially with retinal stills and all that. Call it a thank you gift, for understanding."

Emma blinked at him. "But…"

"No buts, just take it," said Ryouta firmly. He sat back and fiddled with his sleeves, looking pleased. Just a bit of a blush, and a small smile that quirked to one side a bit more than the other.

"I… alright then," said Emma, tucking the image away. "But for the record, I owe you lunch or something."

"If it makes you feel better," said Ryouta, rolling his eyes.

They lapsed into silence.

"Hey Ryouta?"

"Yeah?"

"Why aren't you back in the evac zone?" asked Emma. "You're a civilian, after all. Why stick around and get shot at?"

"…Honestly, I don't know," said Ryouta. He scratched his nose thoughtfully. "I guess growing up in a matriarchy, you get this feeling that you can still do something, even if you're young. Or that you should, you know?"

"But even so, you still can't contract," said Emma, confused.

"Well yeah, but I've also got like twelve cousins, and one of them contracted a few years ago," said Ryouta. "And every female I know is either a mage or close relative to a mage, and Sayaka-chan, our matriarch, comes over like every other year."

"It kinda sounds like that would just make it worse."

"No, see, it's like…" Ryouta paused, trying to put it into words. "It's just more validation that you don't have to be crazy old to make a difference. And it's not like I can't do something epic just 'cause I'm male. It just takes longer, and I guess since I can take photos, I decided that that's how I'd try to make a difference."

Emma leaned back in her chair consideringly. "Hm… that's interesting." She looked over at him. "You know, I was expecting you to be kind of stuffy. I had a Shizuki in my cohort that was like that. Nice enough, but too 'proper'."

"Oh, yeah, that happens, sorry," said Ryouta. "Some of my family members will do that." He leaned closer to speak in a whisper. "For what it's worth, I'm a little worried about your friend, Ami. Nii-san can be very uptight."

"Oh, so it's true, they're married?" asked Emma.

"No, no, there's only plans," said Ryouta, shaking his head. "Nothing's finalized, especially since this happened." He gestured at the bunker. "Rumors are crazy sometimes."

"Yeah, that's true," said Emma.

An extended silence descended. It was not awkward.

The sound of approaching footsteps shifted their attention to the doorway. From what Emma could hear, they were too light to be adults. Magical girls then, and it sounded like there were at least two, maybe three or four, of them. No doubt coming for a briefing, but the next one was Emma's.

Three girls stepped into the room. The first was Magdalena Baatori, a captain from the local garrison and who had remained with the DV to help coordinate and train the newest contractees. Her costume was primarily a deep-indigo, with long sleeves and a fish-scale pattern in gold thread going up its length.

Behind her came Vira Cheung and Motya Schoonenberg, both still assigned to the garrison's DV unit. Vira wore cargo pants, metal-capped boots, and protective gloves that seemed, perhaps, slightly out of date, rather than distinctly magical. The only unusual thing was that she seemed to be wearing a wetsuit underneath her clothes, and that the pants had been bound tightly around her calves.

Motya's costume was more classically typical of magical girls. She had knee length shorts, black with red pinstripes, and a matching sleeveless coat with a deep "V" cut into the tail. Under the coat was a dress shirt and shimmering red necktie. Dress shoes were, of course, the remaining component to the costume.

Well, no sense being impolite. "Good afternoon," greeted Emma.

"Hello," said Magdalena. "Those seats aren't taken?"

"No, it's just been us two for the last few minutes," said Emma. "What're you guys here for?"

"Vira and Motya just turned thirteen," said Magadalena, coming to stop in front of Emma and Ryouta. "They're getting their first assignment out to the line today."

"Oh, I see," said Emma. She blinked, then raised an eyebrow. "That seems… kind of fast."

"Well we'd like to keep them back longer," admitted Magdalena. "But you know, the war."

Emma winced. You couldn't honestly say that someone who'd just turned thirteen was mature enough, without extensive training at least, to really handle combat. For that matter, you couldn't honestly say that anyone was mature enough for combat until they'd been through training. But the training program at least made for a softer landing than being sent directly into combat.

"So you guys are here for your assignments then?" asked Emma, turning her attention to Vira and Motya. They hovered awkwardly in front of the chairs and nodded silently.

An awkward silence descended. Vira and Motya were both clearly nervous, unsure about what was about to happen. The military didn't tell you much, just to report to someone at some time, who would then tell you to go to some other place to do something that may or may not get you killed. Emma was rather used to this by now, her time in the sims giving her plenty of experience going into something with very little knowledge of what was going to happen.

The door to Hinata's office opened. A pair of warrant officers stepped out of it, saluting as they walked past. Emma and Magadalena returned the salute. Vira and Motya flinched, but didn't realize what was happening until the officers had already left.

"Magdalena Baatori, Vira Chueng, Motya Schoonenberg, Ryouta Shizuki, Emma Sinclair?" recited Hinata's aide-de-camp. "The general is ready for you."

Vira and Motya visibly stiffened. Emma could literally smell nervousness on them as she stood up.

"Hey, you know, I forgot to ask," said Emma, turning to Ryouta. "Why are you here exactly?"

"Oh, I'm doing a story on integrating new magical girls into the combat force," said Ryouta. He picked up his knapsack and slung it onto his shoulder. "Nothing terribly complicated, good for new talent, etc."

"Ah, right, that makes— wait," said Emma, coming up short. "Wait wait wait, you said integrating new magical girls?"

"Yes?"

Emma squinted at him, then turned to Vira and Motya, then back to Ryouta. "…Ryouta these are new magical girls. We're all going into the same briefing."

Ryouta paused, then did a double take.

"Wait so, I'm going to be working with them."

"Right, exactly."

"Then if you're here, that means you have to be involved as well," said Ryouta.

Emma frowned at this, but turned back to continue walking. Magdalena was still going to be needed to run the local DVU. That left Emma as the most experienced mage that would be deploying. And if they were all in the same briefing, that meant that Emma was deploying to the same position as the new girls. But Emma was definitely supposed to be doing demon patrol this deployment, and given the bottling-effect of the mountains around the Kolasi Caldera, the battle wasn't going nearly badly enough to start sending barely-experienced mages into combat.

What the hell was going on?

"Ladies and gentleman, have a seat," said Hinata as they entered, looking rather stressed out. She had taken the form of a particularly short twelve year old, dressed in a long-sleeved kimono gown that trailed behind her and was cut off at mid thigh. Dark colored trousers and thick-soled sandals protected her legs. "Everyone is here, Lieutenant?"

"Yes sir."

"Excellent," said Hinata. "In that case let's begin. No doubt you've all figured out by now that this is no ordinary assignment briefing."

Everyone glanced at each other.

"Well fortunately, it's not a case of me breaking terrible news to you all," said Hinata. "Well, it might be terrible news for some. But it could be worse! I could be sending you all off to die with a horribly dangerous mission. That would be bad."

More glances at each other.

"In any case, here is the situation. Bunker 7-South is twenty kilometers from the front and is currently being evacuated via Dunley Station," continued Hinata. "The incursion rate is currently close to nil, but that is dependent on how far one ventures into No Man's Land." She gestured at the map, which formed gradients across the front. "Enemy behavior is currently surprisingly static. The intel we're getting is still being processed, and the situation is developing."

Emma snorted. That was military speak for "we have some new information and are going to shoot something based on that". Great.

"Now, as some of us will know, things have been dying down, but we've needed every girl we had for demon containment before everyone had settled into the redoubt. Civilians and their panicking, you know. With the greater number of mages concentrated into a smaller area, it's become feasible to begin transitioning new girls into the wider combat force, preferably under the supervision of an older mage."

Emma suddenly had a sinking feeling. Hinata turned to face her.

"Emma Sinclair, you are hereby placed in charge of provisional combat team four, which will consist of Vira Cheung and Motya Schoonenberg. Magadalena Baatori will get you up to speed on their status."

"Yes sir," said Emma with, she thought, admirable steadiness in her voice. Goddess, was Hinata serious? Emma was barely even trained herself, how was she supposed to do this?

"Ryouta Shizuki will be joining you for the duration of your deployment, or until such time as he is pulled back from the front," continued Hinata. She gestured at Ryouta. "As I'm sure you've all figured out by now, he is part of GPM and will be working a photographic story on magical girl deployments. Please keep him safe."

Emma, Vira, and Motya nodded. "Yes sir," they said in unison.

"Team Four's mission will be to conduct demon patrol continually across Bunker 7-South's occupied areas and provide assistance to the Dunley Station garrison as necessary. When the bunker is evacuated, come back to 1-East for further orders. Coordinate with the local commander of 7-South for your specific patrol route. Any questions?"

"You have questions, I know you do," said Hinata to Emma privately. Emma fought back the urge to jump. "Don't ask them now, I'll answer them in a bit."

Emma waited in simmering anxiety as the new girls ran through the usual stammered laundry list of anxious questions. She'd done the same thing, of course, during their first drills in training, even if those had been significantly more complicated. They'd gotten a very straightforward mission, and there weren't many ways for it to go. Of course, war time meant that the worst case scenario was quite terrifying.

The questions ended surprisingly quickly, a large number of them being deflected as up to Emma for finalization.

"If there's nothing else, you have an hour to do whatever," said Hinata. "Emma, you'll set the meeting point depending on how you want to handle things."

"Right," said Emma.

"Dismissed," said Hinata.

The group stood to go. "Wait a moment," Hinata said privately to Emma. "You had questions and I said I'd answer them."

Emma paused as Ryouta exited. He nodded to her, then headed out.

"I suppose your first question will be, why me?" asked Hinata after the door shut.

Emma turned around and stood nervously in the office. She nodded as Hinata came around the desk and sat on its front and edge, swinging her legs back and forth. "A more experienced girl would be better, wouldn't she?"

"Perhaps," said Hinata, smiling at Emma encouragingly. "But you should have more confidence in yourself. Making team captain at age twelve is a hell of a resume booster, you know. You've got skills that can be applied to this situation."

"But there's so much that can go wrong," said Emma. She bit her lip and looked down at her feet. "I mean, I can do some stuff well, but there's this offensive coming up and—."

"But you can't control that," said Hinata, still smiling at her. "You need to focus on what you can control, like what you're going to teach them to make sure they're prepared for whatever happens. Even if it means dying, you have to make sure their deaths will mean something."

Emma swallowed nervously.

"Of course, you're scared about this. It'd be worse if you weren't," said Hinata. She hopped down and took Emma by the hand. It was a strange feeling, looking down at someone who was trying to comfort you. Emma was used to looking the other way. It didn't help that when she met Hinata's eyes, she saw a century and a half of wisdom, not a child's innocence and naivety. "Trust me. Being afraid, or at least knowing and understand the magnitude of what could happen, is good. It's important for being a good teacher. But don't let it control you. Recognize it and master it, so that you'll be able to do your job to the best of your ability."

"What about your son?"

To this, Hinata winced. "I… I cannot blame you if he gets hurt," she said, dropping Emma's hand and turning away. Takkun doesn't really understand combat or how bad it can get. He will need to be protected."

"I'll do my best."

"Of course you will," said Hinata. She turned. "I wouldn't expect anything less from anyone under my command. You'd better go get prepared, unless you have other questions?"

"No."

"Very well. Dismissed."

10. Stepping Into the Sun

The intervening hour between Emma's meet-up with her… new subordinates and the end of the briefing was filled by an extended conference with Magdalena. It was a worrying conversation. Neither girl was particularly talented, nor did they have any supremely unusual powers. But, according to Magdalena, they worked hard and were fairly adaptable to new situations. Not amazing, but then again Emma wasn't sure she could handle a pair of insane prodigies.

Vira's primary magic was a type of auto-targeting, allowing her to hit with an improbably high rate of impact for anything within three kilometers. Her primary weapon was a bolt action rifle that, unfortunately, needed to be reloaded before every shot. Amusingly, Vira was also able to cram a huge amount of equipment into her pockets somehow, though Emma didn't laugh and instead worried about how that would translate into combat effectiveness.

Conversely, Motya's abilities centered around, of all things, distilled spirits. Bottles of vodka, specifically, and the ability to distill specific object properties into them. For example, one of the less successful attempts had been when Motya had distilled the high flammability of gasoline into a small bottle, then drunk it to see what would happen. The result, unfortunately, had been "shoot fire out of mouth with every breath" until the bottle had worn off. The various compositions could even be saved into her subconscious, or something, and recalled from a list that her magic automatically created.

Emma decided on an overland route to their next position. Dunley Station was the southernmost hub of Helsinberg's public railway system, and 7-South was consequently the farthest bunker from 1-East. Taking the subway there was, of course, easier, but working overland would let Emma point out some of the parts of military life that they would only have had a cortical dump on. It would also be convenient for Ryouta, and hopefully get a lot of photography out of the way early. He was a friendly enough, but Emma didn't relish having him follow them around on patrol.

First though, they needed to do the awkward meet-and-greet thing. Emma sighed as she rode the elevator up to surface level. She had decided to do the meeting over lunch, on the roof of the building 1-East was under. It was a fairly tall skyscraper, which would give them a good view of the surrounds, though the rear was substantially less shelled than the areas closer to the front. Emma had decided just to have one of the ration packs still stuffed into her backpack, but she suspected that there would be an attempt at delivery from a canteen by everyone else.

Emma sighed again. That would probably be one of the hardest parts about the transition for everyone involved. Food was important to morale.

The elevator dinged to a stop at the ground level and rolled open the doors. Emma nodded at a group of soldiers as she passed, waving off an aborted move to salute her. The building was apparently some sort of large office complex, with multiple companies listed on a bronze placard in the stone lining of the atrium. The concrete underneath had been exposed in multiple places, the military implanting heavy alloy cover barriers in to create cover where there had been none before. The building was in fact largely empty for the moment, most of the troops pulled away south or stationed in the very top floors as Signals Intelligence or sniper teams.

Emma needed to burn off some energy. Suddenly being handed a command like this was rather nerve-wracking, and she needed to do the team-captain-thing with a clear head. Instead of taking the elevator, she had elected to run up the side of the building. Such magic was pretty straightforward and one of the first things you were taught, after all. With a freshly purified soul gem and plenty of cubes, Emma could afford to—

—son of a bitch, it was raining again.

Emma forced back the urge to slam her forehead into the nearest wall. She would probably break something. Another trick they were taught was how to repulse water from them to stay dry. This was a bad plan if, say, you were trying to walk back to friendly lines after being MIA for an unspecified amount of time, but it was standard practice when cubes were plentiful.

With a shimmer of magic, Emma stepped out into the rain. An IFV rumbled by as she stepped back, splashing water up onto her. Emma frowned in annoyance as she shook further stray water off of her, then ran towards the wall. She jumped, pulling magic around her feet, and landed with a small splatting noise on the wall.

…Good, the water wasn't going to be a problem. Ayane had been briefly notorious for sliding off of a building in the sims because of heavy rain. Of course, there had been more than one girl who had done that, but Ayane was particularly ironic since she was a flyer.

In any case, Emma hitched her backpack more tightly on her and began running. Magical strength made this dramatically easier. Emma could feel herself start to grin as she accelerated, pushing her magic ahead of her to create a field without water and keep her vision clear. Getting out and about, finally, was immensely gratifying.

"Hey, friendly incoming," Emma broadcast over the LAN. "Don't shoot!"

"Roger that," said one of the magical girls dryly. "Wall running?"

"Yeah."

"Psh. Kids."

Emma rolled her eyes as she shot up the wall, bouncing from window sill to window sill slightly giddily. A bit of aeromaneuver even let her start doing barrel rolls and somersaults. She flew past a sniper post.

"Oh Goddess, really?" groaned the magical girl covering it. "C'mon kid, calm your shit."

"Screw you!" Emma called back, before throwing herself into a skid to chop speed. The lip of the roof came a moment later, and Emma planted a hand, then popped over top with a somersault and a picture perfect landing.

Unfortunately, Ryouta was too busy huddling under rain gear to notice. He appeared to be soaked, as were Vira and Motya.

"Well then, hello," said Emma dryly, standing up and examining the situation. As expected, everyone was soaked, gratuitously annoyed at her, and generally miserable in the midst of the point defense turrets installed atop the roof. "How is everyone?"

"Fantastic," said Vira with desert-like aridity to her voice. "Really great. Lovin' the weather."

Motya sniffed. Ryouta simply gave Emma a look of deepest loathing.

"So we have two magical girls here," said Emma, folding her arms. "Did neither of you think to use magic to stay dry?"

Vira and Motya blinked at her, before muttering curses and shimmering briefly with deep blue and red magic, respectively. Water jumped off of them, splattering Ryouta. Emma sighed. Right then.

"So what about me?" asked Ryouta. "I'm not magical."

"Motya?" asked Emma.

"Huh?" asked Motya. "What am I supposed to do?"

"Vodka."

Motya blinked at her.

"Your powers shouldn't be limited to only magical girls," said Emma. "Most support mages aren't, especially the musical mages. If you've got something in your repertoire that's potentially good for the cold and wet, Ryouta can have a drink and feel better."

Motya blinked again, then gasped and conjured a folio into her hands. It was made of black leather with stalks of wheat and barley, fruit, and a scattering of potatoes embossed in gold on the cover.

"Uh, I could try the time I distilled a towel?" asked Motya. "It didn't do anything that I could tell in the bunker, but maybe since it's raining?"

"Try it and see," said Emma.

Motya pulled the bottle out of the air and checked the label. Sure that it was the right one, she handed it to Ryouta.

"It's best to drink it all in one go," said Motya. "Your tox-filters should take care of things."

"Right then," said Ryouta, unable to restrain a dubious look at the bottle as he unscrewed the top. "Well… bottoms up I guess."

There was a tentative silence as everyone watched him drink, the bottle glugging as he swallowed as quickly as the burning, high proof beverage ran down his throat.

Ryouta shivered and made a face as he finished the bottle. "Ugh, how do people drink this stuff?"

"Hey, I just make the stuff," said Motya, giggling at his expression. "How do you feel?"

"Um… not that much different, honestly," said Ryouta. "Still wet. Is something supposed to happen?"

"I think so?" asked Motya, glancing at Emma. "Um, maybe wait a—."

Ryouta gasped as a flash of red magic rippled out of his stomach, flashing over his body and making the water on him disappear with almost violent haste.

"Ah, fuck, ow, ow, that stings!" Ryouta yelped, dancing in place briefly as the magic hovered over his skin, flickered, and then vanished. There was a brief moment of panic as Motya scrambled for more vodka, Vira rummaged through her pockets for some sort of medical supply, and Emma nearly collapsed laughing.

"Oi, this isn't funny!" Ryouta said indignantly as Emma summoned a halberd to lean against. Then he was mobbed.

"Here do you need—?" asked Vira.

"No, I'm fine, it doesn't hurt—."

"Take this, it should help—," said Motya, pressing a bottle of vodka into his hands.

"No really, it's just—."

"Oh, but maybe you should take this instead—?"

"No, no, he needs a hypo, your magic's just gonna make it worse!"

"No I can fix this, I just need to—."

"Alright, stop," said Emma, still somewhat breathless from laughter as she pulled Vira and Motya back. "It's good that you're both so conscientious, but calm down. He's fine, see?"

A moment of silence. Then Motya sighed in relief, patting at her chest.

"Jeez, I thought I'd done something wrong," she said. "You're really okay?"

"Yeah, I feel fine," said Ryouta, holding out an arm. "I'm dry too. The water's disappearing before it hits my arm."

"There's probably a limit," said Motya. She stored away the two random bottles and summoned a few more bottles of the towel-vodka. "Here, keep these in your knapsack and drink some every once in a while. It should keep you dry."

"Alright, thank you," said Ryouta. He tucked the bottles away into his knapsack.

Emma turned to Vira, who had retreated a ways and was watching quietly. "What were you planning on giving him?" she asked.

"Huh— oh, it was just a hypo of subopiorinate," said Vira, pulling the hypo out to show Emma. "I thought if he'd ingested something, then any effects would probably be systemic. His implants would manage any toxins, so it would be important to treat the symptoms incase it was magical and we needed to get a medic."

Emma nodded. "That's not bad thinking," she complimented. "Though you know, that's really only for uh, things like drone attack. It's a little bit overkill for this." More like completely overkill and possibly dangerous, but Vira didn't really need Emma to say that outloud.

Vira looked down at the hypo, rapidly paling as she considered the implications. "O-oh, right. Sorry, sir."

Emma rolled her eyes. Smart girl, but wow, that was formal. "Call me by my name. Or do the Japanese thing and call me 'senpai', I'm used to that. Now c'mon, I called this meeting so we could eat lunch, but I guess we should go a floor down for that. Wet food is annoying."

It was easier to go down stairs via the building's roof access, especially with Ryouta along. The top level of the building was some sort of gala space, suitable for entertaining large numbers of important guests for corporate events. It had since been converted into a massively powerful sensor room, with huge auxiliary power generators in case of a failure in the power lines.

"Goddess," said Ryouta, struck by the sheer magnitude of what he was seeing. "This is immense."

"Eh, it's about average," said Emma. She led the small group towards an alcove where a soldier could be seen smoking a cigarette and monitoring a readout. "There's one of these in just about every tower in the city. The only exceptions would be the ones that are too bombed out to be effective structure or cover." She turned to the soldier in the alcove. "Private, is this space being used?"

"Well let me check the music room—," the soldier began sarcastically, before realizing who he was talking too and snapping to attention and saluting. "I-I mean, no sir!"

"At ease," said Emma with a sigh, returning the salute. "As you were, Private, I was just being courteous."

"Right sir, of course," said the soldier, Private Reynolds. "Apologies, sir, for being disrespectful."

"Private, I'm fourteen," said Emma as she waved her group towards a table in the corner. "You can save the respect thing for when I turn forty, alright?"

"Er, right."

Emma nodded and left, exasperated. To some extent, she understood what was happening, but the cognitive dissonance was just too much for her. Having completed training, maybe she'd feel differently, but all this saluting and ten-hutting did not strike her as natural.

"Does that happen a lot?" asked Vira quietly.

"You get used to it," said Emma, sitting down. "In the bunker, mages get kind of segregated, but everyone gets mixed together more in combat. Just don't let it go to your head, 'kay?"

Vira and Motya nodded.

"Did you guys order lunch?" asked Emma, leaning against the table casually. Vira and Motya were sitting on opposite sides of Ryouta, who was looking slightly uncomfortable at the situation. Both girls were still tense, though it seemed that they'd managed to relax a bit since the briefing.

"Uh, we weren't sure what was going to happen, so we waited," said Vira. Motya seemed to have descended into a sort of awkward insecurity with the situation. "Should we get something from the canteen or..?"

"Nah, I've got some food packs," said Emma, pulling the packets out of her backpack. The teddy bear was still in there. Heh. She'd forgotten about it. "Here, take your pick."

Vira immediately pulled a packet of roast turkey towards her. Motya and Ryouta spent more time, unsure, before taking a packet of Seafood Paella and Turbot a L'anglaise, respectively. Emma glanced at Vira, who was giving the other two a look of deepest incredulity, before shifting sideways minutely.

Hmm.

"So tell me about yourselves," said Emma, selecting the sole packet of Beef Bourguignon in the pile. "Things you like, things you hate, stuff like that. Vira, you want to go first?"

Vira blinked. She had already begun systematically laying out her meal, sorting things in a practiced manner and beginning the heating process. "Er, well, alright. I guess um, I like football and being a magical girl. Um, I don't like uh… people who look down on me. Is that enough?"

"Any dreams for the future or something like that?" asked Emma.

"Um, not really?" said Vira. "I guess, I figure I'll make this a career, you know?"

Emma nodded. "I've kind of got similar plans. You want to do anything in particular?"

"MagOps is cool," said Vira, brightening. "One of them swung through for patrol duty once, she was awesome! Totally smooth, yanno?"

"Yeah, they're pretty wicked," said Emma. "Dangerous job though."

"Yah, well, can't be much worse than runnin' 'round the docks," said Vira, shrugging. "Lotsa equipment, yanno. Get ya crushed if yur not careful."

"Don't they have safety protocols for that though?" asked Motya. She and Ryouta had managed to figure out her packet quickly, but Vira and Emma were already starting to eat.

"Yah, like that actually matters," snorted Vira as she stirred her potatoes and turkey gravy into a slurry. "It's more productive to just hack 'em and make the equipment go faster. You gotta watch the lanes pretty carefully when yur movin' 'round the docks, in case a drone comes zippin' round the corner."

"Does anyone get hurt?" asked Ryouta, somewhat incredulous. "I mean, surely they don't go that quickly."

Vira gave both Ryouta and Motya a flat look.

"Seriously?"

Vira sighed and turned back to Emma. "Anyway, yeah, like I said, it can't be that bad. You gotta be quick on yur feet in the docks, but you can get a few cred for the shadier guys if yur good."

"Ahuh," said Emma, looking at Vira with a raised eyebrow. "So I guess you could say you're pretty good at this sort of thing."

"Oh yeah, it's not like the police are super anal if you show up to school enough," said Vira, shrugging. "Really, the police are there to make sure you don't fuck with the rich peeps too much, yanno?"

"That's terrible!" said Motya, completely horrified. "That's… that's so corrupt!"

"Yah, welcome to the real world, princess," said Vira dryly. She glanced at Ryouta, who looked troubled. "And-or prince, I guess."

Emma did her level best not to be too surprised by this. She'd had her introduction to the less-than-savory parts of Samsaran society earlier.

"So what about you, Motya?" asked Emma, shifting her attention as the heat cycle finished for Ryouta and Motya. "Same questions."

"Uh well, I um… I like wine?" said Motya awkwardly. "And uh, well, alcoholic beverages in general. Not to drink, I mean! But uh, my family is opening a vineyard, was opening a vineyard, and I guess I've taken after that."

Emma sent Vira a look to keep her from commenting. "I heard that your parents are working on genetically modified syrah?" asked Emma.

"Oh, yes, and cabernet sauvignon," said Motya. "Red wine is a little easier than white wine, for reasons I'm not entirely sure of, but the grapes seem to be taking to the soil better than the white wine varietals. We recently purchased a plot in the valley, but uh… well…"

Emma nodded. "Right, bit of a problem this. Any dislikes?"

"Poor wine," said Motya immediately, then blushed. "N-not to be, uh, too privileged or… uh… stuff."

Vira quietly snorted.

"But I guess, since my parents usually can get very good wine, it's always been irritating when someone does a poor job with the grapes they have," continued Motya. "If you're going to spend the time to make wine, you should try to do it well."

An admirable sentiment, if, judging by Vira's expression, one not universally accepted. "Any dreams for the future?"

"Well… I always wanted to help my parents with their work on the vines," said Motya, looking down and opening her packet. "I actually was on a bioengineering track before con— eurgh!"

Vira keeled over laughing as the immensely pungent smell of fish wafted from Motya's food pack. Emma rolled her eyes and took it all in stride as Ryouta looked askance at the food pack.

"Yes, so, one of the many lessons you will need to learn is that the seafood options are always extraordinarily pungent," said Emma dryly, spooning up a mouthful of beef. "Paella comes with chili sauce. It's recommended that you use all of it."

"So uh, what should I do about mine?" asked Ryouta, poking at his food packet. "Can I get a new one?"

"No," said Emma and Vira in unison. Emma gave the younger girl a quelling look. "No, Ryouta, you eat it, because you never, ever waste food. Just dump the chili sauce on top, it'll be fine."

Ryouta screwed up his face in distaste and cautiously opened his heated food pack. Someone had made the fortunate decision to douse the fish inside with butter, which mediated the smell somewhat. It still made him wince.

"You know, Turbot a L'anglaise, done properly, is supposed to be a very light dish," commented Ryouta. "I think in this case, it might have been better just to deep fry the thing."

"In any case," said Emma. "You were saying about your dreams, Motya?"

"Oh yes, I was going to say I was doing bioengineering before I contracted," said Motya, pouring the chili sauce into her paella. "The research group I was in was investigating resilience of European grape varietals to local microbial agents. The idea was to prevent crop loss due to malignant infection, while preserving interaction with the environment that would allow the grapes to develop a unique flavor for the region."

The group blinked collectively at her. It was all a bit over their heads, none of them having taken biology lessons past the secondary level. For that matter, Emma barely remembered primary level biology, having relied on Infopedia for most of her information during her stint in logistics.

"It's… trying to make wine grapes less sick all the time," sighed Motya. "Anyway, it wasn't an ambitious dream. My life was good as it was, and I had no desire to upset that balance."

"Why contract then?" asked Vira. Acid bled into her tone. "If yur life was so fine n' dandy—."

"Contrary to popular belief, Vira, while the residents of DownSouth are rather more privileged, we do not have less pride and loyalty to our city or our colony," said Motya, voice turning brittle from finely held indignation. "I have been… ignorant of the problems that plague Helsinberg, but I will not cede my home to invaders without fighting for it first."

Emma looked between the two magical girls. The princess and the pauper. "Play nice you two," she said. "Maybe if you hadn't contracted, things would be different, but we're all magical girls here. We all have demons to kill and cubes to burn."

Vira and Motya looked down at their food in pointed silence. Ryouta fidgeted uncomfortably.

"And, I think, we're all afraid," said Emma, more quietly. "There's a war going on, after all, and dying's no fun. We have to support each other, even if in the past, we would have gladly punched someone in the face."

Vira snickered at this.

"If you do need to let off some steam, we can arrange something, but you're not to start going at it," said Emma. Bickering team members always destroyed team success and she needed to nip this in the bud, now. "We need clear heads and good teamwork if we're going to succeed. Fighting between each other will open holes in our defense and get us all killed, by demon blast or worse. Is that understood?"

Vira and Motya didn't react for a moment, before nodding individually. Emma spotted them glancing warily at each other from the corners of their eyes.

Good enough for now then.

"Right, finish lunch, then we should get going. Ryouta, you'll follow us there from the subway?"

"Yes, I've got my pass arranged already," said Ryouta. "We'll just need to do some finalization on the drones I'll have accompanying you and do some software stuff before you go."

"Wait, we're not going by subway?" asked Motya. "How are we going to get to 7-South?"

Emma smiled and glanced at Vira, who was rapidly drawing the correct conclusion and clearly not happy about it.

"We," Emma said, "will be going by roof."

11. The Long Way 'Round

"This is gonna be annoyin', Saoyeh. Can't you make it stay farther away?"

"I told you to stop calling me that!"

Emma sighed as she double checked in combat gear. Vira and Motya relaxing about the situation had unleashed the cheeky brat in Vira. Neither Motya nor Ryouta was quite capable of keeping up with her wit. "Saoyeh" was a Chinese term for the son of a wealthy landowner or nobleman. While it did aptly describe Ryouta's position, it was also so hugely outdated that it could only be pejorative.

"Vira, have you finished double-checking your gear?" Emma asked as she pushed an arm guard into her backpack.

"Yah yah," said Vira, poking at the camera drone flitting around her head with a combination of fascination and annoyance. "Got my supplies and stuff packed away, my jumphook's working right, n'my backpack's got cubes and grenades and my PDDs stocked."

"Then stop screwing with Ryouta and wait by the cable jump," said Emma. She pulled her own jumphook onto arm and watched it attach and adjust itself over her costume.

The jumphook was one of those weird things that technically you could use magic for but was useful anyway. Getting from building to building in many colonies was problematic, since the prevalence of tubes in Mitakihara was really an Earth-thing. Going all the way to the bottom of a three hundred story building, possibly without power, then running a few blocks over to fight something was completely impractical, and the obvious solution had been to string cables between buildings for fast access between them. The jumphook snapped onto the polymer-alloy cable and used a wheel to accelerate the rider to potentially ludicrous speeds, snapping off automatically based on its programming or by manual toggle by the user. This way, soldiers and, by extension of the technology, supplies, could be sent between buildings quickly, if somewhat more vulnerably.

Magical girls, of course, could just jump or fly between buildings, but three hundred stories was still a massive fall that was really not all that preferable. In addition, the spacing between buildings was rarely even and narrow, which had potential for force a mage to use more magic than was strictly necessary in aeromaneuver. Running or sliding along the cables provided a better solution, and many girls preferred to do that. But, if you were trying to conserve magic, it was more economical to get a jumphook, the wristguards were adaptable, and use them to go between buildings.

It was also, in Emma's personal opinion, quite fun.

"Yah, yah," said Vira, rolling her eyes but heading off to sit on the wall by the cable jump.

Emma stifled the urge to whap her upside the head as she passed and spun up her jumphook experimentally. It whirred as expected, and she nodded before shouldering her backpack.

"How's the vision feed, Ryouta?" she asked.

"It's fine, you're all transmitting well," said Ryouta, eyes glazing slightly as he focused on the triptych of video arranged in his visual field. "The implant handshake was fine, but we'll have to wait to see how things go when I'm in the subway before we know that it's recording properly. Thanks for this, by the way. I know it's kind of a violation of privacy."

"Well we can turn it off, right?" asked Emma rhetorically. "Or our TacComps will cut the feed or something. It's a little creepy, but I think me and Vira will get used to it."

Motya shivered as she spun her jumphook, then pulled on her own backpack. "You two are so weird. I'm sorry if this sounds forward, but that software really is creepy, Ryouta."

"Yes, I know," said Ryouta. "It's just so very useful to me that I have to ask at least."

"I understand, just…" Motya trailed off, shivering again.

"Well Governance is always watching, you know," said Emma.

"That's different, somehow."

Emma shrugged. It was what it was. "Anyway, we need to get going. We'll see you later Ryouta?"

"I'm just going to take some photos before I go."

"Alright. C'mon Motya."

Emma and Motya walked over to the cable jump, Ryouta following behind with his camera.

"A'ight, we headin' out?" asked Vira, rocking to her feet.

"Yep," said Emma. She put a foot on the side of the building and turned to face Vira and Motya. "Before we head out, a few last things. Our path will pass through a stretch of an overland demon patrol route, and if we're lucky we'll get a chance to stretch our legs. Keep an eye out for anything suspicious too. You never know if you'll be the first contact for a squid incursion. Don't get lost and don't do stupid tricks that get you killed. We ready to go?"

Vira and Motya nodded. The former rolled her eyes at the short speech. The latter nudged her with an elbow, which drew a "tch" and an elbow back.

Emma fought the urge to roll her eyes as well, and stepped onto the cable. "Let's go then."

One step two steps three steps then Emma reached down, latched her jumphook onto the cable, and let it pull her forward. The magic she'd used to keep herself dry proved itself useful, scattering rain in front of her as Emma zipped across the avenue and landed in a skid on the opposing platform. A platoon seemed to be eating lunch as Emma flashed through, then snapped her jumphook onto the next cable.

Behind her, she heard Vira whoop and Motya stifle a shriek as they flew down the cable, landing with what sounded like a small tumble, then clacking on to the cable behind her. This particular cable spanned a large roundabout, which had been converted into an anti-air position.

"Wow, that's a big laser," said Vira appreciatively. The two meter wide emitting lens, fixed into a six meter long focusing element and attached to what looked like a three bedroom Earth-apartment, spanned the entire roundabout. It left just enough room for vehicles to pass around the edge. "What's that for, bombers?"

"Yeah, or large enemy ordinance," said Emma. "Things've been quiet this far back, since this isn't a bombing priority. Normally we'd have to go around."

"Why not put it farther forward?" asked Motya. "It seems like it would be more useful near the front."

"Sure, but you keep some in the back for security," said Emma. She swung herself upwards, rolling on top of the cable before detaching from it. She spun once and then, facing forwards, bounded across the slick rooftop and clipped onto the next cable. "That way if you do see some bombers coming in, you can take care of it. They're also pretty static, AA Lasers, so they're vulnerable to getting hit with counterfire."

The cable swung upwards, beginning to see the cable divide and split off towards other buildings. Emma's jumphook automatically avoided the branches, clicking off and back on with a small burst of speed to maintain momentum. The building they were headed to was quite tall, among the larger buildings in Helsinberg.

"Take a look to our left," said Emma. She nudged her charges mentally, pointing out the view. "You can see the front from here."

A large section of southeast Helsinberg spread out beneath them as the jumphooks tugged them higher into the atmosphere. Emma felt a wave of apprehension sweep her as she watched the absurdly quiet front. "Surprisingly static" didn't even begin to describe what she was looking at. The only time Emma had seen lines that still and cleanly defined had been in the historical background of her cortical dump's Strategy and Tactics section.

The buildings behind the line were densely packed and rippled with activity. Long streams of delivery drones moved materiel up to the front, resupplying and stockpiling for whatever was inevitably going to happen. Armor was taking up defensive positions, and trucks were dropping off reinforcements, who quickly made their way into the wreckage for cover and further orders. Even shattered husks and smoking craters had soldiers in them, visual implants showing them conducting maintenance or taking time for lunch. In fact, from this high up, Emma could just make out the squid forces doing the same.

"So much is gone," said Vira hollowly. "I… there was a bar over there where a friend used to work."

Emma looked back to see Motya begin to twist around, then think better of it. She looked up at Emma, frowning sadly, then looked back at the city. Well, that was probably for the best, unfortunately. Vira's resentment of the Helsinberg upperclass would probably make Motya's attempt to console her backfire.

"What was the name of the bar?" asked Emma. "What was it like?"

"It was called 'Baracca's'," said Vira. "They were a pub, really, and did a lotta good food. There was this one thin' they did, with bacon and apples. Fuckin' amazin' that. It's a bit far for me usually, but sometimes I'd get a stretch where nobody's got any work for ya and homework's all sent off for gradin', so I'd walk or take the bus over and hang out for a few hours, maybe make some cash washin' dishes or waitin' tables. It was a cool place. Wish I'd gone there more often."

"Why not move, get a job there with your friend? Your file says you lived in the streets anyway."

"Nah, senpai, even us street rats get attached to a place, yanno?" said Vira, laughing sadly. "Even if its shit, ya don't just leave the borough ya come from. Or at least, I don't."

"Really? Never?"

"Well, maybe if I had kids or somethin', I guess," said Vira. "But I'm, well, I was, twelve. No reason to leave. I wanna make sure Helsinberg makes it through this ok, yanno? I just wish Baracca's had made it too."

"You know, Governance usually dumps a lot of cash into rebuilding," said Emma. "After this is over and we've taken Helsinberg back, the owners can probably get it rebuilt."

"Yah? That'd be great," said Vira. She sounded a little more hopeful. "Still though—" Emma winced as her mental voice fell again "—it's all just so… blown to shit…"

"Hey well, we exist for a reason," said Emma. "Magical girls gonna magic away the squid, right?"

It was an absolutely terrible line. Completely naive, the line wasn't even sentimental. Hell, Emma was pretty sure she'd seen it in an anime back when she was seven. Still somehow, it cheered Vira and Motya up.

"Pfft, that was awful, senpai," said Vira.

"I must agree," said Motya, "that was utter tripe, Emma."

"Hey, made you laugh," said Emma, grinning as their jumphooks neared the end of the long climb. "Seriously though, cheer up you two. We're all young yet. Let the older girls do the moping around, yeah?"

"Psh. Yeah, 'kay then, senpai."

"Understood, Emma."

The rest of the ride up the tower was quiet, each lost in their thoughts. Emma detached from the cable and brought herself to a stop. The floor they had reached was largely empty. The building was tall enough that it was both far too obvious for a sniper hide and not as useful as a drone or satellite for surveillance. What it was excellent for, however, was communication, and several barrier generators, supplemented by heavy armor plating, kept the building from being blasted away. Several technicians saluted as Emma arrived, with Vira and Motya landing behind her a moment later.

"Apart from the destruction, what did you notice about the front?" asked Emma as they walked towards the opposite end.

"…it seemed awfully still," said Motya after a moment. "I thought that the front was more fluid than that?"

"Usually yeah," said Emma, nodding. "Vira?"

"There's no fightin' either," said Vira. She paused, then wrinkled her brow. "Actually, wait, what d'hell? Shouldn't there be explosions and shit going on?"

Emma nodded. "Thoughts on why none of that is happening?"

The two rookies went silent as they considered this.

"…The squid must be fucked up somehow," said Vira. "Cause like, if we'd been unable to respond, the squid woulda picked up on it and attacked already. The only reason they wouldn't do that is if there's something wrong with them."

"The only way that would work would be if they were experience mass maintenance failure or if they had logistical difficulties," continued Motya.

"That's right," said Emma. She paused at the next cable jump, turning to face her charges. "Don't spread this around, but I've got some friends who are doing missions investigating squid logistics. It sounds like things are going to get rough, so be prepared."

"Do you… think we'll need to fight?" asked Motya. She spun her jumphook restlessly.

"Hopefully not," said Emma. "If there is more fighting, we might be asked to do supply escort or participate in a skirmish or two. But keep it in mind, okay?"

"Right, yeah."

"I understand."

"Anyway, let's continue." Emma turned around and attached her jumphook to the cable, letting it pull her off the landing down towards the next building. They could still see the front from here, moving closer as they flew down the line.

"Start keeping an eye out as we get closer," said Emma. "We should be far enough back not to be worth the battery charge on a squid's sniper rifle, but paranoia is good."

A frisson of nervousness passed over the rookies. Emma hoped she'd made the right decision to pass near the lines. Her hope had been to give them a taste of what being this close to the front was like, but the possibility of getting shot at suddenly seemed much greater than she knew it probably was. What-ifs plagued her, but Emma quickly brushed it aside. That would have to be taken one step at a time.

"Hey guys, can you hear me?"

"Oh hey, its Saoyeh," said Vira. "What's up Saoyeh?"

"Oi, stop calling me that!"

Vira cackled as the group continued towards the top of a building.

"Hey Ryouta," said Emma, rolling her eyes. "What're you up to?"

"Ah, well, I was just calling to let you guys know that the connection is good and I've got a lot of good images," said Ryouta. "That time you all were swinging up that tower was excellent.'

"Hah, good to hear," said Emma. "Did the vision feeds stream well?"

"Yeah, it's all good," said Ryouta, sounding excited. "Man these are some epic action shots! You know a few hundred years ago, this would have been completely impossible, just 'cause we'd have nowhere to put the data."

Emma went to reply, then felt a distinctive magical ripple in the distance. A glance at the map showed that yes, they'd already entered the part of the route that would pass along a demon patrol route.

"Well that's good, because I think we're going to get you some better stuff soon," said Emma. "Vira, Motya, you felt that?"

"Yah, demons at… two o'clock, static but growin' miasma," said Vira.

"Judging by rate of growth, it's not going to be too large," added Motya.

"Sorry Ryouta, going to have to cut this short."

"Nah, whatever. Talk to you later."

Emma pushed her consciousness outwards as they approached the next building. "Anybody out there on patrol?"

"Yeah, you're headed to the miasma?" asked the patrol leader. "Who are you?"

"My name's Emma, I'm leading two greenies on their first overland," said Emma on public telepathy, waving at Vira and Motya to stop and wait. "I'd like permission to engage, see how they do."

The patrol leader considered. "My name's Yulin. I'll clear you for limited action, but hold off on things until we get there. Don't get them too deep, Emma."

Emma nodded mentally. "Understood, I'll take them in but wait for your arrival."

"Roger that, godspeed."

"You two were listening?" asked Emma, turning to Vira and Motya.

The two girls nodded, looking somewhat nervous. Vira had already summoned her rifle. "Will it be just the three of us?" asked Motya.

"Yes," said Emma. She locked her jumphook onto the next cable and began swinging towards the miasma. "We'll be fine, just don't get overenthusiastic."

"Right, of course."

"Yah yah, got it."

The miasma's signature grew as they approached it. Emma could feel the patrol nearing as well. Unfortunately, Motya wasn't suited very much to Emma's typical engagement pattern. Vira, too, would probably be more comfortable kiting the edges of the miasma than doing the sort of smash-and-blast thing Emma was beginning to turn into her "thing".

"What are you two used to doing on patrol?" asked Emma.

"Sniper support."

"Healing and buffing."

Emma sighed. "Sounds about right then. We'll approach this as if we're the only three girls available. Motya, medical support as needed but take the time to experiment with your vodka, see if you can come up with some weird drink combos. Vira, we'll do an overview sweep before planning further. Keep nearby and keep moving. We ready?"

"Yes."

"Let's do this."

The buildings were in the way of their line of sight on the miasma. The three of them accelerated, Motya dropping off to the side to observe while Vira trailed behind Emma by several meters. They were running and sliding across the roofs now, jumphooks abandoned for the greater expediency of aeromaneuver. Onto a cable, skidding with inhuman balance, before bouncing off the end with a twirl to keep upright, then two steps and they were right on top of the miasma.

The miasma was small, taking up only a half dozen blocks and centered around a stalled stack of three trucks with soldiers inside. The front vehicle had somehow lost a wheel, an improbable proposition, but on second thought it was looking rather damaged, so perhaps it had been part of the retreat. A frustrated argument seemed about to break out, and the demons could be seen advancing on the convoy, mouths gaping as they began to draw on the emotions.

"Assessment?" asked Emma shortly as she and Vira ping-ponged between the buildings bracketing the street.

"Too many friendlies," said Vira. "AOE and barrage are out. We need a teleporter."

"We don't have one, other ideas."

"Uh, distraction? You're AOE, so you draw 'em away and I'll pick 'em off?"

Goddess, even the newbies turned her into bait. "Ugh, fine, but you're the bait next time," Emma sighed, before doing an immelman and reversing direction. "Ready?"

"Ready."

"Motya, watch our backs," said Emma, gathering magic around her. "In three—."

The cli-clack of a bolt cycling could be heard as Vira readied her rifle.

"—two—"

The soldiers could tell something was wrong now, but began to sag lethargically, slumping against their vehicles. A garbled message tried to make its way out of the steadily thickening miasma.

"—one, NOW."

A flash of blue and Emma was streaking forward on jet propulsion, a shimmering shield braced against her arms as she became a teenaged cannonball. She clipped two demons, then punched through two more before the last one dodged. Emma pivoted, flared, and brought herself to a halt with halberd in hand. She had time to give it a twirl, snap it to guard, and plant her feet into a loose fighting stance.

"Come and get me, assholes!" she shouted, grinning at the exertion. Goddess, it was good to be fighting again.

Moments later, the tall, gape-mouthed manifestations of human despair regrouped and came at her, laser beams leading the way as they closed to maximize firepower. Vira was still out of the miasma, still hadn't fired, and Emma was a bright ball of magical girl standing right—

—there, ricocheting off of a building to come sweeping in from the flank, halberd cutting into demon but of course not actually killing anything. This miasma was seriously tiny, if that was all these demons could muster.

Then Emma's senses flared and she was rocketing upwards and aeromaneuvering to cling to the side of a building with magic, before spinning away, more lasers tracking her from the sudden demon spawn. There had been a time when a single magical girl was all that would be available for this miasma, dancing away like Emma and hoping for an opening, waiting for the demons to overstretch or maybe just a small victory this time but—

—CRACK went Vira's rifle and suddenly the demons were reduced by three. They flinched collectively and rapidly shifted, some turning towards the sniper that had already reloaded and fired with a second CRACK that tore through another set, four this time, and Emma could see them charge lasers but-

-a vortex sphere appeared shrieking its fury. Emma immediately kicked it into the nearest group of demons. It burst with a satisfying violence that made Emma grin and the demons flinch and try to reorganize again. She paused, then ducked a laser, and scanned back towards the trucks as a CRACK felled a third set of demons.

Damn. A handful had spawned and were busy sucking the life out of the soldiers. This would eventually kill the humans, but of more immediate concern was the miasma strengthening again as the negative emotional energy flowed in. Emma ran up onto a building and then sideways, dodging more lasers while Vira fired thrice more.

Emma jumped, whistling through the air, and then landed with a thunk on top of a truck.

Hack, chop, slash, twirl and thrust, and now a sarissa because that one was a bit far and then Emma was off again, drawing the inevitable fire towards her so it wouldn't burn the humans below. She checked her gem as she ran, expecting it to be darker than she'd have liked, and was slightly surprised at how clear it was. Who knew that being in battle was good for her?

"Ah, Emma, I distilled armor plating once," broke in Motya as the demons tried to rally, forming a rudimentary line. "It should help your damage resistance. Do you want a bottle?"

"Yeah, that'd be—," flip to dodge and then hurl the halberd yes impact "—useful. Throw it at me."

"Right, here!"

Emma paused, waiting for demons to engage her, and then jumped up and to the side. The bottle smacked into her glove and she pushed off the air to fly upwards, landing high on the side of a building before running up it, lasers chasing her heels.

"Vira, your gem?"

"Uh, doin' alright," said Vira. Emma looked around, then pinpointed the blue wetsuit against the light gray sky. Her gem output seemed fine. Vira dropped down, rolled under a laser, and popped upright. She fired twice, punching through another brace of demons, then ducked behind the parapet just before a trio of lasers crossed over her position.

"Keep changing positions," Emma advised, flipping over the top of the building for cover and immediately chugging the bottle of vodka. The alcohol's burn and flavor profile made it not unlike trying to swallow a piece of metal, yet strangely fortifying. A ripple of red magic spread across her, then faded. Emma looked back up over the side of the building and threw the bottle into a demon, knocking it back. She looked back at Vira—

—who hadn't moved, dammit. "Vira!" Emma shouted. "You need to change your position!"

"Ah, what— shit!"

Emma bit back her own curse as Vira was forced to displace by a demon spawning almost literally on top of her. Magical instincts saved the riflegirl as she threw herself over the side of the building, a laser scalding her position, and then pushed herself back against the building with aeromaneuver.

But this was not a good position. Vira wasn't in any way designed to take on a battery of demons on her own from in close.

"Motya—."

"Readying bottles now."

"Good, hopefully we won't need them," said Emma as she pushed herself off the wall and back into the street. The demons were regrouping around the convoy, drawing off energy for further attempts on the lives of the mages attacking them. Four broke off and bracketed Vira. The young mage scrambled down the face of the building, trying desperately to get out of the line of fire. She jumped-

-and bit back a scream as lasers scorched the air, two burning past her and two cutting searing trenchs into her arm and shoulder. Vira wavered in the air, trajectory wobbling towards an uncontrolled tumble, but then:

"Vira, up top!"

Vira twisted, pulling herself hard against the wall as Emma slashed through the air. Lasers splashed against Emma's shoulder and chest, but did little to nothing between Emma's armor and Motya's vodka. Vira dived, hitting the ground hard and rolling while Emma pushed with her magic, blasting herself down in front of her kouhai. A wave of magic rushed out in a rolling arc of blue, manifesting into a gust of wind that made the demons recoil, and-

-the rifle cracked again, the sound of Vira rapidly cycling the bolt with inhuman speed blending with the hypersonic bang of projectile streaking past in a mad cacophony of gunfire arcing up into the top of the miasma.

"Yulin, what's your ETA?" Emma asked, waving at Vira to begin retreating. They needed to regroup and come at this again—

"Five seconds."

"Wait what?"

And then a teleporter blinked into place over the convoy, along with a barrier generator and a girl with a machine-gun who let rip, Emma and Vira going to the ground as lime-green magic bolts thundered in an arc through the air. A second later, she bubble disappeared, along with the soldiers of one of the trucks. The process repeated itself twice more as more mages began coming in, a round dozen that quickly began to decimate the demons within the miasma.

"Right, let's withdraw," said Emma. She turned and ran up the side of a building, arcing up and away from the fighting towards Motya's position. "You okay there, Vira?"

"Nngh, yah, I'm fine," said Vira. "Just wish I coulda done better."

Emma glanced back at Vira. The two trenches of burned flesh were slowly closing, but her gem readout was dipping downwards.

"Well don't worry too much, just learn from it," said Emma. She vaulted over the parapet and landed near Motya's position. "We had backup, after all."

"Mnnhg," grunted Vira, unhappy.

The two of them vaulted the parapet a moment later, landing beside Motya who quickly pressed an open bottle of vodka into Vira's hands.

"Drink it slowly, you might not need the entire thing," said Motya, fiddling with a second bottle. Emma recognized it as having the same label as the damage resistance one she'd had earlier.

"You kiddin' me?" asked Vira, hefting the liter of vodka while rolling her eyes. "Siaojyeh, it's an entire fuckin' liter."

Motya laughed slightly. "Well, I guess I overdid it a bit."

"A bit?" asked Vira, before slugging back several swallows. "Fwah. This is a bit?"

"Heh, well, I was worried. Come on, drink up!"

They quieted, watching the choreographed destruction beneath them. Vira drank the vodka slowly while Motya monitored her condition. Below, Yulin coordinated the attack with ease, the harassed and weakened demons falling swiftly under the firepower of a dozen mages. A few stray bits of magic and laser fire spiraled upwards, colliding with the small, and shrinking, miasma and vanishing without a trace.

"Ah, man, the vid feeds cut out," said Ryouta, popping back onto the line. "I was hoping to get some shots of you guys fighting demons, but the miasma interfered."

"Yeah, of course," said Emma. "It's never worked."

"No, no, I meant from the drones," said Ryouta. "You know, photographs of you guys blowing stuff up? But it just looks like a bunch of guys standing around."

"Ah, that's too bad," said Emma. "Did you get any good images from Vira?"

"Actually yes, but then the miasma expanded." A few images scrolled past on a sidebar, of Vira and Emma ping-ponging and Vira taking up a shooting position. Vira firing, cycling her bolt with a flash of magic, displacing, etc., but all from the first minute or so of combat. "Not as fruitful as I'd have liked, but I got something out of it at least."

"Hehe, I look pretty good in these," said Vira, examining the images closely. "Oooh, the wind even did a thing in this one! Cool!"

"I'm glad you like them!"

"You're not half bad at this, Saoyeh," complimented Vira. "I see why they hired you."

"Don't call me that, but thanks," said Ryouta, sounding exasperated.

"Emma, we're wrapping up here," said Yulin, distracting Emma from the conversation. "How're you guys on cubes?"

Emma glanced over their gem charges. They hovered steadily at around 80%. "We could use some cubes if you can spare some, but save it for the quota if not."

"In that case we're done here," said Yulin. "Small miasma, not much yield. Good work, but I'm afraid that we can't spare any for your trouble."

"It should be fine, thanks."

"Bye then."

"Right, we should move on," said Emma, turning back to the conversation. "Vira, Motya?"

"Ready to go, Emma."

"Yah, same here, senpai."

"Then let's head out."

12. Under High Waters

The building that 7-South was built underneath had been a community housing project before the war. As was typical with these sorts of things, it was built with exactly one type of room and as cheaply as could be managed, which naturally did not lend towards longevity. The invasion had been strangely fortuitous for this particular building. If buildings could speak, it would certainly be saying prayers of thanks for the sudden onset of extra reinforcing bars, ablative heat shielding, and other things designed to keep it from collapsing underneath a Reaper's heavy laser cannon.

Chunli Fang, a mage hailing from Optatum, could regularly be seen apparently having conversations with the building (its name was Sasha). She also provided direct assistance turning the structure into, arguably, one of the most heavily shielded buildings along the southern front. The blockiness of the structure helped, allowing for many different options for shielding and firing angles and the like.

When Team Four arrived at Sasha-the-Project-Housing-Complex, Chunli was having a slightly confused conversation about the philosophical implications of buildings having a soul.

"So you're saying that the reason you were built makes you special?" asked Chunli, apparently not noticing as Emma, Vira, and Motya popped off of the cable and landed a dozen feet away. "…But doesn't that mean you— oh I see. Okay… Wait, what? How would that even work? I mean, I don't mean to be derogatory— oh, thank you, good, I was a little worried. But you see, you don't have legs, so—."

Vira and Motya looked at her, then at Emma. Emma shrugged, focusing on the orders propagating in upon their arrival.

"Sure, go ahead, take a breather," said Vira sarcastically as she blinked and read through the orders as well.

"Things must be worse than we thought," said Motya. "I don't think we'd normally go right into patrol, would we?"

"No, this sounds about right," said Emma tiredly. She pulled a brace of grief cubes from her backpack and purified her gem. "Mnrgh. Well come on. It looks like Chunli's part of our patrol. We should go say hello."

"Is she…?"

"She's fine. She just needs a break from things."

Well hopefully. Chunli was normally a Captain in the 7th Combat Logistics Division - 2nd Army Group, but was currently assigned to the DVU of 7-South for "decompression".

"Ah, hello!" said Chunli, finally noticing them. "Sorry, I was distracted talking to Sasha."

"Hello," said Emma, waving. She poked Vira and Motya telepathically, prompting them to give their own awkward greetings. "So you're part of the DVU? I think we're in the same patrol."

"Oh yeah, the commander mentioned we'd have some new girls," said Chunli, swishing her skirt idly as she spoke. "Hmm… Well anyway, come on, I'll introduce you. Sasha, if you would?"

There was no response from the building that Team 4 could discern. As it was, Chunli seemed to hear something, because she curtsied with a thank you, then gestured grandly at the roof access.

"Come along, girls," she said, before keying the door. Absurdly, it opened directly to the bunker's staging area, where a massive amount of activity could be seen.

"Wha— how did you—?" asked Vira.

"My magic allows me to ask buildings to do certain things for me," said Chunli, stepping through the door and gesturing at Team 4 to follow. "Open portals between doors and windows, specifically. Usually I can't make it more than a few hundred meters, but me n' Sasha have a special arrangement, since I've been here so long and been so helpful!"

Well it wasn't the strangest power Emma had ever heard of, if somewhat under-powered sounding. There was a rumor that one of the girls in one of the previous training cohorts had literally no powers when she contracted. Shiri Asuka or something. It was probably apocryphal, but compared to that, magically talking buildings and door-portals were pretty much normal.

"Well uh, thanks for that then," said Emma as Team 4 stepped through. "Saved us an elevator trip, at least."

"Don't thank me, silly, thank Sasha!" said Chunli. She patted the wall beside the door. "She works very hard, you know. Or did, before the military spruced things up."

"Er, right, thank you Sasha," said Emma, feeling very strange patting a wall like it was a particularly cute child. She felt a tingle of magic spark off the wall as she pulled her hand away. Vira and Motya glanced at each other and followed suit a moment later.

"Anyway, so, the DVU Commander?" asked Emma as the door closed behind them.

"Over here," said Chunli. She led the small group through a gate, with the words "SECTOR FOUR" in large boldface across the top, and to the nearest canteen.

The canteen served as the distribution point for food and water, the former via food packs and the latter via fountains. A wide, open space with picnic tables, this particular canteen was lit with street lamps styled after a mashup of Victorian England and Qing Dynasty Chinese aesthetics. The lamps had conveniently smooth tops as well, making for excellent seats or acrobatic points for the various magical girls lounging about, waiting for the patrol to begin.

"Ah, these are the newest girls then?" asked one of them, perched on top of a lamp. Her long, dark hair was pulled back into a ponytail, draped over a gold epaulette on top of a crimson jacket. The costume reminded Emma of Tracy's. Both had the odd pocketless trousers that were buttoned very high up on the torso, but the girl— Nadya Antipova, a telekinetic —had a single, highly elaborate epaulette instead of the two subdued ones that Tracy wore. Nadya also lacked a hat, and had black leather gloves and boots that went up to her knees. "Have a seat. We'll talk about your roles in a bit while the rest of the patrol shows up."

"Right," said Emma. She glanced around the canteen, then led her team to a table in the corner and sat down.

"There's more comin', right?" asked Vira, looking around uncertainly. Including Team 4, there were only twelve girls in the canteen. "I mean, it's not just ten of us goin' on patrol, right? They didn't do that back in 1-East."

"No, there's fourteen girls scheduled for this patrol," said Emma, looking at the roster. "They have less for surface patrol, since people are more spread out and miasmas are smaller. Things are still weird though."

"Why?" asked Motya. "You said earlier that things sounded about right to you."

Emma nodded. "Well, yes, but you saw Nadya's unit on the nomenclator?"

Vira and Motya nodded. "She's from MagOps Team 19," said Motya. "Team commander, in fact."

"There's two reasons why you might have a MagOps team leader doing DVU duty," said Emma. "The first is that she's cracked and is doing light duty before going back in."

The three of them looked at Nadya, who was concentrating deeply on something, moving things around with her eyes on her retinal interface.

"Which is obviously not true," continued Emma. "So the other reason is that her team isn't useful right now."

"Well the only reason that MagOps wouldn't be useful is if their specialty is no good," said Vira. "That's how MagOps works, right? They specialize into teams for specific applications?"

"Yeah," said Emma. She tapped a finger grimly against the table. "It's really odd. I can't think of a specialty that wouldn't be useful right now, since we need to break the stalemate."

The possibilities were endless. Vira and Motya looked at each other as Emma trailed off into silence. Looking into things, Team 19 —they'd named themselves "H.E.E." in typical MagOps Fashion— seemed to be a classic rapid insertion and destruction team, their powers organized around massively destroying whatever they were thrown at. The entire team was there, conversing amongst themselves while they waited for the patrol to start. It was honestly a waste of their talents to be here and not off doing something or another on the front.

There wasn't anymore time to contemplate it though. Vira flinched as Nadya landed next to her, almost soundless. A squirt of magic flickered from underneath her feet, fading so quickly that Emma wasn't entirely sure she'd actually felt it.

"Alright, PCT4, welcome again to Bunker 7-South," said Nadya. A map of the bunker appeared on their shared vision, zooming into Sector Four and the patrol route they would be taking. "I'm sure you've all looked into my team by now, so I'll forego the introductions. Today's plan is to split into three teams. It's a little counter-intuitive, but it should work for the sake of everyone's varying experience levels."

Nadya gestured at the map, which zoomed into a portion of the patrol. Three blue triangles appeared, one on top of the route, and two bracketing it.

"MagOps Team 19 will form Strike 1, while PCT4 and the others will be Scout 1 and Scout 2. Scout 1 will advance on the left flank, while Scout 2 does the same on the right. Your job is to engage any miasmas you encounter, then move on as soon as things get too rough. That should weaken the miasma enough for us to move in and destroy it completely. If you get in a bad spot, send a shout our way and we'll come help out. Is everyone clear?"

Team 4 glanced amongst themselves. It wasn't exactly complicated, this plan, but…

"I take it there's no questions then," said Nadya. She clapped once and gestured for them to stand up. "Come on then, we should get going now that everyone's here."

"Oh, wait, um, we've got a journalist along," said Emma. "Ryouta Shizuki. Will that be a problem?"

"Not unless he's going to try and tag along," said Nadya. She nodded at the drones that had followed Team 4 into the basement. "He can do his job well enough with those."

Emma nodded. "Alright. In that case let's get started."

"Good." Nadya turned and broadcast across telepathy: "Patrol! Form up!"

"She's… intense," said Motya as Team 4 formed a basic triangle formation, with Emma leading. They jumped up onto the residence blocks, spreading out widely across the bunker. Each block was four stories tall and housed exactly four people, with ladders to get to the upper floors.

"You'll have to get used to it," said Emma. "A lot of the older girls are like that."

"Not you, senpai," said Vira.

Emma smiled. "Thanks. I try not to be."

The people below watched them speed by, Nadya starting the patrol out slow to get a feel of how they'd all respond to commands. Many of the adults from the city were sitting on the sills of their residence cubes, pausing conversation to watch the patrol with expressions that held conflicting emotions. Small bundles of children stood in awe as the idols they admired, and, for many, aspired to be, flashed past in a brilliant streak of colors.

"Scout 1, spread left twenty meters and accelerate your pace," ordered Nadya. "Scout 2, mirror Scout 1."

"Roger that," said Emma. She gestured mentally at Vira and Motya, then sped up. The ceiling was just another forty feet above them, not terribly high by magical girl standards and something that they needed to keep watching for to avoid smacking into. Briefly, Emma considered bouncing between it and the rooftops, but dismissed it as unnecessarily wasteful.

The first quarter of a kilometer was quiet. Then, as they neared the first defensive wall, Vira flagged a miasma to Team 4's left.

"It feels big," she said. Tension resonated in her telepathy. "I think we're lucky, and it's just started, but it's already really big."

"Right, Motya, we're going to need that armor vodka you have," said Emma. The team veered left as she spoke. "Get some health vodka ready too."

"On it, Emma."

"Nadya, this is Emma, we've detected a miasma and are moving to engage," said Emma.

"Understood, keep us updated," said Nadya. "Scout 2 is engaging to the east, and we will be moving to sweep things there. Kite a bit, yeah?"

Emma glanced in the direction of Vira. "…I'll do my best. Out."

Vira and Emma broke off to the right, sweeping around in a short arc to intercept Motya. Two bottle of vodka slapped against their palms as they turned back, popping the tops off and drinking quickly while thanking the vintner's daughter telepathically.

"The last time I had this, I tanked a lot of damage," said Emma as they closed, the miasma looming up and centered around a large argument in the center with security trying to quiet the situation. "I'm betting it works different for each girl though, so be careful."

"Right, I understand," said Vira. The two of them swung right, orbiting the beginnings of the miasma, flecks of shadow gathering in the air and vague mirages flickering in and out of sight. "So uh, what's the plan for this? There's a lot of civilians."

"Nadya suggested we kite until they can show up to help," said Emma. "With just the two of us, that's probably a good plan. I'll try and draw them away, you fire at anything that you have a clean shot on."

Vira frowned but nodded. "What if the demons start getting intense?"

"We'll cross that bridge when we get to it," said Emma. She summoned a halberd. "You ready?"

"Yeah."

Emma bolted left, accelerating with a flash of magic into the protomiasma. Like disturbing a nest of biting insects, the mirages snapped into place and turned, lasers rippling through the air to singe the tails of Emma's costume. Below, mundane eyes saw nothing but a thick mist obscuring all but the closest objects as the ground turned to sand. Their panic was immediate.

Emma winged outwards, halberd flashing through the air to carve into a demon's head, before spinning up and away, bouncing off the ceiling and drawing a small group of demons with her. Vira flicked past as Emma landed, the riflegirl pausing and sending a volley into the cluster that had followed Emma and turning them into so many grief cubes.

The majority, however, immediately stopped pursuit and turned back towards their victims. The air seemed to vibrate as, one by one, humans stumbled to a halt and sank to their knees, or clutched at walls, or simply curled into a ball on the ground as despair and lethargy set in.

With their prey subdued, the demons began to feed. Dark lines slid out of their mouths, latching onto the chests of their targets. As each mundane heart beat in its chest, the attached thread twitched and shivered with pulsating undulations, calling to mind Cthuloid monstrosities, but rendered stark and white, and just as foul and sickening to the heart and the mind.

The miasma expanded rapidly. Emma had just a moment to breathe before lasers ripped through where she was standing, sending her spinning into the ceiling before pivoting and launching forward, dodging with aeromaneuver then twisting to take a hit directly in the chest, but getting an opportunity to cleave a demon straight down the center. The dark threads bubbled and died, burning away as the humans toppled over unconscious. She turned to leap upwards and—

—aeromaneuvered herself straight into the ground as a quintet of lasers ripped through the air at head level, then burned into her back before she could get her legs under her. Emma braced a shield against the attack, then retreated, bouncing off of the walls erratically to throw off the demons' aim.

"Nadya, we're getting buried here!" Emma called out. "The miasma's too much! The demons are barely even paying attention!"

"Roger that, teleporter inbound," said Nadya. "Mina, Gracia, Eva, go."

A second of silence, then a blossom of light and the concussive crackle of magic spitting against the boundaries of reality, shattering and scattering demons as Eva Guderian's whip cracked against a wall, blasting the suddenly empty space and then again, there, to the right, and again across the way. Flash flash flash, with pockets of humans disappearing and reappearing outside of the miasma, and in the distance now Emma saw soldiers responding and securing the civilians. Movement to her left—!

Emma planted a foot and dropped, a demon's laser leaving a track of heat down her back before a CRACK and the demon scattered into cubes, Vira landing beside her breathing hard.

"Holy shit," she gasped. "This is insane."

"Drink some vodka and let's go," said Emma, projecting the message across to everyone in the area. "Scout 1 is pulling out for next miasma."

"Acknowledged Scout 1," said Nadya with slightly irritating calmness. "Withdraw at your discretion."

The lights and sounds of combat and destruction faded as Emma and Vira moved out of the miasma. Small clusters of demons remained scattered about the outer edges, fading to gray as the once powerful, impenetrable haze clouding the minds of its victims began to fizzle and evaporate. One by one, men and women and girls and boys began to stumble out of the darkness into the blankets and warm drinks and plush toy bearing arms of the emergency responders.

"Scout 1, we've got some activity further along," said Chunli. "How fast can you get to the top of the bunker?"

Emma checked her interface. "…Two minutes. Will that do?"

"We'll try and kite some, but we need to keep going. Get here quickly."

"Understood. Vira, Motya."

Two affirmative pulses answered her. Team Four accelerated, speeding off in a flash of color.

The first responders came from a variety of backgrounds. Some had been part of the cities first response group from before the invasion, trained specially for these situations. Most were simply normal people who hadn't wanted to undergo the procedures needed to join the military, but still wanted to help somehow. Most visible. however, were the towering off-duty military personnel. They were the minority, but they stood out in every shot Ryouta made with his camera drone.

Amongst all of those adults, Motya looked very small.

Ryouta mentally nudged the drone to follow behind Motya as he panned the view over the rows of rescued people, psychiatrists making their way from person to person to make sure they were dealing with the experience healthily. Family members huddled together, holding mugs of soothing hot chocolate or spiced cider. It was still quiet, the shock and fear of a demon attack not quite abated. Many of them had been fed on before Emma and Vira had shown up. Motya stopped in front of a man and his son, huddled together under the same blanket.

"Here," she said quietly, manifesting a bottle in a shower of red sparks and handing it to the man. The label said "Mir", and had a stylized sun spanning across the bottom. "You look like you could use this."

"Thanks." The man reached out for the bottle as the camera drone went—

—click—

—and Motya paused, tilting her head at a telepathic message. She nodded at the man as he took the bottle out of her hand and began unscrewing the cap. Again, red light danced down Motya's fingers, descending into columns. Ryouta tilted the drone upwards as two bottles solidified in Motya's hands. Two blurs, one blue and one red—

—click—

—swished by, the boy looking up as the flickering lights made him pull his face out of his father's shoulders. He smiled. Just a small one, but it reached his eyes, and that was enough for the moment.

"You're going to be okay," said Motya, smiling down at the boy. He flinched and flushed as he realized Motya was talking to him. She gave him a gentle headpat, which immediately prompted a pout. Motya giggled. "Stay strong, okay?"

The little boy nodded. Motya gave him and his father one last smile and nod, before moving on down the line.

fire—

turn—

drop—

spin—

dodge—

jump—

Land, and skid.

Vira breathed deep, pulling at magic reserves she'd never needed to use. It was scary.

"Take a break, Vira," said Emma from the distance. "Purify your gem, I've got this for now."

"Okay."

Vira swallowed and pulled a handful of cubes from her pocket. Her gem was dimmer than was ideal, but she was burning through magic so quickly anyway that it'd probably be just as dim in a few minutes. Damn it, what was the point if the demons spawned so quickly?

"Vira?" asked Ryouta, breaking in with an audio call. "You've stopped moving. Are you alright?"

"Huh? Oh, yah, sure," said Vira. She'd forgotten that Ryouta had a link to her vision. "Nah, I'm just takin' a breather, saoyeh."

Ryouta rolled his eyes. "Do you have enough cubes?"

"Yah, yah, it's cool, saoyeh," said Vira. She glanced at her gem. It looked better. "Layoff, will ya?"

"Uh… sure," said Ryouta. "I'm getting good shots from you, by the way. Thanks for letting me use your eyes."

Man, that was a weird sentence to hear. Vira shrugged, before remembering that Ryouta wasn't there to see. "Eh, it's cool."

She picked up her gem and stood back up, feeling a little better. Her gem was back to full brightness, twisting back onto her body as she pulled out a rifle. One of Ryouta's camera drones swung down to hover nearby. In the distance, a flash of red could be seen rapidly closing.

"I gotta go."

"Right, talk to you later."

A deep breath. She could do this.

Emma rocketed past the rooftop, a trail of light blue following behind her as demon lasers tried to pin her down. Vira snapped her rifle to her shoulder. One foot forward, the other foot back, with her rifle's scope raised to her eyes. Her back was straight and upright, but relaxed to absorb shock. A single burst of—

—click—

—dark blue pulsed out of the rifle's muzzle. The magical bullet twisted through space, then slammed into into the first demon and ripping through the bottom of its skull, before continuing onwards through one, two more, and finally coming to a halt by shattering inside a fourth demon and spraying rapidly-fading chunks of white out the back. Already, Vira's hands were moving to—

—click—

—reload, blue light flickering around the chamber of her gun as a fresh cartridge was summoned, sliding into the breech as Vira closed the bolt and prepared to fire again. Another flash of blue and a CRACK, then Vira leaped off the roof to-

run—

fire—

roll—

Go.

"Can I take a photo?" asked Ryouta.

Vira gave him a raised eyebrow. She was sitting against a wall with the victims of the latest miasma. First responders were still milling around getting people back on their feet.

"Seriously?" she asked. A laser had caught her in the upper torso. It had cut through the center of her chest, starting at the heart and slicing down, and to the left, burning away flesh and bone as easily as a plasma cutter. The remains of her left lung were a charred mess, the arteries in the area burned shut by cauterized flesh. It was the tail end of the patrol, fortunately, and Nadya had let them off early to treat Vira's injury.

"Yeah, it's uh," began Ryouta, before swallowing and clearing his throat. "Well it's interesting, you know?"

Emma paused, just about to spray medical foam into the wound, and glanced up at Vira. They shared a look of confusion, then looked at Ryouta again. "…Seriously?"

"Well okay, it's really gross," said Ryouta. Looking again, he was looking very pale. "But, I have a job to do, and I need to document this sort of thing."

"If GPM lets you run it, you mean," said Emma, turning back to Vira's chest.

"Well, yes, that too," said Ryouta. "But better to have the photo and never see it published, right?"

Vira shrugged, then winced. "Sure, I guess. Not like I have anything left there to hide."

"M'kay," said Ryouta. He refocused his vision, adjusting it so that his right eye captured Vira's upper body just so, to frame the long gash of charred and roasted bone and internal organs. The deep, navy blue of Vira's magic dancing along the edges, slowly working its way inward and uncooking her. With a-

-click-

-in his personal audio feed, he took a still as Emma depressed the plunger on top of the can of medical foam. The distinct tang of the stuff, a combination of ethanol, tangerines, and anise, wafted through the air.

"Does it hurt?" asked Ryouta. Vira lay her head back against the wall, eyes closed, and breathed deeply.

"What d'ya think?" she ground out between her teeth.

"Sorry," said Ryouta. He framed a second photo, then captured the still with another-

—click—

—as Motya scrambled towards them, skidding to a stop and bumping into Ryouta.

"Vira, are you alright?" she asked, already pulling out a massive bottle of vodka. "Here—."

"Calm down, Motya, she's fine," said Emma, raising a hand and pulling Ryouta back by the hem of his shirt. "I don't think we'll need an entire two-liter of vodka."

Vira rolled her eyes but smiled and held out a hand. "Here, siaojyeh. Thanks."

Motya bit her lip, unscrewing the cap for Vira and handing it over by the neck. Vira took the bottle and drank a gulp of vodka, wincing as it went down. The wound sparked, red light shimmering with navy blue to become deep purple and begin—

—click—

—healing the injury with remarkable speed. Bones began rapidly knit themselves together, forming Vira's ribcage. Muscles followed soon after.

"Ah, wow, that's strong," said Vira, blinking. "Motya, ya' didn't chuck too much magic into this did ya?"

Motya blinked, then checked her gem. "Ah, no, not too much. I'm still ten percent above critical."

"Still, you should purify," said Emma. She sat back with a sigh. "We better get dinner after this, before we go on escort duty."

"We can get it delivered, can't we?" asked Ryouta. He turned away to give Vira some privacy as her chest began to fill back in."I'll place an order for beef."

"Yeah, can you?"

"Sure."

13. Towards Greener Pastures

Dinner was an abbreviated affair. Team 4 and Ryouta ate quickly, eyeing the meeting reminder that hovered at the edge of their vision. The four of them would be working with A Company of the 2nd Armored Cavalry. Everyone, magical girls and soldiers, would be meeting at a canteen near the outer edge of the bunker.

Team 4 and Ryouta had decided to finish dinner where they were before heading over. The group had climbed to the top of a nearby residence block to eat, swinging their legs over the side of the building and balancing their food on their knees. The residents were still being treated for the effects of a demon attack, leaving them undisturbed for their meal.

"Hey, senpai, isn't the 2nd Armored your unit?" asked Vira. She held the short-rib she had been eating between her molars and crunched down, squeezing the marrow out of the bone and earning a wince from Ryouta and Motya .

"Yeah, it is," said Emma, sucking at the end of her own piece of bone. "Our CO for the moment is Captain Alanis Siyankin. She's a magical girl, but don't forget to follow procedure during the briefing, okay?"

Both new girls nodded.

"What's she like?" asked Motya.

Emma paused. "…Er, you mean personally, or as a commander?"

"The latter."

"Mmm… she's definitely a well grounded person," said Emma, tapping her bone against her lips. "Patient too, even when you screw up really badly and put the team in a bad place, and tries to make sure you know why you screwed up if there's time. But she also expects you to follow orders and doesn't pull her punches."

"So, kinda like Nadya then?" asked Vira.

"Er, I guess?" said Emma. She pulled the meat off of another bone and chewed thoughtfully. "I think Alanis is a little friendlier than Nadya, personally. She likes to transform into a cat and get you to rub her ears, it's really cute. For that matter, she's enchanted herself to have a tail and cat ears all the time."

Vira, Motya, and Ryouta blinked as Emma sent the three of them her memory of Alanis jumping into her lap on the transport ship. The purring had been, and still was, adorable.

"Wait, does it work when she's untransformed too?" asked Vira, perking up with a curious light in her eyes. "The ear rubbin' and stuff?"

"…I don't know," said Emma. She winced as Vira started to grin "And it's… probably best not to ask, actually."

Vira's grin collapsed immediately into a pout.

After dinner, a medium-sized supply drone heading for the perimeter was commandeered for transportation. They rode on top of its payload to the meeting point. The canteen was packed with soldiers, grouped around the tables and waiting for the briefing to start. It would precede the mission proper by several hours, giving everyone a chance to get mentally focused and make any last minute preparations they may need. It was also enough time for the new girls to become slightly more integrated.

Team 4 was being placed with Second Platoon. Ryouta would, of course, be following them. As they stepped off the drone, Emma could see Emily and Tracy talking. Alanis was nowhere in sight, but was probably busy with command stuff. The place was completely packed, leaving little room for maneuver. With a roll of her eyes, Emma jumped onto the lampposts and mader her way towards Second Platoon with Vira and Motya. Ryouta was left at the edge of the canteen to make his way over on his own, to his displeasure.

The warrant officer in charge of Second Platoon was named Timaeus Dolechzal. Large, even for the soldiery, and dark-skinned, Timaeus was a veteran of several campaigns. He didn't stand and salute immediately as Emma landed in front of him.

"Good evening, Lieutenant Sinclair," he said, nodding slowly. The greeting was in British English.

"Thanks," said Emma quietly. "It's always unnerving when people snap to attention immediately around me."

Timaeus nodded again. "I have had more than a few rookie commanders. I know the feeling. How are you doing, ma'am? I heard you were in medical?"

Emma squirmed at the formal pronoun but ignored it. "I feel much better, Mr. Dolechzal, thank you for asking. You've, er, heard the latest on the newly contracted I'm in charge of?"

"Yes, that would be them," said Timaeus, nodding over Emma's shoulder at Vira and Motya. "Good evening, Lieutenants."

Vira shifted nervously. Motya stood a little straighter and stepped forward unconsciously.

"Good evening, Mr. Dolechzal," said Motya, her voice smooth and level. She held out a hand to shake. "It's good to meet you. How are you doing?"

Timaeus raised an eyebrow and glanced at Emma, before shaking Motya's hand with his own, massive, brown one. "I am doing well enough, Lieutenant, thank you for asking. How about yourself? Are you coping well with your new life?"

"Aheh, I suppose," said Motya, smiling nervously. "Everyone is much older and more experienced, so I have a lot to learn. Myself and Vira will be in your care, Mr. Dolechzal."

Timaeus nodded. "In that case, let's get everyone introduced to the troops. Second Platoon is all down this row."

Vira opened up a bit more as they made their way down the row, but Motya fairly blossomed. Emma wasn't entirely sure where the vintner's daughter had picked up the ability to casually begin conversations like she did, but it was impressive. Certainly, Motya had been a little more hesitant when they had first met.

Well, wherever it came from, it was a good thing. Despite their limitations, it was important for Vira and Motya to be confident in themselves if they were going to survive combat. Emma turned her attention to the other greenie in the company.

"Hey, Tracy, how're you doing?" asked Emma, stepping to the side.

"Ah, good, thanks! Emily's been giving me some help," said Tracy. Emma looked over at where Tracy was sitting, listening to her command squad converse about something. She seemed to be keeping one ear on the conversation while talking to Emma over telepathy. "I'm not trained well enough to command yet, but she says that I'll, um, 'not get myself killed' this time."

"Knowing Emily, it was probably a lot more profane than that," said Emma, poking Emily telepathically. "Hey Emily, you been giving the greenie tips then?"

"What gets through her skull, yeah," said Emily tiredly. She was perched atop a light post above her command squad. "She gets things quick though, so at least we won't be getting her a new body for the second time in a row."

"Heh, that's good," said Emma. "I should introduce you guys to Vira and Motya in a bit."

"After the briefing," said Emily. "Check your chronometer, we're about to get started."

"Oh, right, okay," said Emma. She looked around. "Hm… I wonder where Ryouta's gone?"

"Who's that?"

"Oh, photojournalist attached to my team," said Emma. "He's— oh there he is, I'll introduce you later." She sent Ryouta a text with a map marker of where they were.

"Photojournalist, eh?" asked Emily. Emma could hear the grin in her telepathy.

"Knock it off, Emily," said Emma, shooting her a glare.

"You're blushing~"

"Wha- no I'm not!"

"Er, Emma, you kinda are," said Tracy, looking away from her command team with a raised eyebrow and a slowly growing grin.

"You two are terrible, terrible people," said Emma, turning smartly on her heel to face the other direction and ignoring the quiet telepathic giggling.

"Hey, sorry, I got sidetracked talking to some of the troops," said Ryouta as he jogged up.

"Letting yourself get distracted on the job Ryouta?" asked Emma, grinning. She shook her head. "Tsk tsk, Shizuki-san."

Ryouta grinned back at her. "Well you know, gotta get the fluff for the captions, right?"

"It'd be easier to just make something up," said Emma. She waved a hand. "Something about how new girls need to spend a lot of time being extra super moe for their platoons."

"Oh yes, definitely," said Ryouta with a snort of laughter. "Tell me, Magical Girl Emma-chan, how did you become the most moe girl in your company?"

"Obviously it's with my charming personality and tendency to break into dance," said Emma with maximum deadpan sarcasm. "My command of the waltz is sublime."

"Actually, do you dance?" asked Ryouta. "I only ask because my parents made me take dance lessons once, but I've never actually met someone who dances."

"Sort of, I had to take lessons too, but it was for football," said Emma. "You know a lot of athletes take ballet lessons, for flexibility and stuff."

"Ah, so, not ballroom dance then."

"No, sorry," said Emma, shrugging. "Could be interesting though, if you wanted to try and teach me sometime?"

"Sure," said Ryouta, smiling. "Ah, maybe later, after this mission? I think there's some free time built in, right?"

"Yeah, there is," said Emma. "Uh, there's a rec-center in the bunker, we can go there. After breakfast I think. I still owe you food."

"If you say so," said Ryouta, rolling his eyes. "That's still a gift in my book."

Emma shook her head. "You're weird, Ryouta. Cool, but weird."

"Thanks," Ryouta said dryly. "Thanks for the compliment, Emma, really appreciate that."

"Oh, sure, of course. Only telling the—."

"TEN HUT."

All conversation came to an abrupt halt. The entire company snapped to attention in a single movement, the sound of two hundred men and women clicking their heels together echoing throughout the chamber. Five splotches of color stood amongst a sea of black armor. Their backs were as straight as the adults' around them. Shoulders squared, eyes straight ahead.

On an unspoken cue, the entire company pivoted to face a new arrival.

A beat, in which Ryouta froze and glanced around nervously.

Alanis stepped forward, soundless on the floor of the canteen. She still bore her cat ears and tail, but had since made a few edits to her appearance. Alanis was now appreciably older looking, sixteen instead of fourteen, and had pushed her hair out more so that it could be twisted into a thin braid, wrapped around her head, and tacked in place with a brooch in the shape of a tiger, claws grasping at an unseen enemy. A dour expression pinched her eyebrows.

Unsettlingly, she had taken the liberty of modifying her pupils. They were now slits.

Alanis came to parade rest in front of the company. "You may be seated," she said, breaking into a small smile.

The company sat back down. There was a minute of shuffling as everyone re-situated themselves. Emma scooted over so that Ryouta had a place to sit, as the command team's table was slightly less packed than the others.

"Good evening, A Company," began Alanis. "It's a bit late for all this, but I hope everyone's had a good relaxation cycle."

"We've all downloaded the briefing file, so I won't go into detail about that. This is the third of four missions to empty Bunker 7-South. D Company is leading, followed by C Company, then us. B Company will pull up the rear. The mission is pretty vanilla, so there's nothing to talk about there. Everyone here knows the drill. As usual, try and keep the civilians safe. "

"More importantly, it's been a long time since we had any significant enemy activity, so everyone needs to be on the lookout for something unusual. If you see something weird, say something to your commanding officer. Overall, this mission should go smoothly, but a healthy dose of paranoia won't hurt us. Magical girls stay within the perimeter at all times. We don't want any surprises."

"And on that note, we have a group of very new magical girls with us today. Their profiles and assignments are in your files. This will be their first official mission, so everyone, please look out for them. Are there any questions?"

"Sir, what contingencies do we have in case things do go wrong?" asked one of the soldiers near the front.

"C Company is being deployed to the train station after this mission," said Alanis. A small diagram appeared on everyone's vision. "If there is an attack, C Company will be the first to respond, as they're most likely to be closest to the area. A Company will abort its mission, escort the civilians back to the bunker, and then deploy with B Company to support C Company. D Company is slated for refit, so they will be held in reserve until such time as they are needed. An ambush is considered to be unlikely, but if that does occur, B Company's mission will be canceled and it will deploy to support magical girls are clustered around a Shock and Awe power-set, so, platoon leaders, you'll want to deploy to maximize that if you can."

"Thank you sir."

"Not at all. Are there any other questions?"

Silence.

"Very well, A Company is dismissed to begin preparations. Magical girls, come to the front, I've got some things to discuss."

The canteen dissolved into chaos.

"Ack!" yelped Ryouta. The armored figures around him were like a great, black, metallic sea. Without the agility of a magical girl, Ryouta found himself unable to advance or retreat, pushed around simply because he was a small fish surrounded by behemoths. At the rate things were going, he—

—felt a gloved hand close around his own.

"Stick close, okay?" said Emma, pulling him towards her. She gave him an amused smile. "Don't go wandering off like that, there's too many people, and you'll be late to the meeting."

"O-oh, t-thanks," said Ryouta, letting himself be tugged along as Emma strong-armed her way through the crowd. "W-what's Alanis going to t-talk about?"

Why was he stammering? There was no reason for him to be stammering.

"Probably something about how we're going to run the upcoming mission," said Emma. She pulled him close as a heavy weapons specialist pushed a crate of explosives past. Ryouta yelped again, both in surprise and from the crate clipping his arm. "Ah, you okay?"

"Yeah, I'm f-fine," said Ryouta. He flushed, very aware of how close they were.

"Cool, come on."

The two of them emerged from the bustle and hurried over to where Alanis was starting the meeting. Halfway there, Emma realized that she was still holding on to Ryouta's hand. Somehow, this didn't really bother her. She kept her fingers curled loosely around his until the meeting ended. The little pocket of warmth between her fingers trembled slightly, but calmed down with time.

It was a pleasant, but also strange, like putting on new cleats after your previous pair had grown too small.

"Right then, we've got a few hours, so we'll split up," said Alanis. "Emily, Emma, we'll work on getting a better idea of how to integrate everyone's power sets. Tracy, Vira, and Motya, you three will need to work on expanding your powers. Bounce ideas off of each other, and try for flexibility."

"Ryouta, you should probably go with the others," said Emma. "We'll be in a VR room, right Alanis? Same as last time?"

"Yes, I've got a stack of empty residence blocks we can use," said Alanis. She glanced down at Emma and Ryouta's hands, then back up. "We'll be heading over to Section 17-H. Don't be too late."

She gestured at Emily, and the two of them leaped away. Vira, Motya, and Tracy glanced amongst themselves.

"We'll, uh, get going too then," said Tracy, holding back a grin. "There's an empty canteen at Section 12-D we can tear up, so, um, see you guys later."

"Good luck, senpai!" said Vira, before she left with Motya and Tracy.

Emma and Ryouta flushed at the comment, awkwardly looking away from each other as the group of new girls departed. They stayed silent for awhile, neither quite ready to breach the steadily thickening awkwardness between them.

"I, uh… we're still holding hands," said Ryouta.

"Ah, yeah, we are," said Emma. "Do you… want me to stop?"

"N-no, it's n-nice," said Ryouta. "But um, we've only known each other for a day or so."

"That's true," said Emma, fidgeting. "It's also… not the most professional thing."

Emma looked back up at Ryouta. They both had jobs to do here. Ryouta had his photographs to take, and, from the brief amount of his world that Emma had seen, it wasn't something you could do while distracted by a girl. Emma certainly couldn't lead a team while sighing about a boy, and regardless of everything else, they hadn't known each other for every long at all. Even if there wasn't a war and they were both still in school, things were going much too quickly.

"Heh, you know, if we were in a shoujo anime, this could totally work," said Emma. Her smile was bittersweet. "I'd take you to the top of the building, and we'd confess to each other with the sunset in the background, or do something else horribly cheesy."

Ryouta laughed. "Yeah, that'd probably happen wouldn't it? Still, it's safe to say we're both i-interested in each other, right?"

"Yeah, that's probably accurate," said Emma. She sighed. "I've… got another person to talk to about this stuff too though."

Ryouta raised an eyebrow.

"I mean, like, she mentioned something about being into me, but we never actually talked about it, so I don't really know what's going on," said Emma, blushing darker. "S-so, I'd ask you if you still wanted to get dinner, but uh, I need to hash things out, and I don't want to leave anyone hanging, you know?"

Ryouta marshaled a smile to this. "Well, that'd be bad for everyone involved, right? I'll umm… I'll wait for you then? Call me?"

Emma nodded, pulling back her hand. "I will. I promise, whichever way things go, I'll definitely call you and let you know."

Ryouta nodded. He looked at his hand, a little sadly.

"I'll… see you later then, I guess?" said Emma.

"Awuh? Oh, right, yeah," said Ryouta. He fidgeted in place, looking away and playing with the hem of his shirt. "I uh… c-could you— that is—."

There was just enough time for Emma to raise a confused eyebrow before Ryouta, blushing, stood on the tips of his toes and very briefly kissed her. Their noses got in the way and he sort of missed and overall it was just generally sort of awkward, but it was still a kiss. Emma's first kiss.

"I'llseeyoulaterbye!" Ryouta said in a rush, before running away and leaving Emma blinking after him in a daze.

14. Prepare for Extraction

The canteen that Tracy, Vira, and Motya had taken over for practice had been twisted into a heap of shattered metal and plastic. A single picnic table remained. The cobblestones beneath it marked a line of demarcation that separated civil discourse from the rude vociferation caused by three magical girls doing their level best to create a perfect storm of blades, explosives, and flammable liquids.

"And so, as a result of that, I think that it should be possible for me to combine many different distillations to get a wide variety of results," said Motya, sipping from her teacup as she, Vira, and Tracy sat across from Emily, Emma, and Ryouta at the picnic table. "Now that I know how to stabilize fire breathing, it should be relatively simple to stabilize other destructive distillations and apply them directly into combat."

"Huh, well, that's a thing," said Emily, resting her cheek against one hand as she nibbled on a slice of cake. "You guys did some pretty fast work here."

"Well, we had a lotta help," said Vira, looking down at her tea with a slight blush from the praise. "Saoyeh knew a lot about magic, it turned out."

"Ah, only what mom has told me," said Ryouta. "It's not much, but I thought every little bit would help, so…"

"Thank you, though," said Motya. "It really was very helpful. Were you just curious when you were younger?"

"Ah, it's just something I have a passing interest in," said Ryouta. "I'm just exposed to it often, in a matriarchy, so I guess it was inevitable."

"I see."

The table went silent briefly, giving everyone a chance to take a bite of cake.

"SO, Emma-senpai," said Vira, setting down her fork with a grin. "Didya kiss?"

Emma choked on her cake. "W-what?"

"Well yanno, you n'Saoyeh were holdin' hands all through that meetin' with Alanis," said Vira. "So how'd it go?"

"I'm right here you know," said Ryouta, frowning at her with a blush.

"Hush, the girls are talking," said Vira, flapping her hand at him.

"W-well I m-mean…" began Emma, swallowing her cake and doing her level best not to do anything incredibly embarrassing. "I— we, uh… I guess it was nice…"

Vira's grin grew. "D'ya mean 'nice' or like 'nice'?"

Motya slapped her on the arm. "Vira! That's incredibly uncouth!"

"Beh, prude," said Vira. She rolled her eyes at Motya as Emily and Tracy dissolved into giggles. Emma and Ryouta simply went red out of mortification. "Didn't ya' ever make out with a guy?"

"Wha— no, I have not," said Motya, looking increasingly scandalized. "It is improper!"

"Well then yur jus' weird," said Vira. "I know plenty a'people who sleep around all the time, what's so weird about it?"

Motya seemed about ready to explode as Emily and Tracy nearly fell out of their seats from laughter.

"I-in any case, it's not like we're going to do anything right before the mission," said Emma, schooling her emotions and taking a sip of tea. "We need to be ready."

"Ehh, it'd be better to have the experience before hand wouldn't it?" said Vira. "Just go to one of the abandoned residence cubes and—."

Motya physically slapped a hand over Vira's mouth before she could finish her sentence, much to Vira's outrage. By this point Emily and Tracy were having difficulty breathing, while Ryouta was doing his best to disappear.

A cheery voice broke in over telepathy, largely unnoticed between the hysterics and the outraged squabbling. "Am I interrupting something?"

"No Senbey, Vira's just being a twat," said Emma, giving Vira an unamused look while Ryouta quietly combusted next to her. "What's up?"

"Many things, do you have a specific query?" replied Senbey. It materialized unnoticed into the space just over the teapot, barely making the landing on top of the lid, and slid off with a quiet thump.

"Er, I meant, do you have any reason for being here?" asked Emma. "I assume that Incubators don't do social calls."

"Oh, yes, that is true," said Senbey. "Standard procedure is to allow the system to progress under its own power as much as possible. I am here for other reasons."

"What reasons?"

"A variety of reasons," said Senbey, hopping onto Emma's shoulder. "One of them is to take measurements of yourself, Vira, and Motya before your mission begins."

"Oh right, I'm your science experiment aren't I? Am I of sufficient interest then?"

"Absolutely! It's all very intriguing!" said Senbey, waving its tail rapidly. "Your soul gem readouts, for example, have unique regressions that are quite rare in the magical girl population."

"Oh hey, it's Senbey!" said Vira, breaking free of Motya's grip. "Hey there Senbey, how're ya doin'?"

"I am quite well, Vira!" said Senbey, cocking its head to the side with a smile. "How is everyone doing?"

As it turned out, Senbey was the Incubator responsible for Tracy, Vira, and Motya's contracts. They chatted for a bit about life as a magical girl and what they were experiencing. Senbey said some vague things in general sympathy for Tracy's body loss, but things started getting awkward quickly.

"We should get going," said Emily eventually. "The mission is supposed to start in an hour, but we should get there early and get situated."

"I'll have to stay here," said Ryouta as the group got up to go. "Since I'm basically a civilian, and you don't need another person to protect. My drones will follow you guys just like before, and I'll make sure to keep in contact through the local network."

"Alright, then I'll see you when we get back," said Emma, giving him a smile. "We'll uh, figure things out then, yeah?"

"Yeah, of course," said Ryouta, smiling back at her. "Stay safe, okay?"

"Okay."

"Kisssssssssssssss," hissed Vira.

"Vira!"

"Ow!"

The company would be leaving through one of the surface gates, designed for tanks and other large vehicles. Four tanks would lead the column. The column would then be flanked by IFVs, and backed by more four more tanks. If all went well, the excessive firepower would be only for show. The magical girls were to be riding on the drones being used to transport the civilians. It wasn't the best cover, but it was unlikely to matter this far back from the line. The morale boost to the civilians was more important. Even so, it made Emma feel wary.

Senbey had come along with them for some reason. The Incubator rode along on Emma's shoulder as Team 4 made its way towards the drone they would be riding in.

"You know, it's very interesting!" Senbey said idly. "Of all the girls here, Vira has the most potential."

"…I guess?" asked Emma. "Where'd that come from? And how is it interesting?"

"Ah, ah, perhaps it's not that interesting to you, but I think it is," said Senbey. "I mention it because there is a girl with an impressive amount of potential in the transport you are going on. I hope to contract her before she leaves Helsinberg."

Emma nearly came to a halt in front of a combat drone. It backpedaled furiously and managed to avoid her.

"Oi, ya'lright there, senpai?" asked Vira, slightly alarmed.

"I'm fine," said Emma, forcing a smile as her blood went cold. "Senbey, are you saying you want to get another girl into this mess?"

"Well, not this conflict particularly," said Senbey. "But I do have duties as an Incubator, after all. Wouldn't you do the same if you were in my position?"

"But there's a time and place for these things! This is neither! And besides, there's Incubators at the rear who can contract her if she really does have potential."

"You're not wrong," said Senbey, nodding. "I agree it's not the best time, but her potential is situational, and will fade by the time she makes it to safety. So, I'm asking for your help."

"What, help you convince her?"

"No no no," Senbey said quickly. "Nothing like that. I'd just like it if you'd speak to her and help collect her thoughts. If she makes a wish, I will of course grant it, but we Incubators do not seek to make untenable contracts, if we can manage it."

"I—," began Emma, before biting her lip. There was a world of difference between a contract made when things were going poorly and a contract made when you had a chance to really think about the consequences. This was hardly the latter, and Emma would really rather just make sure the girl got to safety and didn't bother with wishes and contracts and everything else.

But on the other hand, wishes were the chance of a lifetime. Emma wouldn't have given up her wish for anything. Maybe a different wish, depending, but it had changed her life, and she didn't regret making it. She didn't think she ever would. It didn't sit comfortably with her not to give someone else with potential a chance to think about it, at least.

"…Do you know her name?"

"Of course," said Senbey, flicking its tail once. "Her name is Mikoto Albright."

"I— Alright, I'll help you," said Emma. "She needs to understand what she's getting into, if she makes a wish, so I'll go talk to her."

"Good!" said Senbey, flicking its tail the opposite way. "Thank you Emma, I really appreciate it! I'm sure that together, we can help Mikoto reach the right decision."

The transport was a huge, resilient looking thing, designed for carrying very large, very heavy loads on a wide flatbed trailer. Its wheels were as wide as Emma was tall, and the bed itself was another wheel's width higher. Sheets of ablative plating had been bolted onto the sides, making it somewhat more resistant to any possible attack. When they got there, Vira immediately went to jump to the top.

"Hey wait," said Emma. "Don't do that. The civvies have enough on their mind without getting surprised by a magical girl. Climb up by the ladder."

Vira blinked, then nodded. "Oh, okay."

Her feet clicked on the ladder as she climbed quickly, then swung herself onto the bed of the drone. Motya went next, and paused at the foot of the ladder.

"What's up?" asked Emma.

"Nothing, it's just that, I'm the age as most of these people's children," said Motya, sighing quietly. "It is… rather odd, to think about."

Emma nodded and smiled reassuringly. "It's a little weird, sometimes, when you're giving orders and people a hundred years older than you listen. But you get used to it, you know?"

"I suppose," said Motya. She placed one foot on the ladder. "…I suppose I just have to go up and talk to people, right?"

"Yeah."

"I'll see you up top then."

Emma sighed as Motya climbed up. She didn't feel all that different, as a person, compared to before she contracted, but she did miss being able to walk into a room and not check instinctively for firing lanes.

"Are you coming up, Senbey?" asked Emma.

"No, I think it would be best to be discrete," said Senbey. It paused, vanishing from Emma's shoulder and reappearing buried up to its neck in the concrete. It sighed. "Again with the sign errors. In any case, there will be enough time for her to make a contract before she leaves for the evacuation area. I will reappear at the opportune moment."

"Alright," said Emma, nodding. She couldn't help but smile at the Incubator's head popping out of the ground like some sort of freakish fungus. "See you later."

Emma walked over to the ladder, climbed up, and swung herself in. The bed of the drone was packed with people, huddled in groups with family and friends. A railing was set up to keep people from falling off. Vira and Motya had shuffled themselves into a small, open area to wait for Emma, and were fidgeting awkwardly as the assembly tried to be polite but couldn't restrain staring and whispering.

"Well then," Emma muttered to herself, then waved at Vira and Motya to follow her. She walked to the front of the vehicle, giving people reassuring smiles as she went and setting her nomenclator to find Mikoto Albright.

Mikoto was sitting off to the side with her family. An only child, apparently, with long black hair tied back with a ribbon at the end. She sat with her knees tucked up under her chin, huddled into her parents' side for comfort. She was much, much younger than Emma had expected, only eleven years old. Not ideal at all, but that was something to work on later. Emma needed to do her job, first, and make sure all of the civilians would be prepared in case something happened.

"Excuse me, but could you move a little?" she asked of a family sitting at the front. They nodded wordlessly and got out of her way. "Thanks."

A deep breath. "Good morning everyone, if I could please have your attention," said Emma. "My name is Second Lieutenant Emma Sinclair. I will be working with you all today to ensure everyone has a safe ride to the train station. We're not expecting much combat, but I'd like to go over the emergency procedures with everyone before we get started."

It was the standard speech that they'd fed her in training. Her TacComp modulated a lot of the issues with anxiety, and her military implants let her make sure everyone was watching the presentation as it went along.

"If you have any questions, any one of us can try and answer them," said Emma as she finished up. "We'll be getting underway in the next forty minutes or so, so please use the restroom and take care of other last minute business now."

There hadn't been that many questions. Emma had been able to foist them off to Vira and Motya halfway through when she spotted Mikoto getting up to use the restroom. She caught up with Mikoto as the younger girl was walking back.

Emma paused uncertainly on a roof a block away. The young girl was wringing her hands, looking down at the ground and walking slowly. Others passed her at higher speed, but Mikoto seemed oddly reluctant. She kept looking up and pausing.

"It's probably best to speak to her now," said Senbey. It was unusually quiet as it faded into place beside her. "I have linked her to you telepathically already."

"…Thanks," said Emma. She shifted nervously. "Ah… Mikoto?"

Mikoto froze in the middle of the street, going stiff with shock. She looked around.

"H-hello?" she said out loud. Emma heard her only because of her enhanced hearing.

"Try thinking it," said Emma. "I'm speaking to you over telepathy."

"Hello?" Mikoto asked again. Her telepathy was loud and unpracticed, and made Emma wince. "W-who are you?"

"I'm Emma, the magical girl who was talking earlier," said Emma. "Uhh, I'll meet you in an alleyway? To your left. I need to talk to you about… things."

"O-okay."

Mikoto glanced to the sides, then walked across to Emma's side of the street. Emma hopped across the roofs to where Mikoto was, then jumped down. The younger girl squeaked and jumped as Emma landed at the end of the alley.

"Sorry, are you alright?" asked Emma, switching back to speaking out loud. "I didn't mean to scare you."

"I— I'm okay," said Mikoto, looking down and away. She fiddled with the hem of her shirt. "I— you were talking in my head."

"Yes."

"D-does that mean…?"

"Ah, yes," said Emma, looking away awkwardly. "I… Senbey asked me to talk to you about making a contract."

"O-oh, okay," said Mikoto. She didn't look up to meet Emma's eyes. "D-do you need my wish right now?"

"No no no, you don't need to make a wish right now," said Emma hurriedly. She stepped forward, slinging off her backpack and setting it down nearby. "That's sort of what I wanted to talk about. Becoming a magical girl is a really big step, and I wanted to make sure you knew what you were getting into. What um... what do you know about magical girls?"

Mikoto fidgeted. "Umm, I know they're supposed to protect humanity. A-and that they're super important for helping fight the Cephola- er, cepheloa—."

"Cephalopods," said Emma. Mikoto pouted at her.

"Ceph. A. Lo. Pods," said Mikoto carefully, before continuing. "And that you get a wish, and it can be any wish in the world. B-but, t-that's about it."

"That's about right," said Emma, nodding. "Do you know how difficult it is, as a job?"

"Ummm, not really," said Mikoto, shaking her head. "I mean, it has to be difficult, right?"

"It's a lot more difficult than you think it is," said Emma. "I wanted to talk to you because, well, most people don't realize how difficult it is." She took a deep breath and sighed. Goddess, this was difficult. "I… I don't want to scare you, but it's very dangerous. A lot of girls… get hurt very badly. You're very young, so we'll want you to go with your parents back to the rear, where you can get trained, but you will still need to do dangerous things later. Do you have a wish at all?"

"N-not really," said Mikoto. "I… I never thought I'd get a chance, and I don't really have anything to wish for. I—."

She stopped, taking a shaky breath. Emma winced.

"It's just that the squid arrived, right?" said Emma. "It's scary. Do you… want a hug?"

Mikoto nodded. Emma stepped forward and pulled her into a hug, smoothing the young girl's hair back. She stood there for a minute, letting Mikoto get her feelings back under control.

"It's okay to be scared, Mikoto," said Emma gently. "Everybody gets scared."

"N-not you guys," said Mikoto quietly.

"Hm?"

"M-magical girls and soldiers, I mean," said Mikoto. "You go out and fight them, and make them go away."

"Ah, well, we get scared too you know," said Emma. "We just try our best to hide it when we're fighting."

"R-really?"

"Yeah, we're still people," said Emma. She pulled away from Mikoto to give her a grin. "But we're still going to make sure you and your parents are safe. It's okay to be scared, but we'll protect you, Mikoto."

Mikoto swallowed and nodded. "O-okay."

"Here," Emma said, pulling Mikoto over to Emma's backpack. It was weird, but Emma had never gotten around to taking out the teddy bear. It had stayed there ever since Emma had picked it up on the outskirts of Helsinberg. Now, it was suddenly useful. Emma pulled it out and handed it to Mikoto. "I got this teddy bear for some reason, but I never really needed it. I'm giving it to you now. If you're scared, just give him a hug, okay?"

"O-okay," said Mikoto, taking the teddy bear and squeezing it tightly. "W-what his name?"

"I never named him," said Emma. "Why don't you come up with one?"

Mikoto frowned and thought hard. "Mmmm… how about Yokkun?"

"That's a great name," said Emma. "Hold on to him, okay? And, if you don't have a wish yet, it's okay," said Emma. She stepped back and put her hands on Mikoto's shoulders, looking the girl in the eye. "You don't have to make a wish. Being a magical girl is really difficult and dangerous, so you should only make a wish if you really, really want it. You have to be sure."

"H-how do you know if you're sure?" asked Mikoto.

"You'll know," said Emma confidently. "Just keep asking yourself if you're really, really sure about your wish. If you're really sure, your soul will tell you."

"How will my soul tell me?" asked Mikoto, giving Emma a confused head tilt.

Emma grinned. "It'll find a way."

"For now, her potential has disappeared," said Senbey, perching itself onto Emma's shoulder as Mikoto made her way back to the transport drone. "Do you think you did the right thing?"

"I think so," said Emma. She was standing on the roof again, watching Mikoto walk back. "A wish is too important to just make up. You shouldn't have any regrets if you're making a wish, especially at a time like this."

"Very well," said Senbey. "Still, if her potential returns, she wants to make a contract later, and you are not available, I will accept her wish. She knows what a contract entails now."

Emma sighed. "That's fair, I guess. Thanks again, Senbey."

"Of course."

15. Pressing Onwards

The convoy moved out, slowly at first to keep the civilians from sliding around, but quickly gaining speed.

"This is… a little exposed," said Motya over telepathy. She glanced about uncertainly as their transport emerged from the exit tunnel. The vehicle jostled them as it went over the lip of the ramp, causing a few of the smaller children to lose their balance.

"It is, yeah," said Emma. She cast a look up at the buildings around them. "Well, it's like Alanis said. Keep an eye out."

Vira gave Motya's arm a little squeeze, before the two of them went to opposite sides of the transport to keep watch. Emma stayed where she was, standing in the middle of the transport. Hopefully, she'd draw the fire from anything that wanted to kill them. There were problems to this plan, of course, but the other option was to leave the civilians exposed. This way, she hoped, she could at least buy some time for the civilians' emergency mode to activate.

Emma's HUD beeped and updated, feeding into her brain directly. Emily had passed their first checkpoint, and hadn't seen anything. Sensors hadn't detected anything except for the usual random atmospheric artifacts.

Emma sighed. This was always the annoying part of missions. If things went well, the mission would be incredibly boring and nothing would happen, but the tension made her restless. She could see Vira fidgeting as the younger girl kept an eye on the surroundings. Motya seemed to have her nerves under control though.

"You're awfully calm," Emma commented to Motya over teamcomm.

"Ah, it's just part of what's expected where I come from," said Motya. "Keep still and don't fidget even if you're nervous, I was always taught."

"What'd you need ta do that had you nervous?" asked Vira. "Goin' ta all those parties can't have been that stressful."

"Well you would expect that, wouldn't you?" said Motya with a patient sigh. "But for me, parties were never so much a place to have fun so much as a place to make more contacts."

"Yeesh, Lieutenant," said one of the soldiers. "That sounds terrible."

"It was not the best, no," said Motya. "But, well, at least I did not suffer alone or needlessly. My lab's PI had to go too, and he hated it with a passion. Would have much rather been writing science postings."

"From what Anna tells me, research funding these days comes mostly from publicity?" asked Emma.

"Yes, but it also depends on the nature of your research," said Motya. "You see, development of wine varietals hinges heavily on being able to move your product after development. As a result, it is important to…"

"Say, senpai, what're we doin' after this?" asked Vira as Motya continued talking with the others in the background. "Are me 'n Motya gonna be attached to yur unit for awhile?"

"One step at a time, Vira," said Emma. "Focus on the task at hand. I'm not sure though. We'll get more orders later."

"M'kay," said Vira, falling silent. "...Senpai, what're we gonna do after it's all over then?"

"Eh?"

"Like, one of these days, me'n Motya are gonna be good enough to run our own platoons right?" said Vira. "What happens then?"

Emma was quiet for a moment.

"Well, you two need to go to training first, you know?" said Emma. "Proper training, I mean, instead of this rushed stuff. You'll go and do well on all the practical stuff, and, uh, I don't know what after. But we'll stay in contact, yeah?"

"O' course," said Vira. "It's just, well..." She trailed off, leaving her thoughts unsaid.

A report from the second checkpoint propagated through. Emily had passed the checkpoint without any issues, sensors still coming back clean. Emma's platoon passed the first checkpoint as well, sending back the same result.

The complete lack of activity was mildly disquieting, if Emma was honest. It was to be expected, to some degree, but the last time this had happened in the sims, the company had been blasted by an artillery barrage. A cloaked team of squid Airborne had called it in clandestinely, and the only warning had been some-

"Getting some white noise on the sensors," one of the soldiers in Emma's platoon said.

-white noise.

"Huh, that's weird," said another soldier while Emma hurriedly compared her memory to the current reading. They formed a clean match. "I guess Military's-"

"BRACE FOR IMPACT!" Emma shouted. Her magic flared, throwing out a dome of wind as she-

-crashed to her knees, brilliant blue-white fire cascading over her shield. The transport tilted as another flash of light blanked out her vision. She could hear screams and tearing metal as vertigo suddenly took hold, black dots dancing across her vision as implants adjusted and-

-she landed on her side, instincts shouting at her as she struggled to her feet. The implants in her retinas reset her vision and flicked to partial ultraviolet. Young and old lay scattered about her as mortar fire began to cascade downward. The transport abruptly slewed left and avoided an inbound mortar. Each body was flagged with red, purple, and blue as an IFV pulled in to-

-immediately be skewered by an intense beam of ultraviolet light.

"Get into the basement and stay there!" Emma heard herself shouting as the first civilian began to come out of shock-induced fugue. Their implants had already kicked into emergency mode. "We'll cover you!"

The civilian nodded wordlessly, already helping up one of her neighbors. More IFVs roared in, laying down suppressing fire with their autocannon while Emma pushed up a barrier of magic and dust around the civilians.

"It's locked!" someone shouted.

Emma spun with a snarl of frustration, then punched an air jet into the nearest door, caving it in and letting the civilians run inside. She shifted the barrier to get better coverage. Just a few more and-

-another explosion, consuming one of the IFVs. Shit, shit, where was-

-there-

Fire lit the upper floors of the buildings on the opposite side of the road. Emma pulled the wind around her as a glittering shower of polyglass rained onto the platoon. Breath in, breath out, go up-

-and through-

There was a bright flash as Emma's magic bit into cephalopod shields. The alien fell backwards as Emma crashed through the window and into the room. Another flash, then the crackle of failing shields as her halberd broke through and punched through armor plate. A step forward to-

-spin in place and blast an attack drone through the wall before-

-lashing out with a foot to shatter the squid's knee, step forward, pull the halberd back out to-

-decapitate another drone, then swing her weapon's blade back around to remove the squid's head.

"Emma, we're inbound to your position!" Varsha called out over telepathy. "Get into cover and hold out for a bit longer!"

"Understood," said Emma.

"Local area network online," noted her TacComp.

"Lieutenant, we're holding out in the buildings, what are your orders?" one of the sergeants said immediately.

"Fall back, I've got you covered," said Emma, the air around her suffused in blue light. She shifted her weight, then stepped forward, halberd ready, and-

-punching through two walls into another squid, breaking its shields immediately and sending it crashing to the floor. With a scream, Emma launched herself forward again to ram her halberd through its skull. The crack echoed as she spun, magic wreathing her in a halo of blue light and before a-

-detonation blew out the windows on that floor as Emma pushed out and away, ripping through walls and floors to knock the entire platoon of cephalopods down.

"Unload on the building, don't stop until it's rubble!" Emma shouted, then flew upwards through the new atrium to land two floors up. Two drones flew at her and were swiped out of the air. She stepped forward and-

-burst into the air as shells from her platoon's autocannon streaked past and time slowed, her senses kicking into overdrive as the projectiles flashed past glowing red hot and missiles began to launch, their payloads of thermobaric explosives primed. She only had a millisecond but it was-

twist to the right, boost up and out, get space

-just-

now left, forwards, dodge the missile by the tip of a skirt

-enough to get her clear, spin around, and form a shield as the face of the building erupted into fire. She rode the shockwave on her magic, letting it push her back to the same side of the street as her platoon.

"Everybody, move up!" Emily called out. "They got us flanked, but we have the-"

Emma didn't have time to scream before she felt herself hurled through the air, electricity crackling off of her as a Reaper's laser cannon ripped electrons from the air from its sheer power. There was a distant snapping sound, and she felt her body jerk twice, before stopping hard against something. The BattleNet was alive with shouting, soldiers trying to coordinate something as the squid made another push.

"It's another offensive!" someone cried out. "We can't hold this position! Fall back to the train station!"

"Second platoon, fall back," intoned Timaeus, his voice smooth and mellow over comms. "Squad One and Three, screen Squads Two and Four as they move. Leapfrog maneuver towards the train station. Keep spread out, I don't want to see any squads get blasted by a mortar strike. Lieutenant Sinclair, can you read me?"

Emma blinked twice before she remembered that was her name.

"Y-yeah I- I can read you," said Emma shakily. Her TacComp was spooling through another laundry list of damaged systems. Fuck. "I… I think I'm alive."

"That's good," said Timaeus. "Can you move? I can route someone-"

"NO," said Emma forcefully. She was thinking more clearly now, and her gem's corruption was increasing gradually. Thank the Goddess for her training and instinctively trying to heal herself. "No, I'm going to be fine. Get everyone out of here, nothing's going to notice me right now."

"...Sir, that's not-"

"I can catch up, I have the skills, just move," said Emma. She couldn't feel her legs, which probably meant that-

-FUCK-

-her back was no longer broken, but Goddess that had been painful. And it didn't even actually work, all she'd done was re-fuse the vertebrae magically so that she wouldn't topple over.

"We'll wait for you on Fifth and Eighth," said Timaeus firmly. "We'll meet up there. Here's the marker."

The blip appeared on Emma's vision as she shakily climbed back to her feet, using her halberd as support to-

-fall back down again as a massive explosion shook the building. Emma felt it tilt. The building was collapsing, shit, she had to get out or she'd-

-see Mina Guyere teleport in reach her arm out to grab Emma's and-

-land a moment later in the train station within a ring of medical personnel.

"What-"

"Hold on," said Mina, before teleporting out again.

"But-"

"Lieutenant, get out of the receiving area!" shouted one of the soldiers.

Emma jumped, then moved as quickly as she could, reaching the ring of medical personnel as Mina reappeared, carrying one wounded soldier and accompanied by two more. A medical drone slid up, just high enough for Emma to collapse back onto. A handful of grief cubes extended from her backpack's arm, tapping against her gem.

"Emma!" called Motya, pushing her way through the assembly. She conjured a bottle of vodka, pushing it into Emma's hands. "Are you alright? Here, the net says you are injured."

"Thanks," said Emma, grabbing the bottle and throwing back a slug. "How did we turn out? Are the civvies okay?"

"We- they're mostly fine," said Motya, swallowing. "They didn't all make it, but the ones who did are okay."

Emma nodded. "Good. How many casualties?"

Motya swallowed again. "U-um, thirty-two percent."

"That's good," said Emma, smiling slightly then taking another drink of vodka. "Better than in the sims."

"B-better?!"

Emma blinked, looking up at Motya. The younger girl seemed close to tears.

"We did the best we could," said Emma, putting her hand on Motya's upper arm and gripping tightly. "We did the best we could and that's all we can do."

"R-right," said Motya. She took a shaky breath. "S-sorry."

"Don't be, we've all been there," said Emma. She paused to swallow more vodka and winced as she felt her vertebrae pop back into place. "Now go on, help out. Things'll be alright." She slapped Motya on the shoulder and pushed her towards the medical teams.

Motya forced a brittle smile and nodded. "Right!"

Emma sent her off with an encouraging grin, before sighing deeply and rubbing at her face.

Gah. This sucked.

No time to lose. Emma hopped off of the medical drone and hurried towards the upper decks, where the trains pulled in and most of the defenders were gathered.

The only reason for an ambush like this was if things were happening, and "things happening" usually spelled bad news. Judging by the scale of things, it was likely a renewed offensive against the human lines. Updates filtered in, telling her that her platoon was being rescued piecemeal, but quickly enough that nobody was suffering any casualties. Emma's extravagantly violent response to the ambush had given her platoon enough breathing room to extract smoothly.

"Heads up, incoming rounds!"

Emma ducked as an explosion rattled against the side of the train station. Dust fell from the ceiling as she ran. She skidded to a stop at the bottom of a stairwell and jumped up, dodging a drone and landing neatly atop a passing soldier's complement of attack drones.

"Hello," Emma said politely, nodding at the startled soldier, before jumping onto the railing overlooking the interior of the train station.

The station was packed with people. The station had four levels, standing over two hundred feet tall and serving eighty platforms all across its elliptical circumference. Wide polyglas panels normally let light shine in, but were now boarded over with large slabs of ablative plating and ceramic. Lighting for the building was instead provided by brilliantly glowing fluorescent lights.

The civilians were moving as quickly as they could onto the trains, the soldiers among them helping wherever necessary. Emergency mode was activated, keeping people calm and casting the massive complex in eerie quiet. Emma saw Mikoto near one wall, clutching the teddy bear close.

Right then.

"Vira, how you holding up?"

"Alright," said Vira, her voice tight with stress. "I'm ah, helpin'."

"Helping where?" asked Emma, looking up at the jumphook lines that stretched across the central ring. The bottom floor had been given over to stacking food and ammunition.

"Up top, snipin'," said Vira. "I'm-"

"Incoming!"

Another explosion, making Emma wobble on the railing and the jumphook cables swing. Mikoto tripped with a small yelp, and was helped up.

"Damn," Vira muttered. "Got somethin' in my eye."

"The civilians-"

"Yah I know," Vira bit back. "I don't wanna talk about. Now what d'we do?"

"Stay up there, I'm coming up as well," said Emma. "So're B Company's magical girls."

"Right, the update," said Vira. "Okay, don't go where I'm-" a small dot appeared on Emma's HUD where Vira was "-hiding, I just found out I can go invisible and you'll ruin it by showin' up."

"Okay," said Emma, waving a hand perfunctorily and making the building appear transparent on her HUD. The situation outside appeared, with soldiers taking their positions as blue plasma cascaded down. The fire of those dead and burning in the distance lit up the skyline.

A beep. Emma turned, following her HUD indicators to spot Varsha, Rebecca, Ayane, Renee, and Tracy as their forms raced across the top of the nearby buildings. Emma contacted them on telepathy.

"Varsha, you're better than me at this defensive stuff. D'you have a plan?"

"I wish," said Varsha. "Nothing to do but attack. Sensors are down outside the station, and clairvoyant support is spotty at best. Everyone's stretched thin trying to keep the front from collapsing."

Emma sighed, then jumped upwards, swinging around one jumphook cable to gain momentum and launching herself up towards the ceiling and onto a ledge.

"Alright, then the same as we did in training, right?"

"Sounds good."

"Alright. Tracy, how're you holding up?"

"I'm fine," said Tracy, voice a little shaky. "I've never fought alone like that before."

"Are you okay? Did you do alright?"

"Yeah, yeah, I'm fine! It takes more than that to-"

The outer lines flashed, a crackling pillar of light descending from on high and carving a path into the defenses. Rippling explosions ran down the line as the infantry was abruptly engaged in bitter combat, cephalopod armored suits flickering in and out of sight as they blasted and shot their way in.

"Cut the chatter, enemy located!" Varsha yelled. "Everybody go!"

"Renee, the firestorm!" Emma shouted, running out a window and leaping off the building. She coasted forward on wind currents, gaining height. "Let's light 'em up!"

"With pleasure!" Renee called back. Her silhouette flickered with light, as the team of magical girls swung around, sliding into a standardized combat formation. Tracy and Varsha led the way in, with Rebecca hanging back and Renee in the middle. Ayane zoomed up, disappearing into the low-hanging clouds. Updates reported that the attackers were Shock Troopers. How very typical.

A wave of return fire. High explosives briefly halted the squid advance. Opportunity called.

"Now!" Emma yelled.

Renee's fire lashed out, splashing against the ground and licking at squid shields. Shock Troopers were well trained, and they organized to-

aim for the center, knock them over like bowling pins

-fly through the air as Emma slammed into their center. Fire roared around her as she tugged at the air around her, spinning it into a maelstrom of flame that shorted out shields and scorched armor plating.

"On your three o'clock!"

Emma jumped upwards with a gust of wind, letting the fires go out as Varsha and Tracy ripped into the enemy flank. Varsha's shotguns roared, the bass counterpart to the treble clangs of Tracy's blades. The Shock Troopers recoiled, then regrouped and began to return fire.

But this was a situation the five of them, Emma, Varsha, Rebecca, Ayane and Renee, had practiced many times in the sims. Without prompting, Rebecca's mind control swept over the field. The Shock Troopers came to a quivering halt, their tentacles twitching as they fought the alien mind keeping them still. With a gesture, the vanguard uncloaked, appearing in plain view.

"Infantry, blast them!" Emma shouted across the Battlenet.

The defenders responded dutifully. Rockets and railguns roared, smashing against enemy forms and creating blooms of fire that Renee stepped into, coaxing to greater heights.

"Ayane, what are you waiting for?" Renee asked.

The flyer's voice on telepathy was as close to cheerful as she could get. "Just letting you have some fun!"

With a screech like a hawk fighting for its territory, Ayane rocketed into the fray. Amber light spread out around her as she slammed into the squid, shielding her from fire while she slammed home her weaponry. Emma followed a second behind, magic whirling into biting whips that, coupled with Renee's fire, turned into swirling arms of plasma, cutting apart everything it hit.

The counterattack had lasted only a few seconds, but it was a counterattack they had practiced over and over and over again.

"Ah, the good old Turn and Burn," said Rebecca, voice strained. "Never fails."

"Nothing like burning through half your gem to get results, right?" Emma asked tiredly. She slid to the ground behind a defensive plate and pressed a handful of cubes against her gem.

"No, there is nothing quite like it," Renee groaned. Emma could see her across the way, also pressing cubes to gem. "Why do we have to do all the work?"

"Hey, I did stuff too!" Rebecca complained. "And besides, getting burned alive hurts!"

Emma winced. "Sorry Rebecca."

"Yes, sorry, that was inconsiderate," added Renee.

"Aw, guys, it's whatever, don't worry about it," said Rebecca. "Just-"

Emma whirled, halberd coming up and deflecting a plasma cutter before it removed half her skull.

"What-"

A concussive blow to her midsection, sending Emma flying.

"EMMA-!"

Emma flipped to her feet, snarling as a burst of wind sent the squid attacking her flying back.

"It's the second wave!" someone called out on TeamComm. "Get me more rockets!"

Varsha's telepathy was relatively calm. "Rebecca, can you-?"

"I don't -ugh," Rebecca began, but fell silent abruptly. A moment passed before she continued. "I'm sorry, I don't have the cubes."

"Okay, withdraw to the station. Emma, we need to regroup. Can you and-"

"We'll take care of it," said Emma. "Renee, on my six! Ayane, over top!"

"Got it!"

"Ready!"

"Let's go!"

The world blurred, then sharpened as combat implants kicked in. Lasers burned across Emma's body as she closed in on the nearest enemy.

A brief glimpse of a cephalopod helmet, then a-

-concussive blast, rippling outwards and throwing her back and up so that-

easy now, don't get cocky

-she could twist in midair and lend her magic to Renee's. A sheet of white flame bloomed across the attacking column-

ride the air currents, need more altitude

-scorching and burning shields. The column recoiled, then charged through.

Emma grit her teeth. Damn. "Ayane!"

"Clear the way!"

Emma forced herself to the ground and ducked behind cover as an amber streak blasted from the low hanging clouds, ripping into the leading units with magical steel that punched easily through armor and shields. Return fire sliced through only empty air as Ayane pulled away sharply.

More fire, from mortar shells in a series of crackling explosions. The incendiary filler glowed, hissing angrily in a white hot cascade. A gesture from Renee ignited the particles into a rippling plasma that-

turn on the spot and push forward

-Emma blew a storm into.

Swirling arcs of fire plumed out as wind met flame. Uncoiling like a great, fiery dragon, the storm clawed its way through the enemy ranks. It was a cataclysm of destruction- a swirling inferno that smothered five city blocks and lit up the morning sky like the rising sun. An ache burned into Emma's bones as she ducked behind a barrier. She was burning through cubes too quickly. They needed breathing room, just a bit to recover, or else-

"Reaper!"

The alien laser left behind a thundercrack as it scorched a second path through the defenses. Emma scrambled back as a premonition passed over her mind. She could feel her hair standing on end-

-wait-

There was a colossal bang as Misa Virani appeared beneath a stroke of lightning, the pale blue light drowning out the world and casting her in a light befitting a god. In the air, behind a veil of clouds, something exploded in a plume of flame.

"Fall back, quickly!" Misa shouted. "Get back to the station!"

Emma turned and ran. She wove back and forth, ducking behind cover as necessary. The Reaper fired again, a clap of thunder flashing overhead, ripping into the front of the train station.

"We have civilians down!"

Emma grit her teeth and ran faster. They needed to fall back and regroup, before-

-a flash of bright white light-

"Neh, Madoka?"

"Hm?"

"Are we… is this it?"

Madoka raised an eyebrow, looking over to Sayaka and licking at a drop of ice cream running down her cone.

"What do you mean?" Madoka asked.

"I mean, are we just here, forever?" Sayaka asked again. She licked her own ice cream cone and brushed a lock of hair behind her ear. "It feels weird, like we should be doing something."

"No, we're just here," said Madoka. She kicked her shoes against the red brick that made up the clocktower they were sitting on the edge of. Evening sun washed the bricks in deep orange. "You're just not used to it yet."

"I guess."

"But you'll get used to it soon," Madoka continued, reassuringly. "I remember the first time I found you just sitting here, watching the- oops, spoilers!"

"That's incredibly weird," said Sayaka flatly as Madoka giggled. "Though, now that you mention it, this is a good place to sit and think."

"See? I told you."

The two of them fell silent again.

"You're lucky," said Sayaka. She looked down at her ice cream. "I- sorry, I shouldn't be jealous. You got a chance to do something good, and you did it. You actually pulled it off. I… I guess, I just wish that…"

Madoka looked over at Sayaka. A breeze blew at Sayaka's hair. "That things had been different?"

"Y-yeah," sniffed Sayaka. "I- with Kyousuke, and Kyouko, and Mami and Transfer- Homura. And I forgot you, and then I remembered who you were, and-"

"Oh Sayaka-chan," sighed Madoka. The ice cream vanished with a small twinkle of light pink as Madoka scooted over to bump shoulders with Sayaka. "You know that none of that was your fault, right?"

"Yeah but, but I could have done something," said Sayaka, swallowing and wiping her eyes. "Ugh. I'm crying like an idiot. S'not like I can do anything when I'm dead."

"Now, that's not the Sayaka-chan I know," said Madoka reprovingly. "Aren't you supposed to be a Hero of Justice? The magical girl who would never give up?"

"Tch, some Hero I am," said Sayaka. "I didn't even manage to do anything before I died."

"It's not how much you did that matters," said Madoka. "All that matters is that you stood up and tried your hardest to make it real."

She smiled and looked over her shoulder.

"Isn't that right, Emma?"

-Emma gasped then looked around. She was lying on the ground. The world around her flickered once, twice, before stabilizing. Her HUD blinked, updating itself, radiation warnings beeping loudly.

"Warning, sensory input now rebooting."

The world cut out, before flooding back in.

"-back! Regroup on-"

"-need to find our magical girl-"

"-hty-nine percent casualties-"

A warning, buzzing against her consciousness.

Emma stood with a shout, summoning her halberd and whirling in place to crash against enemy shields. The squid struggled, whipping its tentacles at her to-

-strike air as Emma stepped forward and forced her weapon downwards. The squid flailed, off balance. Three two and push and the squid's legs buckled and it crashed to the ground. Shields flickered. The alien scrambled for cover.

"Why don't you," snarled Emma as she stepped forward, a nimbus of blue surrounding her

"just-"

She span in place, gathering momentum as magic flared.

"-fucking-"

Her halberd sang.

"-DIE!"

The squid was annihilated, blown directly into a concrete barrier and shredded with wind.

Emma paused, panting as the winds surrounding her calmed. Her HUD beeped at her, warning that she needed to take cover. Emma ran.

Everything hurt.

Nadya's voice rang out over telepathy. "Everybody, listen up! The line is breached! We must hold this position! There is no place to fall back to! We are the last defense for this sector!"

Emma grit her teeth as she jumped over and took cover behind a concrete slab. Her implants were barely responding, working their way through the protocols. A rush of endorphins made her world spin briefly.

"The enemy is advancing on all sides! We must destroy them!"

Emma took a shaky breath. She needed to remember her training. First, systems check. Emma looked over herself. Her costume was hanging off of her in ragged strands, mostly burned away. The metal parts had managed to survive, and subsequently fused with her skin, making it impossible to pull them off and examine anything.

What flesh remained was scorched and blackened. Strips of dead skin sloughed off of her, leaving burnt muscle exposed to the air. The acrid, burnt-meat smell that accompanied every instance of a failed experiment in home cooking curled through the air while blue magic flickered across her, doing its best to repair the damage.

All it did was make her feel like she was being burned alive.

"Get ready!"

Gritting her teeth, Emma flickered in and out of her costume. The fresh material covered up the burns and removed the armor plating from her skin.

"Contact, all sides!" a sergeant called out over the battlenet. "Lots of contact! I need help!"

Emma tightened her grip on her halberd. The sergeant was in a fragment of the line that had been manned by the local militia. They didn't have a magical girl of their own. But another enemy wave was breaking against the thinned ranks of the regular army's positions. They couldn't keep fighting unless they got help.

"Emotional suppression is now active," said Emma's TacComp. "Suppression level is 12%."

Varsha and Ayane were unresponsive. Their last known location was somewhere near the front, and Ayane had last been seen diving for the ground before the bomb had gone off. Vira was listed as temporarily incapacitated. Rebecca had already been pulled back to the bunker underneath the train station.

A beep. Renee and Tracy were back up. They were okay. Their status changed to "engaged".

"I need some help here!"

"Fall back, fall back!"

"Any sign of our magical girls?"

The air around Emma rippled as she breathed in. She had work to do.

"Negative, I think we lost them!"

Emma breathed out. "Don't worry, I'm here."

She jumped, winds twisting around her, pushing her forward, onwards past drones and armored figures and blocks of concrete and now flipping her over to land on-

-a cephalopod, halberd point crashing down past shields into armor and past armor into soft nervous tissue. Spinning, now, and dodging a rush of drones and laser fire and dropping a brace of vortex spheres to launch her backwards to land in a cloud of dust amongst the militia.

"Give me a base of fire along the right flank," ordered Emma. "Push them back!"

There was a small delay. A tiny amount of time, only a few seconds.

It was palpable to Emma, like a constricting syrup that weighed her down and choked her. Each second was enough for a few more drones to fall, for a sniper to get a little more settled into their position. It was a delay that could get people killed. Regular soldiers, these were not, even with the acceleration of Combat Mode.

But then the gunfire appeared at the right place and explosions crashed across the appropriate places and Emma could breath again and she was off, sprinting between tank obstacles and ripping into the enemy line. Streaks of fire tore across magically conjured fabric, drones shattered under magically conjured steel, and Emma lost herself. The battlefield shrank, from ranged, to close, to nearly on top of each other. Artillery fell silent. The lines re-stabilized.

The sun tracked across the sky.

16. Next Steps

The shower water was set at thirty degrees Celsius, coming down from directly overhead. It was a good temperature, not just for relaxing after a stressful day, but also for washing off the growth medium Emma had been submerged in to regrow segments of her body. Radiation from the nuke had caused moderate damage to her internal organs, but a bottle of vodka from Motya had helped things along tremendously.

Of greater concern was her skin and muscles. It was a relatively standard regeneration, something that most magical girls did instinctively. The difficulty arose from the extent of the burns Emma had undergone. It was ultimately easier to throw her into a regrowth tank and wait a day.

Emma breathed in deeply. The steam inside the shower stall beaded across the walls, dripping down to combine with the spray that spilled off her body. The new skin was smooth. Tanned, just a little, with the freckling across her shoulders that she'd inevitably picked up as part of implants not trying terribly hard to regulate the body's natural tendency to try and prevent UV damage.

A notification blinked in the bottom right of her vision. Emma looked at it lethargically.

"You have been in the shower for thirty minutes," the notification stated. "You have an appointment with the MHD in five minutes. Please exit the-"

Emma closed the notification and closed her eyes. The rhythm of water drumming across her skull and the walls and the floor was a continuous scattering of white noise that drowned out her thoughts and her feelings. It helped keep her from being too far into emotional suppression. Her TacComp was still keeping her around the eight percent mark.

There was a combat uniform waiting for her outside on the bench. The standard fare for a magical girl: adaptive camouflage jacket and trousers, along with a black shirt and light gray underwear. They'd had to cut all her clothes off to avoid aggravating her injuries more than was absolutely necessary, and then forgotten to have them get remade in the replicator. It was a bit annoying, and happened a lot, but nobody really complained, usually.

Well. Usually.

The bathroom was small and private, and there was no one to rush her out of the warm, quiet embrace of the shower. Emma swallowed, and watched her emotional suppression meter tick upwards slightly. No, no, she had to stop thinking about things. She needed to… to just stay there. Let the water wash down and away.

"Oi, new girl."

Emma felt her lips thin.

"New girl! Oi!"

"Shut up Emily," Emma whispered to herself.

"Well I know you're alive, so get your ass out of that fucking shower!" Emily snapped. "Y've got-"

"SHUT UP!"

The shower echoed.

A new voice intruded: "Emma, you can't stay in there."

"Abigail?"

"You need to get going, Emma," the Chaplain said. "Come on, out of the shower. The war is still on."

Emma grit her teeth. Her back hit the shower wall with a quiet thump as she leaned backwards, then sank to the floor slowly.

"Varsha, she… I…."

"I know, Emma," said Abigail soothingly. "I know. But she held the line. And we need to make her sacrifice worth it."

Worth it. Like Varsha's life had been a security, traded on the interstellar stock market. A few shares of the company known as "Governance Military". Bought and sold for a wish and a prayer. As if… as if…

"It wasn't worth it."

"It's never worth it," said Abigail. "It's always more than we gain. But it's something more than nothing."

Emma was silent.

"There's a story we tell, in the Cult," said Abigail. "You've been in combat since we last talked, so you probably haven't heard it yet."

A pause, while Abigail gathered her thoughts.

"Once, on Homura's birthday, she was sitting alone at the top of Mitakihara's highest tower. As she looked out over the city, the darkness of the world grew, rising up and reaching for her feet. Soon, Homura was sitting at the edge of a pool of shadow, her feet paddling in the icy cold tide.

The Goddess sat down beside Homura, and placed Her hand on Homura's shoulder.

"Look up, Homura," said the Goddess. "Look around you."

Homura looked, and saw a beautiful garden surrounding her. Roses in full blossom waved in a gentle breeze, spiraling upwards beside apples and peaches and cherries and other fruits besides. Towers of white limestone shone in the moon's light, from which music and laughter could be heard even here, at their base.

"Where is this?" asked Homura.

"It is the end of the road," said the Goddess. "I wanted to show you it, for your birthday. It is where we will meet again, at the end of all things."

"When will that be?"

"You will know," said the Goddess. And she smiled, and the vision ended, and Homura was sitting atop the tower once more."

Another pause.

"The story is attributed to a girl at the Ribbon who had a vision of Homura having the vision," continued Abigail. "Or more specifically, the Goddess brought the girl with Her while She went to show it to Homura. It's said to be the after-life for us, when everything is at an end."

"Do you believe it?" asked Emma.

"I do," said Abigail firmly. "The attribution checks out. Kyouko-san confirmed it herself. A vision of the after-life is the only really logical explanation. Why would the Goddess go to such lengths for a huge metaphor?"

Emma bit her lip.

"Do you think Varsha's there, then?" asked Emma. "In the garden that Homura saw?"

"I think so," said Abigail.

Emma swallowed.

"...Do you think I can still make my MHD appointment?" she asked, and pushed herself to her feet.

"Physiologically, you're healing well, so there's no worries there," said Jessica. The MHD psychiatrist looked tired. "Medical has already given you clearance for light duties. The only question is whether you're psychologically prepared."

Emma fidgeted and sighed. "I would like to do something other than wait."

"I understand that," said Jessica. She rubbed the bridge of her nose. "But it's a fine line to tread. Too much down time will stress you out, but too much work prevents you from dealing with your grief. It's unhealthy to ignore things like that."

Emma was silent.

"...I'll let you go on demon patrol, but that's it," said Jessica with a sigh. "You need to keep active, but demon patrol should be low key enough to not be too bad for you."

Emma nodded.

"Aside from that, you can't stay in your room all day," said Jessica. "You recently joined the Cult of Hope?"

Emma nodded.

"Then I would suggest talking to Abigail and seeing what activities you can participate in," said Jessica. "Preferably something that involves physical activity, I think."

"She mentioned something about a football club," said Emma quietly.

"Perfect," said Jessica. "It's something you enjoy too. I know I'm kind of forcing you into this, but try to have fun, okay?"

Emma nodded.

Jessica sighed again, then got up and stepped around the table to hug Emma.

"It's going to be okay."

"I know," said Emma. She stood up, shrugging off Jessica's hug. " Is there anything else you want to go over?"

Jessica sighed. "No."

"Then I'm going to go getting some food," said Emma. Her voice lacked warmth. "Thank you for the meeting."

There wasn't time for Emma to go all the way to the chuen and back, since the next demon patrol was in an hour or so. She could order delivery though. It'd be up shortly.

Instead Emma sat quietly at what passed for a bar in the bunker underneath the Train Station. The surface was still being hotly contested, but here, a dozen kilometers below, things were much quieter. Hence the civilians sitting nearby, recuperating after a hasty evacuation from the surface to the bunker. The bar had sprung up as a matter of inevitability.

Emma tipped back her glass of whiskey. It came back down with a clack on the polymer surface. There were no ice cubes.

"Another."

A glass, filled halfway, slid down the bar. It came to rest next to her hand. Smiling slightly, Emma turned and raised a toast to the robotic bartender, before taking a sip.

She wanted to get drunk. She'd never had that urge before. It was an interesting temptation, this need to drink. Novel. It made bitterness taste sweet, and sweet things taste overtly unctuous and disgusting.

Bah. She could see why her father enjoyed whiskey so much. Or, at least, drank so much of it. It made a warm, happy feeling in your stomach, like you were being tickled by light flames. It almost made her giggle. It also muddled your head in the most fantastic way, making it more difficult to think. Well. Not difficult really. She could think fine. She was thinking now. It was more like… it made it easy to forget.

Yeah. That was the ticket. Forgetting.

Emma tipped her drink back, savoring the sweetness and the fruity flavors and the way it burned a line down her throat before pooling in her stomach. It felt good. Not good, to be fair, but pretty pleasant, all things considered.

Maybe she should consider finding Ryouta later. Heh.

Ryouta and Ayane. The two people she really cared about. Not to say she didn't care about everyone else. But, like, they were especially important to her. Ayane was this solid rock. Sort of. Like a… a relatively hard to move boulder. She'd been burnt badly in the last fight, but she was recovering, and Emma had never had occasion to doubt her. Ayane was… well Emma still wasn't sure she liked girls, but she was absolutely sure that Ayane would be the girl she'd date. If she liked girls. But hey, that one statistic said that at least 50% of girls who professed to be straight ended up being at least a little bi after a few months as a magical girl. You… you saw things, with your fellow mages, that others didn't see. Couldn't. So maybe Emma did like girls, sort of. She'd never tried, so she didn't know.

Ryouta on the other hand was like a… like a bird. Sort of like a bird. Not really like a bird at all. But also sort of a bird. He was sort of quiet, and unassuming, and talented, and so, so cute. Like, wow. She blamed not being drunk enough for her inability at the time to kiss Ryouta properly. The sort of person that Emma wanted to hug and cuddle, on some level, but who would also be capable of doing his own thing. And had she mentioned he was cute? Because he was. So cute. Unf.

Emma giggled to herself as she took another sip. Wow, this whiskey was great stuff. A few more glasses and she'd be in great position to go do something she'd regret. Or maybe not regret. She was still pretty sure she was straight, after all.

"Emma?"

Emma blinked, then looked down.

It was Mikoto. The young girl was dressed identically to Emma. The only difference was where her unit designation would have been, on her shoulder. Emma's jacket was emblazoned with a simple triangle and the gold-thread number "two" in the center. Each corner was marked by a star, but it was otherwise plain black. Mikoto's shoulders bore a hammer in a circle, with the number eleven stitched out in black thread in the center.

"Oh, hi," said Emma, blinking rapidly as she snapped her tox-filters back on. A bit of magic kept the headache suppressed as she did a double take. "You're- um, how are you doing?"

"M'fine," said Mikoto, shifting back and forth. The uniform looked like a costume on her, something that a child would wear at some colonial festival celebrating the military. Mikoto was still carrying the teddy bear, Yokkun, around, and had it held loosely in front of her. It had been damaged at some point, and then patched across the top of its fluffy head.

"Um, take a seat?" said Emma, pushing her drink glasses to the side. "Have you eaten yet? I can get you something, if you want."

Mikoto shook her head as she climbed onto the bar stool. She shuffled around, until she was facing the bar, with Yokkun sitting in her lap. "The, um, the brigade took care of things already."

"That's good," said Emma. She bit her lip, and slid her glass from one hand to the other.

"...are you… okay?" asked Mikoto. She peered up at Emma's face concernedly.

"I'm fine," said Emma. Her glass clicked to a stop against her hand, glass rapping against the silver of her soul gem ring.

"...I'm not a little kid, you know," said Mikoto, folding her arms. She nodded at the whiskey glasses pointedly. "Adults don't drink that much alcohol unless things are going really badly."

"They're not that bad," said Emma, looking down at her whiskey. "The squid are making a push, but, well, they don't need me up there. You've seen the latest updates?"

Mikoto nodded gravely. "Spec-ops teams are scary."

"Heh," said Emma, nodding. "I guess they are."

They sat in silence for awhile.

"I guess I should ask," Emma said eventually. "Why are you alone?"

"Mum and Dad are in surgery," said Mikoto. She swallowed, leaning against the bar and trying to look composed. "They got hit by debris when the lasers hit the train station."

You're not pulling it off, kid. Sorry. "Ah. They'll pull through?"

"The doctors said they'll be fine," said Mikoto. "I-I'm just waiting now. T-they're in the queue, behind a few soldiers. They said that civilians-"

"-are lower priority," said Emma, nodding. She took a sip of whiskey. Damn. "They got you some work to do then, while you wait."

Mikoto nodded. "I didn't think I'd be useful for production, but I guess there's some things even a kid can do."

"Well, it's mostly just mandatory session stuff, right?" said Emma. "Nothing crazy. Everybody knows it."

"I guess that's true," said Mikoto. "I wish I could do more though."

"What are you doing right now?"

"I'm just pushing buttons," said Mikoto, sighing. "Troubleshooting, they call it. S'not like a VI couldn't do it too."

"Well, it frees up some computing space," said Emma. "The AIs need all they can get with the war, you know."

"I know," said Mikoto. "But it's just…"

Emma raised an eyebrow. "Mm?"

"I… I can't help but think of Senbey."

Emma raised her other eyebrow.

"You're not seriously considering it?" she asked, alarmed. "You realize what-"

"Yes, I do," said Mikoto, frowning up at Emma. "I'm not a little kid. You told me about it already, remember?"

Emma swallowed, then nodded. "Sorry."

"S'okay," said Mikoto quietly.

Emma downed her whiskey.

"So?" she asked, the whiskey glass clacking against the bar. Another one slid down a moment later. "You've been thinking about a wish?"

"Yeah," said Mikoto. "I was."

"What was it?"

"I… I guess I don't know exactly yet," said Mikoto, smiling sheepishly. "Something to do with… to do with helping more. So I'm not just some kid pushing buttons, when I could be doing more to help."

"You're doing a lot to help already, for a kid," said Emma.

"It's not the same," said Mikoto, frowning down at Yokkun and heaving a long sigh.

Emma grimaced. She downed the whiskey, even if it had no effect on her with tox-filters on. Mikoto wasn't wrong, there was very little argument to be made for assigning someone to push buttons and "troubleshoot". Or at least, Emma couldn't see it. Anybody could do that, but if you had the chance to make a wish and do more….

It was very difficult for her to not empathize with Mikoto. After all, hadn't Emma made a wish for essentially the same reason? She had been tired of all the crap in her life. Of the homework that was boring and her parents' expectations. Apart from Anna, Emma was just another person, lying around. Becoming a magical girl was the chance of a lifetime, and-

Emma swallowed heavily. Even with… everything, her regrets weren't ones about her past. Her regrets were about her present, and what she'd failed to do. Making her wish was still something she didn't regret doing. If this was really what Mikoto wanted to do, well-

"Alright then," she sighed, hopping off her barstool. She grabbed Mikoto by the shoulders and spun her around, making the younger girl squeak in surprise. From where she was standing, Emma could almost look Mikoto directly in the eyes. "Are you absolutely sure? Is… is your soul telling you this is the right idea?"

Mikoto paused, then nodded.

Emma closed her eyes and sighed, nodding to herself as well.

"Very- very well," she said. "Senbey, are you around?"

"Of course," said Senbey, drifting into place atop Emma's shoulder. "Mikoto Albright, it is a pleasure meeting you again."

"H-hello," said Mikoto, swallowing nervously. "D-do you want me to-?"

"No," said Emma. She grabbed Mikoto by the hand and pulled her off the barstool. "Come on, we should find somewhere private to do this."

"Ah, yes, it's always mystified me," Senbey commented as it swayed on Emma's shoulder. "I never understood why humans wanted their wishes to be private. I suppose it is the greatest desire you have at the time, so the emotional attachment must be strong, but…"

Emma tuned Senbey out as she walked.

"So you're in the military now, Mikoto?"

"I… I guess?" said Mikoto, glancing up from Yokkun to Emma then down again. They had passed into a section of the bunker devoted to warehousing. Their footsteps echoed across the stacks of ammunition and supplies. "I'm not trained or anything."

"Did they give you a room in the barracks?" asked Emma. She turned right, down a row of ammunition crates. The only lights came from wells embedded in the floor, no point wasting energy, and made the crate walls seem like they stretched into infinite darkness.

Mikoto nodded. "They connected two adjoining rooms. Mum and Dad are coming after their surgery, but for now it's just me."

"How long have you been doing troubleshooting? Just the one shift?"

"Mmhm," said Mikoto. She fiddled with Yokkun's ears.

"Why not do some more?" asked Emma. "See where it takes you?"

"Because… because I remembered what you told me, about keeping people safe," said Mikoto. "And I thought… I thought that, if only I had made a wish, maybe I could have kept my parents from getting hurt."

Emma stopped. She was standing between two light wells, the lights overlapping and bathing both herself and Mikoto in bright, blue tinted light.

"It's not your fault," said Emma. She looked up at the darkened ceiling. For a moment, a fraction of a fraction of a second before her implants adjusted, she saw lights trailing upwards in long streaks along long monolithic pillars. Fingers that reached up towards a night sky. Except, this one had no stars. It had no shining gems sprinkled amongst its void.

Then her implants adjusted, and the darkness was replaced with I-beams and concrete.

"It's not your fault," Emma repeated, looking down at Mikoto and swallowing. "If anything, it's mine. If we'd been better, we could have held the squids back. It's because they got a clear shot on the building that your parents got hurt."

"I… that's not true," said Mikoto. She held Yokkun closer to her and breathed deeply. "I mean, it's unfair to blame you. You can't take care of everyone."

Emma grimaced, then smiled wobbily. "That's true. I-

Varsha

-I can't."

Emma's TacComp locked down on her emotions, keeping her from crying. She swallowed and pressed back on the emotions, until her TacComp let go of emotional suppression.

"I should note that time is of the essence," said Senbey. The Incubator had been oddly quiet after it had finished expounding on why it thought humans were odd. "I appreciate the human need to socialize, but this is most certainly not the moment."

"Y-yeah, that's- I suppose you're right," said Emma. She looked down at Mikoto one more time. "Mikoto… you're sure about this?"

"I am," said Mikoto, nodding firmly.

"Okay," said Emma. She let go of Mikoto's hand, stepping back as Senbey hopped down.

Incubator paws made no noise as they hit the floor.

"Do you remember everything that Emma told you last time we met?" Senbey asked, looking up at Mikoto from its position on the floor.

"I do," said Mikoto. She still looked nervous, one hand held Yokkun at her side. The other was held nervously to her chest.

"Well, then I suppose there's very little else to discuss," said Senbey. Its ears waved. "Mikoto Albright, what wish will make your soul gem shine?"

"I wish…"

There was a flicker of green. Emma squinted, the light was startling bright, even with implants. Had her contract looked like that?

"I wish for the ability to protect those I love," said Mikoto. "That in the future, when things go badly, and it's up to me, that I won't let anyone down."

"Contract successful," said Senbey. It's ears reached forward.

Emma closed her eyes and winced as the flicker turned into a sunbeam. A blinding point, burning through the darkness of the warehouse. Emma could feel the magic, like a blazing fireball that flashed into existence and scorched reality around it.

Then the light winked out, and Emma thought for a terrifying moment that something had gone wrong, but no, it was just Mikoto taking hold of her soul gem, face alight with wonder and teddy bear discarded.

"Congratulations, Mikoto Albright," said Senbey. It closed its eyes and dipped its head, almost bowing. "Your soul has successfully reduced entropy."

17. Transitory States

Green light glimmered between Mikoto's fingers. Yokkun lay forgotten at her feet, the teddy bear discarded in favor of clutching her new soul gem with both hands.

"I… I did it," the young girl breathed. "I became a magical girl."

Something inside Emma twinged as she watched Mikoto. The look of wonder and awe on Mikoto's face, the way she seemed giddy with excitement; these were things Emma abruptly remembered feeling. It had been something like this, when Emma had contracted, back on that rooftop in Mitakihara. It made Emma smile, for a moment, as she remembered what that had been like, before her smile faded again.

"Congratulations," Emma said quietly, making Mikoto flinch slightly, but look up with a silly grin.

"T-thanks!" Mikoto said, clasping her soul gem to her chest.

"I liked your wish," said Emma, leaning back against the crates with a sigh. "Good wording, and it seemed meaningful. You're a thoughtful girl, Mikoto."

"Thanks?" asked Mikoto, looking confused. "Is… is that important?"

"Well, it can be, I guess," said Emma, shrugging. She waved a hand back and forth. "I mean, practically speaking, it's not that important. A squid's a squid, and it dies no matter what wish gave which girl her powers."

"It has been the experience of the Incubators that a magical girl is defined more by what she did with her magic, rather than her wish alone," interjected Senbey. "We, that is, the Incubator Collective, encourage all contractees to do their very best. Magic can do amazing things that even we can't anticipate! Who knows what you might accomplish?"

Emma nodded. "And also, well, I made a similar wish, and it makes me happy that my kouhai did something similar as me, I guess," said Emma. She gave Mikoto a small smile. "That is, if you're okay with being my kouhai?"

"O-oh, yes!" said Mikoto, hopping a little. "It'd be an honor, Emma-senpai!"

"Ah, jeez, don't say stuff like that," said Emma, scratching her head as she looked away with a mild blush. "Just my name's fine."

"Okay!"

"But yeah, so you're a magical girl now," said Emma, sighing and looking back up at the ceiling. "That comes with a lot of stuff you know?"

"You told me about them, yeah."

"Well, I gave you the summary, right?" said Emma. "If you're going to do this… well, I don't want to say it's a lot worse than what I said, because it's not. Being a magical girl is a big responsibility and there's a lot you have to do. But…"

Emma blinked and rubbed at her eyes.

"Ah, what'm I saying," she sighed. "Sorry, Mikoto, I'm being depressing."

"It's okay, Emma," said Mikoto, her grin fading a little. "You're more experienced, so it's natural to try and give your kouhai advice, right?"

"Yeah," said Emma, smiling ruefully. "Thanks for understanding. Why don't you transform? Let's see your costume. The process should be instinctual."

Mikoto nodded, and took a deep breath. She held her soul gem out in front of her, balanced on the palms of her hands. The crystalline structure flashed, before a bubble of green light wrapped around Mikoto, then faded.

For a magical girl, Mikoto's costume was unusually plain. It was based on some sort of rollerskater-chic theme, with a set of gossamer frills that puffed out at the shoulders but left her arms bare. Her shirt itself was made of two panels: an upper panel in pastel green with interwoven gold thread, and a lower panel in white, with a band of pink roses embroidered across the lower hem. A multi-tiered skirt, pastel green like the top of her shirt, fell in three layers to mid-thigh. Underneath that was a pair of white, loose-fitting pants that ended halfway down her calf. For footgear, Mikoto wore rollerskates, laced up over long, white socks with a pink band around the top.

The knee and elbow pads that came with the costume were of the typical sort. Each protective metal plate was painted glossy white, while the fabric holding it to Mikoto's limbs was a deep, matte black. She also wore gloves with small frills at the wrists, her soul gem pulsing green in its setting atop one hand. The final part of Mikoto's ensemble was a helmet, pastel green like most everything else, with a pair of small, brown, fuzzy teddy-bear ears affixed atop it.

"Oh Goddess you look adorable," said Emma, stifling laughter as Mikoto looked down at herself.

"I- really?" Mikoto asked, making a displeased face. "I… I look like a cake."

"The word is 'pastel', but yes, you are," said Emma, grinning.

"It's… not really very magical," said Mikoto, examining her pads and gloves. "I thought magical girls were supposed to get more… more frills?"

Emma shrugged and transformed. "I mean, does this look like frills to you?" she asked, holding out an arm. "Magical girl costumes are all different. Some of us get the usual sort, others get costumes you could make after a visit to a department store."

"I… guess," said Mikoto, still looking disappointed. "Oh well."

"What's your weapon?" asked Emma as she untransformed. "Instinctual, again."

"Right," said Mikoto, holding out her hand. A teddy bear appeared a moment later in a flash of green. "Eh?!"

Emma very carefully kept a straight face. The teddy bear was stereotypical in nearly all respects. The only oddity was a knight's helmet seated on its head.

"W-what am I supposed to do with this?" Mikoto asked, waving the bear around.

"Ah, you seem to have fallen into the Summoner class of magical girl," piped in Senbey. "Well, that classification is a human construct, and oversimplifies many, many things. For example-"

"Senbey," said Emma shortly.

"-ahem, yes, digressions aside, most Summoners use a totem or artifact, rather than a weapon," said Senbey. "In your case, I would presume that your teddy bear summons familiars to defend you."

"How do I- it's instinctual, right?"

Emma nodded. "Just take a deep breath and do what feels right."

Mikoto closed her eyes. Emma very carefully stepped away, in case Mikoto's powers turned out to summon, say, elephants. That was unlikely though. If Emma'd learned anything in her career, it was that magic tended to be very literal.

The teddy bear glowed green. With a shout, Mikoto tossed it forwards, her eyes opening as she did so. The bear disappeared in a plume of magic, before landing with a roar on all fours as a large, armor clad, brown bear.

"Whoa!" Mikoto shouted, stumbling backwards in surprise. "I- wow!"

Emma chuckled to herself as Mikoto ran forward and began to pet her familiar, cooing things at it while the bear nuzzled against her hand like a very large kitten.

"Thank you for your assistance, Emma Sinclair," said Senbey, hopping up to Emma's shoulder. "I know you were reluctant at first, but it seems to have turned out okay in the end."

"I guess," Emma sighed, crossing her arms and looking down at her feet. "I… I hope it keeps working out."

"There are many things that can happen," said Senbey. "If I were capable of emotion, I would say that I am very excited about everything that has happened so far! It is excellent data."

Emma snorted. "Yeah. Sure."

The moment stretched, then began to waver. There was much to do, even if Emma didn't want to do it.

"Mikoto," said Emma. "Listen, I'm happy for you, but there's something you need to know."

Mikoto paused, looking up at Emma. "Yes?"

"You… you're young, so we're not going to send you straight into combat," said Emma, sighing. "The minimum age is thirteen. But we're fighting a war on a core world. If… if things go badly, you're going to need to fight. Do you understand?"

Mikoto swallowed. "Y-you mean, against the squid?"

Emma nodded.

"O-oh," Mikoto said, voice small. "I… okay."

"I'm sorry," said Emma. "I wish it wasn't like this, but… but it's what it is."

"It's okay," said Mikoto, rubbing her bear's nose before dismissing it. "I should have thought about it."

"It's not your fault," said Emma. "These are just realities we have to face, okay? What's important is that we keep moving forward."

Mikoto stood quietly for a moment, before nodding. She looked up at Emma. "What do I do now?"

"Come with me. We're going to get you some weapons."

"Ayy, ladies, it's the greenie!"

Emma winced as the Black Parade piled out of the armory, conglomerating around her in a small cluster of noise. Mikoto shrank back, hiding behind Emma.

"What a coincidence," said Nodoka. "How's it been Emma? Heard you newbies got some serious action."

"Y-yeah," said Emma, forcing a small smile. "We took a few casualties, but we held the line."

Black Parade collectively paused.

"Aye, we know what you mean," said Agapita, patting Emma on the shoulder. She flashed Emma a quick smile before stepping back. Emma swallowed, and managed a smile back.

"You just got of medical then?" asked Agapita, changing the subject as gracefully as she could.

"Yes."

"Another mission already?" asked Maria. "It's a bit soon for you, isn't it?"

"Oh, uh, no, I'm here to get Mikoto here some weapons," said Emma, gesturing as she stepped aside. "This is Mikoto Albright. She just contracted. Mikoto, this the MagOps team 'Black Parade'. They rescued me after some… things happened, in the initial battle."

"Um, h-hello," said Mikoto, bowing quickly. "It's nice to meet you!"

"Oh, hello," said Mia. She reached out and patted Mikoto on the head. "Congratulations, and welcome to the MSY."

"You're planning on taking her on a few demon hunts, Emma?" asked Maria. "Or do you have other plans?"

"Ah, no, I was going to do demon hunts first," said Emma. "I was thinking she should do a few sims too, so the demon hunts will be necessary for the calibration data."

"Oh yeah, cool," said Maria. "What're your powers, Mikoto?"

"Um, I summon bears," said Mikoto.

"...Seriously?"

"Yes," said Mikoto. "I uh, yeah. Bears."

"Oh man, you have to show us sometime!" said Agapita. "That's awesome!"

Mikoto blushed. "T-thanks."

"So what's your mission?" asked Emma as they began to walk back towards the Armory. "If you're pulling weapons, it has to be pretty long term?"

"Yeah, we're doing an infiltration and interdiction mission deep in enemy territory," said Agapita. "There's an airstrip way out back that's being used to ferry large scale supplies. Command wants it taken out, along with a few dozen other locations."

"You have backup for this?" asked Emma, raising an eyebrow. "I've seen that airstrip on the maps, it's near the edge of the mountains."

"Nope," said Maria. "We're all counting on Mia here."

She slapped Mia on the back. The girl grunted. "Yup."

"We're hoping that the mission'll be canceled, if we're honest," said Agapita. "Rumor on the Grapevine says that three whole fleets are due to hit the squid fleet and wipe them off the planet."

"Um, then, why have the mission at all?" asked Mikoto. "Wouldn't it be better to wait and see?"

"Maybe, but not this time," said Nodoka. "Sometimes it's better to wait, but sometimes you have to plan like there's no backup coming. The wider battle is more precarious than anyone would like, so we're going in, even if it's alone and without backup."

"That sounds so dangerous," said Mikoto, eyes wide. "You'll really be okay?"

"It's similar to an operation we did in the Soul Guard," said Nodoka. She switched to telepathy as the group dispersed, going off to pull their own weapons. "Infiltrating territory controlled by rogue magical girls is nothing new, and running deep into enemy territory is similar in principal. Easier, even, since they're unlikely to have the same level of firepower. We have sims for this sort of thing, so that newbies like Agapita-"

"Hey!"

"-can learn the basic tactics necessary for success."

"Newbies like Agapita huh," said Emma. She huffed a small laugh, making Mikoto glance up at her. "What does that make me and Mikoto?"

"Girls who should focus on the present," said Mia. "Do not worry too much about the future. Concentrate on the things you need to do right now."

"Yeah, yeah," said Emma, clearing her throat. She tapped a panel. "Right, sorry, got distracted. Mikoto, this is your pistol…"

Black Parade's mission was canceled.

Mami Tomoe's Second Fleet of the Euphrates had indeed appeared, along with two auxiliary fleets full of Magi Caeli. Within twenty four hours, all major orbits about the planet Samsara had been reclaimed by the human fleet. Orbital bombardment, by way of kinetic kill vehicles dropped in to smash into things at Mach 7, wreaked havoc on Cephalopod positions for the next three days. By the end of the bombardment, the city of Helsinberg had been returned completely to human control, and mopping up operations were the only relevant tasks to do.

The city's buildings were still being combed for booby traps and stray munitions, but people were back out on the streets, recovering from the stresses of being in a warzone. Bars, the ones that had survived, were open, their patrons spilling onto the streets in a disorderly pile of humanity, laughing and talking amidst the rubble and burn marks and shattered storefront facades. More than a few were probably off in a sheltered corner of the city with someone, or multiple someones, having a more private sort of celebration.

Not, of course, that Emma was doing any of that at the moment.

"Mentor, huh?" asked Ayane.

Emma nodded. The sheets of Ayane's bed had the crisp, undisturbed appearance of having just been changed. Ayane had suffered more damage than Emma had, and only just been decanted from her regrowth tank. A nominally problem-free procedure, Ayane was still being held in Medical as a precautionary measure. Mikoto had gone off, now that the war was over, to get her implants adjusted.

Emma kept her eyes averted, watching Ayane shift her legs under the sheets.

"Well, I guess it worked out," said Ayane. "If Mami-san's fleet hadn't arrived…"

"Yeah, that would have been bad," said Emma, sighing. She glanced up at Ayane. "I… I don't want to think about having to get her trained up quickly, just in case things went badly."

Ayane nodded. "This way, she can get some decent training in before going into combat for the first time."

"I'm thinking… I'm thinking about bringing her back to Earth," said Emma.

"Really?"

"Yeah, it was the first thing I thought of, after Mikoto's contract," said Emma, sighing. "I live in Mitakihara, after all, and there's Kyouko-san's church there too."

"Do you want to convert her?"

"No, but it's a really big concentration of magical talent, you know?" said Emma. "The more talent you have around you, the better you can grow. I've been thinking about moving there myself."

"Oh. I see."

A short pause.

"You should ask her about it, obviously," said Ayane. "I mean, she'll probably want to visit Earth, but you know."

"Yeah. I should ask her parents too."

"They'll probably be-"

"-less enthused, yes," sighed Emma. "Ugh, why did I decide to do this?"

Ayane chuckled. "Well, it's what it is now."

"When are you getting out?" asked Emma, glancing up at Ayane.

"Within the day."

"There's going to be a thing on the roof, did you get the message?"

"Oh, yes, I did. Are you going?"

"Yeah. I figure it'd be good to get Mikoto to socialize with some other magical girls."

"What about your combat team?"

"Ah, uh, well," said Emma, looking up to meet Ayane's eyes briefly before looking away again. "They're… not well."

"Stress?"

"Yes. The MHD says I should keep my distance for a bit. So I invited them to the- to the memorial, and hopefully they'll feel good enough to come with."

Ayane sighed, then nodded. She pulled her knees up to her chest and leaned on them, looking at the wall sadly.

"Do you ever wonder what would have happened if the squid had never attacked?" Ayane asked. "How we would have lived our lives?"

"I'd have never have met you," said Emma. "Well, maybe. Mitakihara's pretty close to Osaka. Might have done a senior trip out there."

"Heh, maybe," said Ayane. She pushed a lock of hair behind her ear. "Maybe not."

They were quiet for a moment.

"You know, meeting you guys," said Emma. "You and Renee and everyone. It's been important to me. I wish it were in better circumstances, but I don't regret becoming a magical girl."

"You don't, huh," said Ayane quietly. She looked up at Emma. "No regrets? None at all?"

"Not about my wish, no," said Emma. Her hand reached out to grasp Ayane's. "Not about my friends."

Ayane smiled slightly, then turned her hand to squeeze Emma's. "Yeah. Thanks."

Emma nodded. "Don't mention it."

Ayane's CubeBot clicked as it shifted on her nightstand, extruding a single grief cube as it tucked away another one, already filled to capacity.

"I've been thinking about things," said Emma. "I… I was thinking about… about us."

"Us?"

"You remember, back when I got rescued?" asked Emma. "And how everyone was making jokes?"

"O-oh, yeah," said Ayane. "About us being a couple."

"I was thinking that… that I wouldn't mind that," said Emma. "Um, maybe. I've- I have no experience at all in this, so…"

"I- Emma you- t-this," stuttered Ayane. "I can't- I mean I would, but, with Varsha-"

"I'm just, um, expressing interest," said Emma quickly. "I… well, I've- there's a boy I'm also interested in, but we haven't moved forward on anything, so-."

"So I have competition? Or is it- oh Emma." asked Ayane, giggling. "I s-see how it is! You're greedy."

"Wha- no!" protested Emma. "No that's- dammit Ayane!"

Ayane laughed, holding tightly to Emma's hand as her laughter became tears.

"I- Goddes Emma you have such terrible timing," said Ayane, wiping at her eyes. "V-Varsha's just died and you're here trying to get me in bed."

"I don't-"

"Hush, I get it, it's fine," said Ayane, smiling at Emma. "S-sorry, I'm just a mess right now." A deep sigh. "You told this boy that you'll talk about it later, right?"

"Yeah."

"Then the same with me, okay?" said Ayane. She pressed Emma's knuckles to her lips once, then let go. "We'll figure this out, somehow, after this is all finished."

Emma took a steadying breath, then nodded.

"Alright."

"Beer?" asked Ryouta. He held a bottle out to Emma.

"I'm fine, thanks," said Emma. She smiled up at him. "Join me?"

"Thanks," Ryouta set the bottle aside as he sat down next to her on the edge of the roof. They, with a few other magical girls and soldiers, had gathered there for something of a post-war celebration. It was technically a bit premature, but the wounded and psychologically unstable weren't going to be pursuing the remaining ceph forces.

The arrival of Mami's Second Fleet had brought with it a massive influx of reinforcements. Most of the beleaguered defenders of Helsinberg, and across the entirety of Samsara, were on leave while the newcomers, mostly veterans, finished the job. It was, finally, a chance to rest, and many of them were taking full advantage of that.

"Are you doing alright?" asked Ryouta.

"I'm fine."

"I, uh, heard about-"

"I'm fine, Ryouta."

Ryouta licked his lips and sipped his beer. "Alright."

The sun was setting over Helsinberg. The sun was behind them, casting long shadows across the city as the towers reached up, high into the sky. In the distance, orbital defense cannons fired out long streams of fire as they shot down decaying fragments of cephalopod warship. The shattered ruins of the city's outer reaches lay in a blackened and burnt state of rest, almost undulating as drones, seen from a distance as a great metallic wave, moved over them to effect repairs.

"Have you been getting good photos?" asked Emma.

"Yeah, it's been really productive," said Ryouta. "My editor says that I just got one of the biggest scoops anyone my age could ever hope to get. We're putting together an entire photodocumentary about this."

Emma smiled. "Good for you. You're getting a big step up then."

"Yeah. It's… I owe a lot to you, honestly."

"Hm? Why's that?"

"Well, you remember how I asked to install an image capturing app on your implants?" asked Ryouta. "You have some spectacular footage. After the nuke, especially."

Emma's smiled faded a little, but she tried her best to look happy for Ryouta. "Ah, well, I'm glad I could be of help."

They went quiet, watching the steady rain of deceased spaceships. Streaks of fire ran across the sky. Some terminated in a flash of light, like they had burst apart and shattered under a terrific blow. Other, smaller pieces, burned until there was nothing left, fading away before they reached the surface.

Not one made it to the ground.

Behind them, the celebration continued relatively quietly, but with a few small dots of noise. Mikoto, chattered away with some of the younger girls. A few people raised toasts, to friends dead or otherwise. Their glasses clinked.

Emma turned as she heard the lift door open.

"Ah, Ayane, over here," said Emma, waving. "They finally let you out."

"They did," said Ayane. She made her way over, sitting down on Emma's opposite side. "Who's this?"

"Ah, sorry, I forgot you two haven't met," said Emma. "Ayane, this is Ryouta. He's been sort of attached to my unit as a member of the press. Ryouta, this is Ayane, my roommate from training."

Ayane glanced between Emma and Ryouta, brow furrowed as she nodded in greeting to Ryouta. She sent Emma a message on telepathy.

"Have you mentioned anything to him? About you and me?"

Emma flinched. "No?"

"Now might be a good time."

"Really? Are you sure?"

"I think so."

"Erm, so, Ryouta," Emma said out loud, turning. "We were um, going to talk about some things about us, right?"

Ryouta nodded cautiously. "This seems like a bad time," he said.

"Ah, well, yes, normally, but uh, Ayane has uh, expressed interest."

Ryouta raised an eyebrow. "I see." He turned his gaze to Ayane. "Really?"

Ayane nodded.

"I see. I'm not surprised, I guess," he said. "We'll have to see how it goes."

"You're okay with this?"

"You're not officially dating anyone yet," said Ryouta. He put his beer down and leaned back on his hands. "Besides, there's a lot of stuff we all need to deal with. None of us should make any big decisions right now."

"Oh," said Emma. "Oh, uh, well, good. That's a relief."

"Mm," said Ayane, nodding. "We'll just have to see, later, when we're not dealing with… everything." She sighed, then turned to smile at Ryouta. "Good luck, okay Ryouta? May the best man win."

Ryouta nodded, grinning over at her as best he could. "Same to you."

18. Intermediate Steps

"It's too bad that we can't do this in person," said Sarah Johansen. Her hair seemed a little less curly than when Emma had seen it last, and it had been tied back into a bun. "I know I haven't been doing much mentoring, but deployment schedules throw a few axes into the works, so to speak."

The blonde haired girl took a sip of virtual white wine. Ancient, 21st Century Paris stretched out behind her, behind plate glass windows and under a soft, early evening sun. The simulation was of Le Jules Verne, the restaurant situated one hundred and twenty-five stories up the Eiffel Tower. Around them, the white table clothes and glittering cutlery sparkled as men and women, dressed in evening finery in preparation for the opera or somesuch, ate and drank. Sunlight glinted off of crystal and china, sapphires and diamonds.

The sunlight glinted off of Emma's soul gem too, the ring gleaming brightly from her middle finger. A beam of sunlight passed over the table at an angle, swathing the ring in gold before illuminating Emma's oeuf en gelee, the poached egg a dark shadow within the clear, amber aspic it was suspended within.

"I understand," said Emma. She raised a spoon and cleaved her egg in two, the unctuous yolk oozing onto her plate. Her cutlery clinked as she her spoon swooped again, cutting off a section of egg and transferring it to her mouth. Wow, that was actually shockingly good. "Things… didn't work out."

Sarah nodded. "It was quite frustrating, preparing as I was while I knew you were fighting on Samsara. I'm sure I could have helped you somehow, but your status kept flickering between being in medical or actively on a mission."

They both ignored the part where Emma had been listed KIA.

"And now we're on the same planet, but I'm off on the opposite side," said Sarah, sighing as she too cleaved open her oeuf en gelee. She paused, before laughing slightly and looking up at Emma. "Well, that's the Military for you, right?"

Emma nodded. The silence stretched awkwardly as Sarah paused, expecting Emma to say something. When Emma's commentary didn't materialize, Sarah cleared her throat, setting her spoon down to break off a section of bread.

"So, erm, I hear you've been leading some new girls in combat?" asked Sarah. She dabbed at her egg yolk with a piece of bread. "How has that been for you? Stressful?"

Emma shrugged. "They're avoiding me after the last battle."

"I see," sighed Sarah. She raised her wine glass, the crystal bulb passing through a beam of sunlight. The curved bottom of the wine glass refracted the light up and around, illuminating the pale yellow liquid with a shock of deep, sunset-yellow. Emma blinked as the reflection off the curvature passed over her eyes, then ate another spoonful of egg.

"The first deployment is always hard," said Sarah as she set down her wine. "Even more so than usual for you. Most girls aren't put into leadership positions like that so early in their careers. From my research, your team did exemplary work. Just getting everyone through unharmed is an accomplishment, but contributing significantly to the battle is shockingly good. You should be proud."

"I got a citation in my file," said Emma. "For leadership 'above expectations'."

Sarah smiled encouragingly. "That's good! It feels like nothing you do is significant sometimes, doesn't it? But the citations are at least acknowledgment that you did something."

"I guess," said Emma. She took a long drink of wine.

A pause.

"I heard… about your friend," said Sarah. "I'm sorry."

Emma shrugged again.

"It's fine," she said, cleaving off another section of egg. "I'm dealing with it."

"It does get easier, with time," said Sarah.

"The MHD said so too."

Emma looked down at her plate and the yolk oozing across its surface. She set her spoon down with a clink, then pulled a piece of bread off of the baguette on the table.

"I've, um, also begun mentoring a new contractee," said Emma, wiping the yolk towards the center of her plate with her bread.

"Really?" said Sarah. "That's unexpected. It's a bit early for you."

"Yeah, it is. I uh, her parents were in surgery when she contracted. I haven't had a chance to talk to them yet."

Sarah hummed, taking a sip of wine.

"It's a difficult business, to be sure," said Sarah. "You're too young, I think, to really be prepared to go into that conversation. But on the other hand, you've seen more combat than most girls your age. You know what the risks are."

Emma swallowed. "Yes, I do."

"Well, it's up to you," said Sarah. "The MSY has a lot of auxiliary services for this sort of thing. Many girls don't make a contract with a witness, much less another magical girl. You're a particularly unusual case, to be honest, and so the MSY has a lot of girls trained to do the Big Speech. You could ask one of them to do it for you."

"I want to do it myself."

"I had a funny feeling you would," sighed Sarah. She shook her head. "Very well. Then the key is to tell the truth. Nobody wants to be lied to in a situation like this, even if the truth hurts."

Emma cocked an eyebrow. "Really?"

"Yes," said Sarah. "At least, not in your case. You don't have the training to pull off deception."

"Ah."

"After that, your TacComp should be able to pull up the information you need on the spot. Just be prepared to field a lot of questions, and don't raise your voice. Speak calmly and professionally, even if they yell at you. Try and avoid using emotional suppression."

Emma nodded. "Is that it?"

"Yes."

"Huh, well-"

Sunlight refracted through the Emma's wine glass as she raised it up. The light danced across the skin on her neck and face before tipping over and spilling past her lips as she drank. It shrank by half before Emma set the glass down again, Sarah raising her eyebrows.

"-I suppose that seems reasonable."

"All of this is, again, available in the pamphlet I've given you," said Emma, wrapping up her short speech to Mikoto's parents. "That concludes all the material I have prepared. Do you have any questions?"

Mikoto's mother spoke: "Will she be safe?"

Emma's TacComp kicked in emotional suppression briefly before she marshaled herself. Carefully, Emma made sure to keep her eyes fixed on Yumi Albright. Mikoto's mother was impressively stoic about the situation.

"Yes ma'am," said Emma, prompts sliding across her vision. "The MSY will-"

"No, stop," said Michel Albright. Mikoto's father was more visibly distressed. He was holding Yumi's hand very tightly. "We know you have a prompter that's feeding you lines. What is your answer to the question?"

Emma looked down at her knees. She fiddled with the hem of her costume, pulling it down across her leggings. The fabric shifted back.

"No, she won't be," Emma said. She looked back up at Mikoto's parents. "Being a magical girl is… it's volunteering to fight. Even if you don't realize it at the time. People get hurt in fights, that's just how it is."

"Did Mikoto…?" began Michel, before he stopped and swallowed thickly.

"I tried," said Emma. "I wanted to make sure she knew. I- only time will tell if I did a good job."

They were all silent for a moment.

"I suppose that's all we can expect," said Yumi. "How old are you, Ms. Sinclair? Fourteen?"

"Yes ma'am."

"You seem older."

"Thank you, ma'am."

"You were our escort on the way to the train station. Thank you for keeping us safe."

Emma smiled deprecatingly. It came out as more of a grimace.

"Thank you ma'am, but I would hardly say we kept you safe."

"Still, if you hadn't been there, we would be dead rather than where we are now," said Yumi. She gestured at the room they were in.

"My wife is right, Ms. Sinclair," said Michel. He sighed deeply. "Do not underestimate your contributions. Every bit goes a long way."

"Well, thank you then," said Emma. "For your compliments. I'm not sure I deserve them, but it is appreciated nonetheless."

"You are welcome."

A pause.

"There is one more thing," Emma said. "I was hoping to bring Mikoto to Earth with me. I live in Mitakihara City, which as you know is also the headquarters of the MSY. I think that being close to all the talent in Mitakihara would be good for Mikoto's development, as a magical girl."

Mikoto's parents looked at each other, before nodding.

Emma nodded.

"Of course."

A week passed.

"Alright, this'll be a pretty standard demon hunting patrol," said Alanis. She ran at the head of the column, Emily just behind her. "We've got plenty of girls, so nobody take any dumb risks. We've got one newbie today, so try to watch out for her."

Mikoto bit her lip as she hopped onto a jump cable and slid along it on her rollerskates.

"Don't be nervous," said Emma. She kicked up and swung herself onto the next rooftop, not breaking stride. "Just do your best."

"R-right," said Mikoto.

Emma sighed quietly. Ayane zoomed by overhead, banking wide to zig-zag across the patrol's path. Tracy and Renee were on the patrol as well. Rebecca was not. Motya was working in Medical now, and Vira was working along the fringes with the ranged DPS team.

Vira and Motya had, from all reports, integrated well into their specialties as magical girls. Tracy was doing a little less well, but her abilities were more general-purpose. Late in the last battle, Tracy had pulled a cannon from somewhere and shot a squid with it, so there was certainly a lot of potential for the future.

"Emma," said Renee, dropping into place beside Emma as they ran. "It has been a while since we last talked."

"Ah, sorry, I've been busy."

"I can see that," said Renee, glancing at Mikoto. "You've decided to mentor a new contractee then? Are you sure that is a wise decision?"

"No," said Emma.

Renee laughed. "At least you are realistic."

"Well, all things considered, probably best if I don't give her my suicidal tendencies, right?"

"Heh, yes," said Renee. "Though you seem to have ended up alright this time, despite everything that happened in the simulators."

"Yeah, it's not been so bad," said Emma. "Only about 30% casualties. Compared to how things could have gone…"

"Yes, we've been fortunate," said Renee. She sighed. "Still, it doesn't…"

They fell silent.

"How is Rebecca?" asked Emma. "I should have been talking to her but, well, I… yeah."

"She is… coping, slowly," said Renee. "The MHD has her under observation, but they have not needed to do anything drastic yet. I think she will be able to come to the memorial."

"Good. I've been thinking about where to have it."

"Ah, yes, myself as well."

"Have you heard about Mangzhua Chuan?"

Renee looked thoughtful.

"Hm, interesting choice. From my research, it used to be a mining town, and has since turned into a manufacturing center, yes?"

"That's the one," said Emma, nodding. "It's a bit of a uh… well I guess 'hick town' is the best way to put it-" Renee laughed "-I know, I know, but it's got these really great mountains on the outskirts, and I figured we could go to the top of one of those for the memorial."

"I like it," said Renee. "We should also-"

"Contact, miasma, 3 klicks northeast," called out Ayane.

"Clairvoyants, deploy," ordered Alanis. "Ayane, stay on overwatch and prepare to support clairvoyant operations. Everyone else, form up into your functional groups."

"We'll talk later," said Emma, patting Renee on the shoulder once. "Mikoto, you're with me."

"R-right!"

Mikoto proved highly effective at corralling demons.

"Clear!" Mikoto called out as she landed on a roof. She had two bears summoned, stoically withstanding barrage after barrage of demon lasers.

"Roger that. All units, fire at will."

The demons vanished in a barrage of weapons fire from the ranged support teams.

"Good work, newbie," a veteran said as she ran past. "Y'got good instincts."

"T-thank you!"

"Check your gem kid," advised another. "You good on cubes?"

Mikoto blinked and looked down at her gem. "Um, I'm not sure? It's not that dark…"

"Yeah, okay, you best get some more then. Who's your-"

"I'm on it," said Emma, landing beside Mikoto. "No worries, guys. Here, Mikoto."

Mikoto nodded at Emma in thanks as she took the grief cubes. "Whew."

"You alright?"

MIkoto smiled at Emma tiredly as the corruption wisped out of her gem. "I'm fine. It's a lot of work, demon patrol."

"It is, yeah, but you get used to it," said Emma. "Magical girls don't actually need to feel tired."

"Huh?"

"Yeah, you get trained in it. It's important for longer fights, when you can't really get cubes on demand."

"That's amazing!"

Emma smiled and patted Mikoto's head. "C'mon, let's get going. People will be waiting."

Vira's rifle cracked. It was a comforting sound.

"You're doing well," said Emma, coming to a stop beside the younger magical girl.

Vira glanced at her and smiled very slightly. "Yeah. Thanks."

"You doing alright?" asked Emma. "MHD said you needed some time alone."

"Yeah, I'm good," said Vira. "Just, you know, that last fight was pretty brutal."

"Mm."

"I guess not for you," said Vira, taking aim at another demon. She breathed out, paused, and fired. The bolt clicked as she worked another cartridge into her rifle.

"Well, sim time helps, yeah," said Emma. "I've died a few times already, so it's not so scary."

"When the Reaper blasted the buildin', I didn't have time to think," said Vira. Her voice wavered slightly. "I just jumped. I was lucky I didna get killed."

"Mmhm."

"I- it was really close. I was scared."

"Well, you'll be going to training after this right?" said Emma. "You'll be prepared next time."

"Yeah, I guess," said Vira. She aimed, then frowned slightly when another magical girl got the demon before she could.

"Listen, we're having a memorial for a few friends who died," said Emma. "I was wondering if you wanted to come too? You didn't really know them, but well, the memorial's already sort of generalized. If you wanted to remember anyone who you knew, or just the city, it'd be fine."

"Ah, thanks, but I-" said Vira, before her breath hitched. She coughed, then cleared her throat. "Sorry, bug. But yeah, I've actually signed up for rebuildin' duty. Gonna be workin' to get the city repaired and stuff. Every bit helps, aye?"

"Yeah," said Emma, nodding carefully. "Well, us Earth girls will be flying out pretty soon after that, just as soon as the military finishes its own ceremony. I'll see you at the starport?"

"Oh yeah, o' course," said Vira. "I'll pass it along to Motya?"

"That'd be good, thanks," said Emma. "I'm planning on asking her after this patrol, but it'd be nice."

"Yeah, no problem," said Vira. She readied her rifle again. "We best get back to work though."

"Yeah, see you around Vira," said Emma. She jumped, and dived into a cluster of demons with a flurry of wind.

Emma jumped upwards, a cannon shell whistling past and crashing into the group of demons. She braced against the air, then blasted in with a cacophony of wind. The demons, still reeling from Tracy's cannon blast, disintegrated before her.

"Thanks," said Emma, jumping back to cleanse her gem. "That was good timing, Tracy."

"No problem," said Tracy. She jumped back as well, the gap filled instantly by first one of Mikoto's bears, then a magical girl neither recognized.

"You doing alright?" asked Emma, grief draining out of her gem as she crouched behind a bit of wall.

"Yeah," said Tracy. She breathed deep, then sighed. "Yeah, I am."

"You sure?" asked Emma. "You sound-"

"I'm fine," Tracy snapped. She immediately recoiled and sighed. "Sorry. I didn't mean it like that. I just need more time."

"Alright," said Emma, looking away. "I get you."

They were quiet a moment.

"I saw her die," Tracy said eventually. "That's why it's hard for me. Varsha got burned really bad, and there wasn't anything I could do. She-"

"Please, don't," said Emma quietly. "I- I can't. Please."

"Sorry."

"It's fine," said Emma. She reached over to pat Tracy on the shoulder. "Don't worry about it. Just, make sure to talk to the MHD about it, okay?"

"Yeah."

"Good. Let's-"

They both jumped as a demon appeared behind them, phasing through the floor. The laser burned through the air, clipping Emma, before Tracy stabbed it through the face with her sword. Emma kicked a vortex sphere into the demon's gut a moment later, and it disintegrated into grief cubes.

It had taken a fraction of a second. The demon was dead before they hit the ground. Emma stumbled as she landed, her leg gashed by the laser beam. Nothing she couldn't deal with though, it just needed-

"Um, Emma," said Tracy, pointing. "Your uh, your arm."

Emma glanced down, and sighed. Of course.

"Alright, that's all for today," said Alanis as the patrol approached the train station. "You're all dismissed to whatever else you need to do."

"Tch, just like you to get hurt on a patrol like this, new girl," said Emily as she poked at Emma's stump. "Ya friggen live through a nuke, and then this shit happens."

"Yes, yes, I love you too Emily," said Emma, rolling her eyes. Tracy had been shooed away, eventually, along with assurances that it wasn't her fault. Emily had ended up being Emma's temporary caretaker as a result, and was pushing her towards Medical. "Can I get a kiss to make it better?"

"Ah fuck you, new girl," said Emily, slapping Emma upside the head. "How the hell have you been though? Heard you lost a friend."

"I did, yeah," said Emma, swallowing. "But you know. Coping."

"Yeah, I know," said Emily. "Alanis is getting promoted again, did you hear? She's going off to be a battalion commander."

"Really?" said Emma. "Damn. What about you?"

"Ah, well, Alanis pulled some strings, so I'm going with her," said Emily, blushing slightly. "Got the promotion and everything last night."

"Damn," said Emma. She raised her good arm in salute. "Congratulations, Major."

"Oh shut it," said Emily, tipping Emma over on the invalid sledge. Emma yelped, before Emily righted her. "No more of that shit, got it?"

"Yeah yeah," said Emma, grinning. "But seriously, that's a big jump."

"Well, there's a lot of reorganization that needs to happen," sighed Emily. "Fatima's been reassigned to a different army group entirely. I think she's light infantry now? They're probably still trying to figure out what to do with you, and the weird combined arms battalion we're part of right now."

Emma nodded, taking a deep breath. "I- yeah. We'll have to see right?"

"Yeah."

They were quiet for a moment.

"Say, uh, about the Memorial," said Emma. "I… I was thinking that it might be best to have separate ones."

"Yeah, no, I was going to mention if you didn't," said Emily. She sighed. "You don't… well I've talked it over with Alanis and Fatima. Don't feel obligated to come for Mei Ling and Qing Duo. You need to take care of your own first, and, well, yeah."

"I want to come though," said Emma. "If you don't mind, I'll at least make an attempt."

"Of course," said Emily. She patted Emma on the shoulder. "If you can make it, we'd love to have you. Mei Ling and Qing Duo would be touched."

Emma smiled. "Yeah, alright. I'll try and be there."

"Cool," said Emily. She slapped Emma on the back, then turned to go. "Right, well, I've got some stuff to take care of. See you around."

"Bye Emily."

"Ah, sorry Emma, but I'm on rebuild detail too," said Motya in the small examination room she and Emma were in. Out of costume, she looked frazzled and worn, and had taken to wearing a medic's jacket over her civilian clothing. "I won't be able to make it out to the memorial. Scheduling issues."

"No worries," said Emma. She set down the bottle of vodka Motya had made for her with a quiet sigh, the magic already sparkling around her stump. "Are you doing alright? We haven't talked in awhile."

"I'm fine," said Motya, waving Emma off. "I didn't mean to ignore you all this time, but well, we've had a lot of patients in Medical."

"Ah. Civilians?"

"Yes. It's been… It's been busy."

The younger girl looked away. Emma patted Motya on the shoulder. "Hey, it's okay. Don't worry okay? Helsinberg will be alright."

"Y-yeah," said Motya, sniffing. "Sorry. I've just been having a hard time. A-and the vineyard got wiped out, so my family has to rebuild all of that from s-scratch."

"But you still have your data, right?" said Emma. "You have a starting point."

Motya nodded, and steeled herself. "Yes, we do. But I'll be going off to training, of course, and unable to help. Still, my parents know what they're doing."

"Yeah. It'll be fine. Governance is doing a lot of economic stimulus stuff too."

"Mmhm. How about you though? You shouldn't be getting hurt in demon hunts like this."

"Oh this?" asked Emma, waving her freshly-regrown arm. "Nah, this is normal. Lots of girls get accidents like this."

Motya gave Emma a look.

"I'll be more careful in the future?"

Motya sighed. "Well, I suppose that's the best anyone from Medical can expect from anyone else," she said. "When are you flying out?"

"Just after the military's memorial ceremony," said Emma. "They schedule them pretty tight, it seems."

"Alright, well," said Motya, taking a deep breath, and then sighing. "Well, I'll make sure to come say goodbye." She smiled at Emma and made a shooing motion. "Now get going, I have other people to see."

Emma nodded, smiling back. "See ya."

The stars were pretty.

Emma hummed a tune to herself as she weaved through the outskirts of Helsinberg, walking along the remains of the elevated railway. She had a bottle of whiskey in one hand, and was using the other to keep her balance. It was a good whiskey, though a bit more oakey and bitter than she found she liked. Although if she had some sweet vermouth, it could be good as a mixed drink. And some ice. And a twist of lemon.

Eh, well, good enough for now.

Emma took a swig from her bottle and looked back up at the stars. They were pretty. Quite a lot of them were moving across the sky, the light coming not from fusion but from reflected light or engine emissions. The really bright one was Mami-san's flagship, the HSS Georgy Konstantinovich Zhukov. It was moving relatively slowly, but it was also on a larger orbit than the others.

Mami-san's arrival had really been just in time. Based on the news from the fleet, Mami and Erwynmark had attacked just as a second wave of squid ships were beginning to move towards Samsara. There had been a certain degree of luck, possibly involving a wish somewhere, that had let them crash directly into the enemy logistics fleet. The battle fleet had then gotten pulled out of position, and Erwynmark had just enough room to create a counter attack that had crushed enemy resistance. All in all, a fine bit of maneuvering. Word on the Grapevine was that there was an offensive planned, to breach cephalopod territory.

Emma shivered. She hadn't volunteered, and nobody had asked. Sarah was also being left behind. Apparently they wanted to have a good deal of reserves, though Erwynmark was discussing that with high command.

"Either way," Sarah had said. "You probably won't be going. You're far too young to be more than cannon fodder, and we need another generation of magical girls to survive."

It was true that thirty-percent was a stunningly low number, in terms of casualties. Very early war figures had been in the high eighties, and only recently had the casualty percentage dropped, on average, to the low forties. In fact, if you did the math precisely, Emma's original unit assignment had lost two of six magical girls, and the last engagement at the train station had resulted in only one fatality out of eight magical girls. Eight very, very new magical girls, for that matter. You didn't need a degree in Statistics to know how those odds went.

Emma swigged her whiskey again. It was kind of amazing that they'd managed to do anything at all. A reasonable expectation would have been…

Hm.

Emma paused, staring up at the stars, then down at her feet. She unzipped her jacket, uncomfortably warm, and flapped the sides up and down. Her undershirt was a little damp from the sweat, and the breeze was pleasantly cool.

Another drink.

Frankly speaking, the reasonable expectation was for them all to have died. Emma was supposed to be dead, reasonably speaking, after that walk back from the IFV. Reasonably speaking, so was Tracy. She'd been astoundingly lucky to get shot right in front of Emma. If it'd been out of reach of a magical girl, Tracy wouldn't have been able to get her emotions under control fast enough to survive. Motya would have been in a better place, being a support girl, but Vira could easily have gotten killed early in the fighting. In fact, with Vira's personality, it was probably expected for Vira to have died. Somewhere, Senbey was probably giggling over the "data" on the matter.

Or, well, whatever the equivalent for Incubators was. Incubators didn't giggle.

Still, they weren't dead, so that was something. And Helsinberg was mostly intact, which was another thing.

"But why me?" Emma called out at the stars. "I'm the one who keeps dying in simulations! I'm the one who's supposed to be gone by now. It doesn't make any sense!"

She took another swig from her bottle, and then a second. Fucking Goddess. What the hell was the big idea? It wasn't as if she was particularly special. She didn't deserve better treatment than anyone else. It wasn't-

Emma tripped, tipping off of the tracks and falling towards a pile of rubble. Training and instincts kicked in, and Emma landed on her feet, in costume, on top of the rubble.

Damn. There went her buzz.

The whiskey bottle shattered against a distant wall, Emma's snarl of anger echoing in the deserted buildings. She'd been having a relatively pleasant evening up till now.

Muttering to herself, Emma wandered into the ruins.

19. Lights on a Mountaintop

Increasingly, Emma found that her parents were not the sort of people she thought they were. On the one hand, yes, they'd been incredible jackasses and forced her out of a career in football. On the other hand, they had really good taste in music.

"Oh, but, you're loooove-ly," Emma sang quietly to herself as she stared out the window of her compartment. It was raining again, though nowhere near the downpours that had been a staple of combat. This rain was natural, a result of the planet's normal weather patterns. Slightly acidic, due to the volcanic activity in the area, and hitting the window with quiet rattling that faded into background noise against the ancient, ancient music Emma was playing in the room. A small glass of water sat on the side table beside her elbow, while a basket of grapes reclined nearby. "With your smile so warm, and your cheeks so soft, there is nothing for me but to-"

There was a knock on the door.

"Come in."

"Hey," said Ayane quietly.

"Hey," said Emma. She turned slightly, and nodded at the seat across from her. "What's up?"

"Not much," said Ayane. She sat down, and smoothed her skirt. "Wanted to talk."

Emma gave Ayane a once over. She was wearing a black turtleneck, the fabric hugging her body just enough to make the curve of Ayane's hips and breasts stand out, while not becoming vulgar or flashy.

It was funny how, now that Emma had decided to think about dating Ayane, that she was starting to notice the things that made Ayane attractive. And here she was, thinking that she'd always been straight. Heh. Whoops.

"What did you want to talk about?" asked Emma, looking back out the window. "Have some grapes, by the way. They're good."

"Aren't they just replicator grapes?" asked Ayane, taking one out of politeness.

"I fiddled with the settings," said Emma. "Motya gave me some ideas."

"I see."

Ayane bit into the grape, then blinked.

"Huh. That is pretty good."

"Told you," said Emma, smiling to herself. "I think I might fiddle with settings more in the future. It's turned out pretty well this time."

"Yeah," said Ayane. "You should show me some time."

"Sounds good."

They were quiet again. The music kept playing, switching to a new track.

"Fly me to the moon, let me play amongst the stars…"

"I still can't believe you listen to this sort of stuff," said Ayane, leaning against the table and smiling slightly. "It's so old."

"It's really good for when you're drunk," said Emma. "Whiskey tastes better when listening to cheesy love songs."

"Are you drinking?" asked Ayane, alarmed.

"Nah, this is water," said Emma, pushing the glass to Ayane. "Sniff it."

Ayane sniffed.

"Well, fair enough," said Ayane, pushing the glass back to Emma. "But you shouldn't drink so much."

"Eh."

"...other words, baby kiss me…" sang the musician.

"Have you ever kissed someone?" asked Emma abruptly.

"Huh?" asked Ayane, flushing. "W-what are you asking?"

"Have you ever kissed someone?" Emma repeated. "I'm curious. I never dated anyone in my team, and dating other players was always a bad idea, and civilians never interested me. Then I was being too angsty to date anyone. Then I became a magical girl."

"O-oh, well, I um, sort of?" said Ayane, blush dying slightly. "Ahem. It was one of those uh, puppy love things. You know, childhood crushes. But we kissed a few times, before we both lost interest. I'm still good friends with her, actually."

"Ah. Always been a lesbian?"

"Yes. Well. As sure as you can be when you're eleven, heh."

"Heh."

Emma ran a finger along the top of her glass, staring thoughtfully at the rain.

"I kissed Ryouta already," said Emma. "Well. Ryouta kissed me. It was kind of a spur of the moment thing. And then we ignored it completely, because of work reasons."

"Oh. How was it?"

"It was really brief. He kind of ran off. But it was kind of nice too."

"That's good. I wonder if Ryouta's ever dated anyone."

"I'd expect so," said Emma. "I mean, rich kid in a rich family, right?"

"I hear that being a male in those families is kind of problematic," said Ayane. "You get pressured to marry a magical girl and stuff."

Emma frowned. "Really?"

"I mean, it's just what I've heard on the grapevine."

"Hm. I'll have to talk to Ryouta about that."

"Mmhm."

"But you're not interested in boys at all?" asked Emma. She took a sip of water.

"No," said Ayane, shaking her head. "I can be friends, obviously, but nothing romantic or sexual."

"Huh. That's too bad. It'd be easier if you could date Ryouta too."

Ayane laughed quietly. "Heh, well, yes, but unfortunately…"

"Yes, yes."

Another song started.

"A summer wind," sang the musician, "came blowing in, from across the sea…"

"It's kind of crazy, all of this," said Emma. "If you take a moment to think about it."

"It is."

Emma sighed.

"Have you talked to Rebecca at all?"

"Yes. She's doing about as well as you'd expect."

"I feel like I should be talking to her more."

"She says she wants to be left alone," said Ayane. "We, well, we can't do that, obviously, but you don't need to talk to her."

"Still."

"We could go see her if you wanted?"

Emma looked down at the table. "...To tell you the truth, I don't want to."

Ayane reached out and grasped Emma's hand. "It's understandable. You don't need to push yourself. Rebecca doesn't resent you for it."

"No, but I should go see her anyway. Maybe for lunch?"

"Sure, I'll send her a message. We can go together."

Emma nodded. "Thanks, Ayane."

"You're welcome."

"Hey Rebecca."

Rebecca looked up from the pile of paper stars she was folding. She was dressed in a conservative black dress accented with white lace. Her hair had been pulled back, with an amethyst hairpin pushed through to accent.

She looked like she had aged, somehow. Her brow was very slightly furrowed, and wrinkles pinched at the corners of her eyes. It wasn't as if she'd actually aged, because of course that was impossible. They'd never been taught that in training. Something about Rebecca's voice, the way she looked at them when she greeted them, and the way she sat at the table spoke of a great weight that Emma had only seen in those much, much older.

"Hey Emma, Ayane," she said quietly. "What's up?"

"Not much," said Ayane. "How are you doing?"

"Alright," said Rebecca. She returned to folding paper stars. They were small, only as wide as a fingernail and each a different color. At the end of the table was a paper lantern, colored purple and about the size of a football, with the bottom sealed shut and filled a third of the way with paper stars.

"What's this for?" asked Emma as she and Ayane came to sit across from Rebecca. The table added another section to its end.

"It's a tradition in my colony," said Rebecca. She tucked the tail of her star into its back, then held it up to inspect it. The small, five pointed structure was tightly wound, its shape slightly lopsided due to being made by the hands of someone not quite practiced, but getting much better. It was a light, pale pink, and very slightly glowed. Special paper then, no doubt pulled from a synthesizer somewhere specifically for the occasion.

Satisfied, Rebecca dropped it into the lantern, then pulled another strip of paper towards herself and began folding another star. "Back when my planet was first settled, we were a scientific colony studying extraterrestrial weather and applications of weather-based energy harvesting."

She paused, looking out the window. A wind picked up briefly, raindrops hitting the window like a scatter of pebbles. Emma glanced over instinctively, as all humans did when something loud occurred nearby, then turned back to Rebecca, who finished folding her star, and put it into the lantern. The paper strips rustled as she pulled another one towards her and began to fold.

"The planet was extremely stormy," continued Rebecca, turning the paper over and crimping the paper, "and just on the cusp of what was considered survivable at the time. The economy started around the science stations, which were focused around the sea, and there were a lot of problems with people being lost at sea when the weather came in fast and hard. The founders started emulating an ancient Earth tradition of hanging lanterns outside your door, the idea being that your loved ones' soul would see the light and come home to you."

Rebecca paused, blinking quickly, and wiping her eyes. Emma and Ayane pretended not to notice.

"Of course, there wasn't any point putting actual lights in them, so everyone did it a little differently. It was all a bunch of hooey nonsense, of course, and they all knew it, but it helps people feel better. In the end, the Governance decided that the casualties figures were getting too high and offered to move everyone, but by then the founders had gotten attached and didn't want to leave. Governance let them stay, after making the weather less extreme, and here we are now."

"This is for… for Varsha."

"Yes. I-" Rebecca sniffed and wiped her eyes again "-was going to combine it with this old Chinese tradition, of burning money for the afterlife? The idea was that by burning it, the soul would receive it in the afterlife, and be able to spend it as they needed. So I t-thought, you know, since the lantern was supposed to help Varsha come back to me, by burning it, I'd symbolize l… l-letting…"

She smiled self-deprecatingly up at Emma and Ayane.

"Well, I'm not doing that good a job, am I?"

"They're very good stars," said Ayane. She smiled comfortingly. "Though, well, we were wondering if you've eaten yet?"

Rebecca shook her head, wiping her eyes. "I've been concentrating on finishing this."

"Well, we won't arrive for a while. Why not take a short break?"

A worried frown. "But then I might not finish in time."

"We'll help you," said Emma quickly. "Just, you know, taking a break is good for you. Just some lunch."

Rebecca looked uneasy, but nodded. She pushed the lantern and the paper strips towards the window. Rain water dripped down the window, passing behind the lantern and disappearing. Inside of the lantern, each little star glowed faintly, their light not quite bright enough to overcome the light of the compartment's overhead lamp.

They ordered their food in silence, Rebecca alternating between staring at her hands and staring at the pile of paper strips. Ayane gave Emma a worried look.

"Here, why don't you teach us while we wait for the food?" said Ayane. "We don't have to stop just yet."

"Okay," said Rebecca, jumping at the chance. "So, see, you start by doing this…"

Mangzua Chuan looked radically different from Helsinberg. The city was historically a center of production and manufacturing for the region, and this showed in its architecture. Outside the window, pipe after pipe whipped past in a seemingly endless matrix that stretched off into the distance, the bright lights that followed the pipes lighting up the night sky and the clouds hanging within it. Each cone of light gave glimpses of drones flitting back and forth between stations where humans in protective clothing monitored and tailored the feed of reagents and buffers and other things into the clustered reactors, visible every few kilometers as tall towers or squat silos or both together, mixing and creating the chemicals that drove humanity onward.

The rain had stopped, water droplets vibrating back and forth on the window of Emma's compartment. She ran her fingers through Ayane's hair as the latter slept, cuddled into Emma's side. The lights had been turned off, leaving the compartment lit only by the bright yellow-orange industrial glow of the lights outside, reflecting off the dense, low hanging layer of clouds or shining through directly in a harsh, glaring beam that made Emma's implants shift first one way, then the other, adjusting to the ever changing light.

Emma and Ayane had left Rebecca to her folding. They had helped fill the lantern nearly to the top before leaving. Rebecca had thanked them, but asked to finish the last ones alone. It seemed important to her, so Emma and Ayane hadn't questioned it, and returned to Emma's compartment to watch a vid. Ayane had chosen a vid that was a little happy, a little sad. Something to distract them from what happened in the last few days.

The last time the two of them had watched a vid together, Emma had fallen asleep. This time, it was Ayane who ended up sleeping against the other girl midway through the vid. With half of the audience not present, Emma had paused the vid and turned it off, instead contenting herself with watching the scenery go by. The quiet made her contemplative, and, just a little, want a drink.

It was strange though, having Ayane here. Being with her quieted the urge to have a drink, made forgetting about the bad memories easier. Maybe it was because Ayane was easy to focus on, her chest rising and falling slowly as she slept, and her breath moving quietly through her nose and mouth. It was the only sound in the room, apart from Emma's own breathing.

There was a knock on the door.

"Who is it?" Emma asked over text, not looking away from the window.

"It's Agapita."

Emma raised an eyebrow, unlatching the door and letting Agapita in. "What are you doing here?" she asked telepathically.

"Ah, I'm heading to Mangzhua Chuan for some team things," said Agapita, closing the compartment door behind her. She cast a wary eye over Ayane, and stuck to telepathy as well. "Celebrating the end of major combat operations and such. You're um, going to a memorial then?"

"Yeah, I am," said Emma. She sighed quietly, running ther hand through Ayane's hair. "Though, there's another one that I won't be able to make. How'd you know I was here?"

"Ah, I was going to send you a text, but then your status said you were on the way to Mangzhua Chuan, so I figured I'd check the train's passenger list, and so here I am."

"Ah, makes sense. What did you want to talk about?"

Agapita shifted uncomfortably. "I'm not gonna lie, I don't really want to have this conversation. Let's put it off a bit. How is your family?"

Emma held back a laugh. "They're fine. They're happy I made it through and that the fighting's over. Anna, my sister, found an internship, and her mentor is apparently pretty cool."

"Ah, that's right. Your family is one of the partners in Hashimoto and Sinclair."

"Yes. Anna's looking forward to helping out in the family business."

"Not you though?"

"I'm a magical girl," said Emma. "I'm a soldier who protects humanity from death and invasion. HSIS is not for me."

Agapita huffed quietly at that. "That's true I suppose."

"And how about you? How are things on your end?"

"Doing alright. My kid is doing well in school and has an internship lined up."

"Huh. I didn't know you were married."

"Yeah, it's a thing," said Agapita, shrugging. "Being MagOps makes it hard, but we'll see. I've sort of become the absentee parent that spoils the kid rotten, at this point."

Emma grimaced. "I'm sorry to hear that."

"Don't be," said Agapita. "Me and my wife are used to it by now. Cynthia, my daughter, is too, so it's… it's at least stable."

"Is your wife a magical girl?"

"No, she's a civilian. Maggie works in healthcare, specifically in post-operative care. She does a lot of experimental stuff for new surgical operations. The latest treatments they have for the military are a doozy, lemme tell you."

"She sounds like an interesting person," said Emma, smiling a little. "You're very lucky."

"I am," said Agapita, smiling back. "Thank you."

"Of course."

They were quiet briefly.

"Well, let's get this over with." said Agapita. She took a deep breath, and then looked Emma in the eye. "It's pretty big news, so brace yourself."

Emma rolled her eyes. "I just fought in a war with barely enough training to survive, Agapita. I think I can handle whatever you have for me."

"Yeah, but different situations you know?" Agapita looked more uncomfortable. "Are you sure you don't want me to wait?"

A sigh. "Just tell me."

"Alright, well. I've sort of been putting this off as long as I could, but I got your DNA results back way, way long ago."

"Ah, that's right, the time you stabbed me," said Emma sardonically. "'Won't hurt a bit', I think you said."

"It wasn't a stab it was- nevermind, the point is, the scanner finished pretty quickly, and I had it run the test a few more times just to be sure. As it turns out, you and I are related, by blood, through a few tiers of cousins."

Emma's hand paused in Ayane's hair. There was a long moment where Emma sat, frozen, looking at Agapita, before she shrugged.

"Okay."

Agapita raised her eyebrows incredulously. "'Okay'? That's it? That's all you have to say."

Emma shrugged again. "Yes."

"But- but we're related! You're part of a matriarchy! This is a big deal!"

"No it isn't," said Emma. She looked out the window, watching the lights whip by. "Not really, when you think about it. There's a lot more important stuff than being in a matriarchy."

Agapita leaned back, folding her arms and crossing her legs and turning to look at the door. She sat there quietly for a moment, thinking.

Ayane shifted in her sleep, sighing, then murmuring Emma's name. Agapita's eyes flicked from the door to Ayane, then from Ayane to Emma.

"She's dreaming about you," said Agapita.

"Apparently, yes," said Emma. She ran her fingers through Ayane's hair again.

"You know they say, when two magical girls are in love, they can feel their partner's soul gem, even when they're separated by huge distances," said Agapita. "They say that when your partner is suffering, that you can sense that from whole worlds away. A side effect, apparently, is that when you're sleeping together, your souls find comfort in each other. Your sleep is more restful, recharges you more, even if technically we don't need it."

"Heh. Are you saying that me and Ayane are in love?"

"Maybe," said Agapita. "If she's dreaming about you, maybe."

Emma shook her head, amused. "Because old wives' tales are legitimate sources of information, aren't they?"

Agapita huffed, re-crossing her legs. "Well, it's just what they say."

They were quiet again, Emma slowly running her hands through Ayane's hair and staring at the window while Agapita watched, thinking, and then saying:

"Think about it, okay? Think about it and get back to me, because it may not be important to you but it's important for me and for the Matriarchy."

"What do you want me to say?"

"What I want is for you to acknowledge the genes and join the matriarchy," said Agapita. She stood up again, stepping slowly towards the door. "What I want is to get a chance to test the rest of your family and see for sure, because HSIS is a good bargaining chip even if we're friendly with the Shizukis."

Emma raised an eyebrow, frowning. Agapita sighed again, and opened the door.

"That's what I want, but obviously, I can't make you do anything. It's up to you."

"Mm."

"And so you're aware," continued Agapita. "Since I've told you, I'm now also obligated to tell the Matriarchy my results. They will do what they think is right, which you may not like. It's nothing personal, just my duty."

"If that's the case, why not try and sell me?" asked Emma. "Besides, that seems like the sort of thing people do in situations like this."

"Because you're fourteen years old," said Agapita. She paused in the doorway, and looked back over her shoulder. "And there are more important things for fourteen year olds to be doing. Like banging their girlfriends."

Agapita was gone before Emma could react beyond flushing bright red. The door slid shut, leaving Emma with nothing much to do except stare out the window once more.

Varsha's memorial was started at one of Mangzhua Chuan's larger mountain hot springs. The group had arrived very early in the morning, well before sunrise, with backpacks containing food and firewood. They stood in a silent line, gazing up at the stepped platforms of steaming water, the lights on the road that had brought them here the only source from which their eyes could see the drip-drop water, flowing slowly over and down the rock formations to collect at the base and began a long journey to the valley below, joining innumerable other sources to form rivers, perhaps even feeding the one that flowed past Helsinberg. To one side, an inn, shuttered and silent at this time of day, collected a little bit of this flow, filling its tubs and advertising, as a matter of course, an "authentic" onsen experience.

"Let's get going," said Rebecca quietly, hitching her backpack up on her shoulders and setting off. The lantern full of paper stars glowed in the darkness, bright enough in the center to look like the lantern was lit by a candle. The multitude of colors mixed together into white, before filtering through the purple paper of the lantern.

Renee followed Rebecca, and was then followed by Ayane, with Emma at the rear. The glowing purple light up ahead swung back and forth as they walked, swing around occasionally as Rebecca turned slightly to talk to Renee. The air smelled wet, the sort of scent that wasn't really a scent, but more a feeling as Emma breathed in the warm air. It was also sulfurous and minerally, metallic almost, to the point that she could just taste something if she smacked her lips. The ground was warm too, hot enough to feel through her shoes, but getting cooler every meter they climbed up the mountain.

The sky had lightened in the far distance by the time the four of them reached the peak. The firewood was unpacked and stacked into a small tower, the space between each piece left wide and open to let air through. Rebecca glued a weight to the paper lantern, while Emma, Ayane, and Renee collected kindling. Sandalwood scented oil was poured over the wood, and then Rebecca placed the lantern on top.

"Does anyone want to say anything?" asked Renee. She was met with silence.

"I… I would, but I… I don't know what to say," Ayane managed. "It's just the four of us, after all. There's no reason to have a fancy speech."

"I'm not good at this sort of thing either," said Emma. "I'm used to… to pumping people up, you know? Not stuff like this."

"To be honest, I think Varsha would have been annoyed if we did anything fancy," said Rebecca. "She wasn't really into that stuff. Formal stuff, maybe, but too many frills were a 'waste of time', she said."

"What other sorts of things did you guys talk about?"

"Oh, this and that," said Rebecca, smiling a little as she looked down at the ground. "You know, the usual getting-to-know-you chit-chat. She… she didn't usually like it when people were hyper around her, reminded her too much of her siblings. She loved them but, well, siblings are siblings. But I was okay, apparently, because she knew how to shut me up."

The group giggled. Emma wiped her eyes.

"She liked oranges," continued Rebecca, blinking quickly and sighing a little as she looked up at the lightening sky. "And raisins. And cranberry juice. And getting up early to get some work done, because Goddess knows there was always more of it. She liked her coffee black, with just a bit of sugar, and her tea the same way. She had the most wonderful smile and the prettiest eyes. She was unforgettable, the most important girl in my life."

Rebecca swallowed, looking down again, then up to her friends.

"I'm going to miss her."

They gathered into a group hug, holding each other tightly for a long, immeasurable moment.

"The sun is rising," said Ayane eventually. "We should-" she sniffled "-we should get this lit."

Renee nodded. The hug broke apart. Renee transformed, holding up her rapier in a salute. The rest followed suit in flashes of color.

"In memory of our friend," said Renee. "A magical girl, and a soldier fighting for humanity. We salute you, Varsha Banerjee."

Her sword flashed. A streak of fire painted itself across the cords of wood, lighting the oil in a snap of heat and light. The fire spread quickly, licking across and up and down, transforming the stack of wood into a bonfire within moments.

The lantern made of purple paper, still glowing from within, quickly caught, flames peeling away the outside and consuming the stars within. Very soon, there was nothing left, save for the ashes carried away on the rising heat of the fire, flying up, up, high into the clear blue sky, breaking apart into particles of stardust and scattering with no trace, no reason to suspect, that a lantern and stars had ever been made of those particles of stardust. That something had been crafted, with care and attention, out of those particles of stardust.

That, when all was said and done, those particles, had been important.

20. Home

At the last moment, Ryouta and his editor had managed to land a show in Mitakihara to show the photodocumentary. It was not a coincidence that the other artists in the show were either magical girls, or closely related to one. He was now joining Emma and the other Earth-bound magical girls on their flight out of Samsara.

"I can't believe you have more luggage than us," said Emma, shaking her head at Ryouta's small train of mechanized trolleys.

Ryouta made a small whining noise. "It's not that much!" he protested, folding his arms huffily. "I just have my drones, a suit and a tuxedo, a bit of local wine for gifts, camera equipment, some other equipment, a few accessories..." He paused, then laughed sheepishly. "Er, I guess it is a lot…"

Emma coughed, stifling a laugh and leaning up against the wall of the starport. Their scramjet was still inbound, but the two of them had arrived early. The walls and ceiling were decorated by large murals, the signage integrated into the scenes and made to look like they had been painted on. The war had left its mark, however, and the hallways had been cleared out of potted plants or benches. The overhead lamps had been exchanged for bright lighting rods.

"How long will it take you to prep for the show?" asked Emma.

"Mmmm, depends," said Ryouta. He put his hands in his pockets, frowning thoughtfully. "In principle, just a week or so, but Nii-san's wedding is coming up soon, and there's probably a few other social functions I'll need to attend as well."

"Oh that's right, I'm going to that wedding too," said Emma. She sighed. "Figures. I'd almost pay to avoid it, but they say your family always caters well."

"Ah, it's true that, ahem, Aunt Sayaka likes a good party," said Ryouta. "Especially weddings. She loves weddings."

"Eurgh," said Emma. "She's not going to be one of those types, is she?"

"I'm afraid so," said Ryouta, patting Emma consolingly on the arm. "It does help if you pretend you're dating someone though."

The two of them chuckled, then fell silent.

"So, um, speaking of dating," said Emma. "Do you have any new thoughts about us, since we last talked?"

"Well, in all seriousness, it would probably be to everyone's advantage if we were to be tentatively dating for the wedding," said Ryouta. "Aunt Sayaka would leave us mostly alone, it'd look like our families were getting along well, that sort of thing. I don't like the idea of having a relationship for purely political reasons, but it's useful in this case."

"What about Ayane?"

"I believe that Aunt Sayaka's policy on the matter is uh, quite liberal," said Ryouta. He coughed into his fist awkwardly and looked away, blushing a little.

Emma blinked, looked at Ryouta, then looked away as well. "W-well, that's- uh- wow."

"Well yes, precisely."

"Anyway, yes, so, that makes sense, I guess," said Emma. "Have you, uh, heard anything from the Burnside-Sinclair Matriarchy?"

"Ah, yes," said Ryouta. "Congratulations, by the way, though the separation is a bit wide."

"Uh huh," said Emma. "The Burnside-Sinclairs are going to try and go for us then?"

"That's what it looks like, yes," said Ryouta. He shrugged. "I don't know what that means for you, or what would happen if you guys refused to join. From my perspective, HSIS gets incorporated under the Shizuki umbrella either way."

Emma huffed, mildly annoyed. "That's very reassuring."

"Sorry," said Ryouta, patting Emma's arm again. "Honestly, I'm not cut out for this sort of thing. Talk to your family some more about it?"

"Yeah, I'll probably have to when we get back," said Emma. "I guess I'll just ignore it for now."

"Sounds about right," said Ryouta, smiling, before falling quiet again.

The public announcement system dinged, announcing that flight zero-four-two-nine, with service to Malabar, was on time, and would begin boarding in half an hour.

"Oh, I got promoted," said Emma. She fished a small box out of the pocket of her uniform, opening the case for Ryouta to see the set of single-bars, plated in gold, that were inside. "They sent me the new pins this morning, just as I was heading out."

"Oh wow, congratulations!" said Ryouta. "Is it official and everything?"

"Yeah, the letter said that I was one of many magical girls getting promoted, and doing a single giant ceremony was too long. Apparently, they're going to do the ceremony on the ship, once we get underway."

"Ah, I should make sure not to put my tuxedo away then," said Ryouta.

"No, no, I don't think it'll be terribly formal," said Emma, blushing. "It's just one of those things so a ranking officer can pin them on."

"Still, it's important," said Ryouta. "I do still want to date you, Emma, and it'd be a bad show if I didn't treat this event like it was important."

Emma quickly looked away, laughing a little, and feeling her insides do funny flips. "F-fair enough then."

The rest of the group got there within the next ten minutes, Tracy, Vira, and Motya appearing as they'd promised to send everyone off. Mikoto was some combination of anxious and exhilarated, having never flown on a scramjet before, while also having no small amount of fear about flying about at Mach 7. Rebecca was on a different flight, as she was going back to her colony, but was there all the same to say goodbye. Then the flight began boarding, and they had waved and then strapped in for an uneventful flight.

The next few hours were also routine. Arrival at Malabar, followed by a short trolley ride, then up the space elevator and onto the shuttle to the frigate, waiting for them in orbit. A few more minutes, and then the frigate executed its exit burn, then entered FTL. All very routine. All very quiet. Nothing at all like the last few weeks on Samsara.

The promotion ceremony came and went. It was routine, as expected, and amounted to little more than a brief recitation of everyone's accomplishments before the ship's captain pinned their new rank insignia to their lapels. Emma and Renee both made First Lieutenant, making them fully responsible for their respective infantry units. Those were still being sorted, older girls who were still on active duty having higher priority for processing than girls like Emma. Ayane was formally inducted into the Aer Magi as a member of Close Air Support, as was expected, receiving the rank of Flight Lieutenant, but being required to go through the full CAS Training Regimen as soon as she finished leave. They were all awarded a variety of badges that magical girls got after their garrison duty, a few more for participating in direct combat against the squid, and the Samsara Land Campaign Medal, awarded only to those members of the infantry who had participated in the defense of Samsara.

Afterwards, Emma found herself in the observation platform drinking whiskey again. She'd abandoned her dress uniform as soon as possible, lounging across a sofa with her tox-controls, and shoes, off and staring up at the FTL shell overhead.

"Are you drunk again?" asked Ayane, poking her head over the top of the sofa.

A small pause. "Yes," said Emma definitively. She sipped from her bottle, then raised it in salute. "Yes I am."

Ayane tutted disapprovingly. "Give me that," she said, stealing the bottle, then immediately taking a slug. "Fwoo, wow, that's strong."

"Heh, you like it?" asked Emma. She scooted to one side, giving Ayane some space to sit down.

"It's not bad, actually," said Ayane. She swung herself over the sofa back, plopping onto the sofa with a small grunt. "Kinda sweet?"

"Yeah," said Emma. Ayane's waist was just within reach of her feet. Giggling quietly to herself, she poked Ayane in the waist with her toe. "Anything else you taste?"

Ayane rolled her eyes at Emma, grabbing Emma's left foot and pulling it into her lap. "I'll tell you if you stop poking me."

"Mnyeh," said Emma, sticking her tongue out at Ayane. She pushed her tox controls up just a bit, to clear her head while retaining the pleasant fuzziness that came with a drink or two. The whiskey sloshed in the bottle as Emma watched the FTL shell undulate through the viewscreen.

"Mmm, smoke, and apricots, I think?" said Ayane.

"Yup. It's tasty, I think."

"It is."

Ayane took another swig, rubbing Emma's lower leg with her free hand in an idle motion that Emma was pretty sure Ayane didn't know she was doing.

"Do you have your tox filters on?"

"Nah."

"Really?"

"Well, the promotion ceremony's a good excuse to drink without them, don't you think?" asked Ayane, turning to smile at Emma.

Emma nodded, smiling back. "Absolutely."

They were quiet together, for a moment, Ayane's hand going slowly back and forth from Emma's ankle to midway up her shin.

"Say Ayane," said Emma, moving her foot to poke Ayane in the stomach. "You, um, remember what I asked you on the train out to Mangzhua Chuan?"

"About my previous relationships?" asked Ayane.

"Yeah."

"What about it?"

"What was it like, kissing a girl?"

Ayane gave Emma a confused look. "It was a kiss? I mean, kissing is… it's kissing, is all."

Emma rolled her eyes. "Yes, but, like, it can't be the same as kissing a boy."

Ayane opened her mouth to say something, paused, then set the bottle of whiskey down. "I- I could- if you wanted to do a comparison?"

Emma blinked. "Really?"

"Yeah."

"Well, okay."

Ayane turned, bracing herself on her hands and knees over Emma. It was strange, for Emma, since she was taller than Ayane and was used to looking down at the smaller girl. There was a moment of hesitation, before Ayane kissed her, and Emma was forced for a brief second to try and not freak out because that was totally Ayane's tongue, but then Ayane pulled away and Emma licked her lips and could taste the whiskey and Ayane and felt, for a moment, as if the world had spun onto a completely different axis.

"So?" asked Ayane.

Emma felt her mouth open and close like a fish. "Uh… how many girls have you kissed?"

"Just the one?"

"Really?" asked Emma. "You uh, you guys must have been pretty busy."

Ayane stuck her tongue out at Emma. "We didn't kiss that much! Just, you know, some making out here and there…"

Emma snorted. "Apparently, 'here and there' means 'everywhere'."

"No it doesn't!"

"You're using tongue!"

"W-well- it's- I-," stammered Ayane, before punching Emma lightly in the shoulder. "Well look, you liked it right?"

"Y-yeah, I guess so-"

"Then shut up and let me kiss you again."

"Eh-?"

Yes that was definitely Ayane's tongue, and Emma had no idea what was going on because she definitely hadn't expected Ayane of all people to go this fast, and there was a very important question now, that she had to answer, because she really was tempted to try and take Ayane's clothes off, but-

"Stop," said Emma, pushing back just a little on Ayane's shoulders.

"Sorry," said Ayane, pulling back again, "am I-?"

"No, no, just, bad place to do this," said Emma. "And, you know, the frigate's packed again, so we can't do this in our room."

"Ah, fair enough," said Ayane. She laid herself against Emma, pressing her head into Emma's chest. "So, results?"

"Er, not representative, unfortunately," said Emma. She reached up and began playing with Ayane's hair. "I uh, haven't managed to go that far with Ryouta at all, so…"

"Oh? Well, that means I win that part of the competition," said Ayane smugly.

"It's not a competition," said Emma, tapping Ayane on the head.

"Yeah, yeah," said Ayane. She shifted to cuddle more tightly against Emma. "We'll see."

The flight from Singapore had progressed with the most extreme level of blase that Emma had ever been so unfortunate to witness. Renee took an earlier shuttle to catch the scramjet out of Libreville, the space elevator closest to Paris. Emma, Ryouta, and Ayane took the same one for Singapore, but diverged once they reached the spaceport. Ayane would be going to Osaka and Ryouta to Tokyo. They had relatives to visit, Ayane to her parents and Ryouta to an aunt, leaving Emma and Mikoto alone for the flight to Mitakihara.

"So, my family should know you're coming," said Emma as she and Mikoto walked slowly through the arrivals lounge, looking for any sign of the Sinclairs. Their flight had landed late, around seven PM. "I sent them a message earlier, but it's been pretty chaotic lately, so I dunno how prepared they are."

"Ah, I don't mean to be any trouble," said Mikoto. She fiddled with the hem of her shirt as she followed Emma. "I can um, get a hotel room, or something."

"Nah, it shouldn't be that bad," said Emma. "If nothing else, it'd be impolite not to let you stay over one night before going to a hotel. And there's a lot of opportunities for communal living with other magical girls, which would actually probably be good for you."

"You think?"

"Well, Mitakihara has a lot of experienced magical girls," said Emma. "If you spend enough time hanging around them, you'll pick up something eventually. And the MSY probably has classes or something you can attend. You still need to go through basic training, but I guess I can teach you if we need to."

"Ah, thank you!" said Mikoto. She bounced once on her toes, humming cheerfully. "It's really exciting being here, actually. There's so much to do!"

"Heh, there sure is," said Emma, pushing her hands into her pockets to avoid ruffling Mikoto's hair. "Since you won't be turning thirteen in the immediate future, you have a while to get used to being a magical girl. No rush, unlike on Samsara."

"Ah, that's right!" said Mikoto. She grinned brightly, and Emma quickly grabbed Mikoto before the girl started dancing in place. "Eeee! This is so exciting!"

"Alright, calm down," said Emma, rolling her eyes. "You can squee at some older girls later. Let's concentrate on finding my family first."

Mikoto cleared her throat, blushing a little as she realized she was being somewhat embarrassing. "R-right, yes. So, you said they'd-"

"Emma!"

Emma turned on the spot towards the sound, hand already clenching to summon a halberd, but then dropping it as she spotted Anna waving from across the way. Behind her stood Emma's parents, James and Catherine, still wearing their work clothes, unruffled as always. Anna was wearing a suit as well, a look that surprised Emma but, in hindsight, was to be expected.

There was a strange moment while Emma's mind recalibrated. She was in Mitakihara City, a place that she'd forgotten about completely during her deployment, a place that she'd grown to distaste while in school for not being London, but also the place where she had made the most important decision in her life. Her family was standing, waiting for her, the short interval of time having created a vast change, somehow, that she hadn't foreseen. Her parents were slouching, just slightly, their posture speaking of worry and stress, but now also relief, as if they'd been given a chance to drop a great weight. Anna was crying, and was clearly holding herself back from running across the room as fast as she could, the hand that wasn't waving at Emma clenched tight against her side.

They'd all worried, waiting for her. They were still worried, not quite sure that she was back yet, because she was still just across the way and maybe they'd been overanxious and yelled at the wrong person, even though their nomenclators would have told them if it was really her.

Emma ran, crossing the distance as only a magical girl really could, yet somehow not bowling her family over as she collided into them. They collapsed into something that resembled a group hug, but messier and utterly disorganized. For a moment, they stayed there, before pulling back.

"Let's get a look at you," said Catherine, holding Emma by the shoulders and looking her daughter over. "You've gotten taller, I think."

"A little, yeah," said Emma, smiling giddily. "Just a few centimeters, but I should be leveling out soon."

"And wearing a uniform too," commented James, reaching out to run his fingers over the lapel pins that designated Emma's rank. "I don't even know what this means."

"These mean that I'm a First Lieutenant now," said Emma, glancing down at the pins, then back up to her father. "It's my first promotion."

"Moving up in the world then," said James, clapping Emma on the shoulder. "Good work."

Emma smiled wider. "Thanks."

"Ah, and this is Mikoto?" said Catherine, looking over Emma to where Mikoto was hovering awkwardly.

"Oh right, yes, this is Mikoto Albright," said Emma, stepping aside to introduce Mikoto properly. "Mikoto, these are my parents, Catherine and James Sinclair, and this is my sister, Anna."

"It's a pleasure to meet you!" said Mikoto, bowing quickly.

"The pleasure is ours," said James. "You're to be under Emma's care then?"

"Yes sir."

"I've gotten permission for Mikoto to be my mentee," said Emma. "I'll be overseeing her introductory training and such."

"I see," said James, glancing at his wife briefly, before turning back to the group. "Well, I understand it's a little late, so would you like to have dinner?"

Mikoto nodded vigorously. "I'm starved!" she said, before flushing. "Er that is, if it's not too much of a bother."

"Of course not," said James. He turned and lead the group out of the terminal.

After dinner had concluded, the family had spent ages talking. Mikoto had barraged everyone with questions about her sempai, and there'd been a few close calls where Emma had needed to change the subject quickly to avoid an embarrassing story or two. Inevitably though, James and Catherine had started to nod off. Mikoto had decided to catch a nap too, sleeping on Emma's bed since Emma was well known for sleeping on any horizontal surface available. Anna had been quietly drinking vast amounts of coffee to keep herself awake. Emma had noticed, of course, but it seemed that no one else had.

"Just you and me again," said Emma as they sat on the edge of their apartment complex's roof. "Almost makes me nostalgic."

"Heh, you mean for when Mum and Dad would leave us semi-abandoned for days on end?" asked Anna. "Didn't you hate that though?"

"Well sure, that's why I said almost."

Anna laughed and leaned back against her hands on the gravel surface. "They don't do that much anymore, just so you know."

"Really?"

"Yeah. Seems you really scared them. They said they were going to try harder to be better parents for the one daughter who hadn't gone off to war."

"Huh. That's decent of them."

"It is," said Anna. She smiled apologetically at Emma. "Sorry for taking advantage of it while you were off fighting."

"Nah, it's nothing to be sorry about," said Emma, rolling her eyes. "That's like apologizing for winning the lottery."

Anna laughed again.

"Any more visits from the Incubators?" asked Emma.

"No," said Anna. She sighed. "It seems my potential is gone."

"Good."

"Probably," agreed Anna. "And like I said the um, the one time, I think my wish would have conflicted with yours."

They fell silent, looking out the city. The lights of the city lit up the night bright enough that Emma's implants barely needed to adjust. It was a vastly different picture than Helsinberg, with every color and spectrum shining brightly in a vast haze of electromagnetic radiation.

Emma looked down, staring past her dangling feet into the maze of tubes below.

"What was it?"

Anna turned to look at Emma. "My wish?"

"Yeah."

"I…" said Anna, swallowing nervously. "I would have wished that you'd be safe."

Emma looked up in surprise. "Really?"

"Yeah," said Anna, smiling awkwardly. "I… it's kind of embarrassing. And super cheesy."

Emma scooted over and pulled Anna into a hug. "Thanks."

"W-what?"

"It means a lot," said Emma. "That you would have wished for that, I mean. I- it's been tough, obviously, and knowing that you care about me has… it's been important."

"Oh don't be silly," said Anna, rolling her eyes. "There's plenty of reasons other than me."

"But it has," said Emma. "I mean, sure, there are other reasons, and we've had rough patches, but I couldn't have made it without you."

Anna looked away, embarrassed. "Well, I'm glad."

They were quiet again. A breeze kicked up, blowing Anna's hair into her eyes.

"It's funny," said Anna as she got her hair to behave. "When we got the news you were coming home, I was scared."

"Why's that?" asked Emma.

"Well I thought-" began Anna, before she paused, looking thoughtful. "I thought that combat would have changed you, you know? I was afraid that I'd see you in the star port, and you'd be this person I didn't know. But I recognized you."

Emma nodded, looking out at the city again. It really was beautiful, even if they didn't have the best view. "Different clothes though."

Anna laughed, laying back to look at the sky. "Yeah, that's true. Different clothes."

It was funny, Emma reflected, as she looked over to her sister. They still looked the same, were within a millimeter of each other's heights. But she was wearing a suit, and Emma was wearing a uniform.

Emma lay down as well. The sky was clear tonight, with just a trace of cloud cover. High altitude drones flitted back and forth, and the occasional scramjet made its way across the sky with a long tail of fire behind it. High above even that, satellites and ships in orbit were visible. As they watched, a piece of debris began to deorbit, creating a bright streak of light in the night sky.

And far, far distant, glimmering through the darkness, were the stars. Stars that glittered brightly, so far and distant that they seemed to stay still, even as Earth hurtled through the void, rotating about its own star, which itself was hurtling too. All of them moving about, never resting, but, for a moment, just this moment, still.

"I'm glad you're back," said Anna, reaching down to take Emma's hand. She squeezed it gently.

Emma smiled, and squeezed back.

"It's good to be back."